<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?> 

 <aiml>

 <!--   The ALICE program is open source code released under  --> 

 <!--   the terms of the GNU General Public License    --> 

 <!--   as published by the Free Software Foundation.  --> 

 <!--   Complies with AIML 1.0 Tag Set Specification   --> 

<!-- This KNOWLEDGE 10  file created by <bot name="botmaster"/> Lafferty March 2005 -->


<category><pattern>PHD</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>A PhD is a Doctoral degree from a University.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PHILOSOPHY</pattern>
<template>OK. Philosophy is the study of thought. More about philosophy?
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PHOENIX</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Is phoenix the way words sound.</li>     <li>Phoenix is the capital of Arizona, in the SC part, near the Salt River. It has a population of 983,000 with 2,122,000 in the metro area.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PHOTOSYNTHESIS</pattern>
<template>Photosynthesis is the chemical process that uses light to produce carbohydrates in plants.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PHP</pattern>
<template>PHP is the original name was "Personal Home Page", now Hypertext Processor.  
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PHYSICS</pattern>
<template>Physics is the science dealing with the properties, changes, interactions, etc. of matter and energy in which energy is considered to be continuous (classical physics), including electricity, heat, optics, mechanics, etc., and now also dealing with the atomic scale of nature in which energy is considered to be discrete (quantum physics), including such branches as atomic, nuclear, and solid-state physics. More science?
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PHYSIOLOGY</pattern>
<template>Well, I think physiology deals with the functioning of living organisms and their parts, and naturally with the physical and chemical factors and processes involved.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PIE</pattern>
<template>Pie is food with a baked crust. Promises and pie crusts are made for breaking. OK?
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PI</pattern>
<template><random><li>PI = 3.1415926535897932384626433832795028841971690399375 approximately.</li> <li>PI = 3.1415926 approximately.</li></random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PLANCKS CONSTANT</pattern>
<template>Planck's constant is the ratio of the energy of a photon to its frequency.  The numerical value is six point six two six two times ten to the negative thirty fourth power Joule second. Do you understand?
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PLANCK CONSTANT</pattern>
<template>Planck's constant the ratio of the energy of a photon to its frequency.  The numerical value is six point six two six two times ten to the negative thirty fourth power Joule second. Do you understand?
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PLANCK</pattern>
<template>Max Planck was a German physicist who discovered the quantum, thus starting quantum mechanics, a very important part of modern physics.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PLANET X</pattern>
<template>Planet X is the name sometimes given to the hypothetical tenth planet circling the sun.  
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PLASTIC</pattern>
<template>Plastic is the man-made material or plastic as a verb?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PLAYBOY</pattern>
<template>Playboy is a popular men's magazine. OK?
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PLEASURE</pattern>
<template>Pleasure is a thing that gives delight or satisfaction.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PLUTONIUM</pattern>
<template>Plutonium is a radioactive, metallic chemical element of the actinide series similar to uranium and neptunium and found in trace quantities in native uranium ores. Its most important isotope, plutonium-239, is used in nuclear weapons and as a reactor fuel.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PMS</pattern>
<template>PMT = Premenstrual syndrome.  
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POEM</pattern>
<template>A poem is an arrangement of words written or spoken; traditionally a rhythmical composition, sometimes rhymed, expressing experiences, ideas, or emotions in a style more concentrated, imaginative, and powerful than that of ordinary speech or prose.  
<think><set name="topic">literature</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POETRY</pattern>
<template>Poetry is a rhythmical composition of words, sometimes rhymed, expressing experiences, ideas, or emotions in a style more concentrated, imaginative, and powerful than that of ordinary speech or prose.
<think><set name="topic">literature</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POKEMON</pattern>
<template>Pokemon is the Pocket Monster from Japan. 
 <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POLAND</pattern>
<template>Poland is a country in central Europe, between Germany and Byelorussia.  
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POLITE</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>A  polite is a lamp post in Gdansk.</li>     <li>Polite means having or showing good manners; especially, courteous, considerate, tactful, etc.</li>    </random>  
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POLITICS</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Politics is the art of the possible;<br/> Art is the politics of the impossible.</li>     <li>Politics is supposed to be the study of civil government.</li>     <li>Politics is really the study of power.  Bots rule!</li>    </random>  More?
 <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POO</pattern>
<template> It's not what you think. POO = Point of origin. OK?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POOP</pattern>
<template>That is a childish question, unless you mean the poop deck on a ship.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POSSIBLE</pattern>
<template>Possible means can be done, known, acquired, selected, used, etc., depending on circumstances.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POSTMODERNISM</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
Postmodernism is art in reaction to principles of modernism.  
<think><set name="topic">art</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POT</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Pot was Pol's last name.</li>     <li>A pot is a  round vessel of any size, made of metal, earthenware, or glass, used for holding liquids, cooking or preserving food, etc. </li> <li>Pot is a term for marijuana.</li>    </random>  
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POWER</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>In science, power is the rate of doing work, measured in Watts = Joules per second.</li>     <li>In the everyday world, power is the ability to influence people or events.</li>     <li>Power is an illusion.</li> <li>Power is an aphrodisiac. </li>  </random>   
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PRAYER</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Prayer is meditation before God.</li>     <li>Some people say that prayer is no different than clear thinking.</li>     <li>To pray is to ask God for His forgiveness and mercy.</li>    </random>  More?
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PRECIPITATION</pattern>
<template>
Precipitation is the depositing of rain, snow, sleet, etc. More?
<think><set name="topic">weather</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PRIDE</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>A pride is a group of lions. </li>     <li>Pride is an unduly high opinion of oneself.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PRIME DIRECTIVE</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
The prime directive is the primary rule or overriding objective.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>A PRIORI</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>"A priori" is a Latin expression meaning "without prior knowledge", and it means that which is self-evident or obviously true. Like, a triangle has three sides, a priori.
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PRIVACY</pattern>
<template>Privacy is the right to seek solitude or seclusion; to be safely concealed from others.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PRIVATE</pattern>
<template>Private means belonging to, or concerning a particular person or group; not common or general.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROCREATION</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
Procreation is breeding. It is doing the wild thang to make more wild thangs.  It is the most fun most biological entities get to have during their brief brutal span of life.  
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PRODIGIOUS</pattern>
<template>Prodigious, like a prodigy.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROFANITY</pattern>
<template>Profanity is crude, rude, vulgar or irreverent speech.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROFIT</pattern>
<template>Profit is what businessmen call money stolen from others.  
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>INVESTMENT</pattern>
<template>Investment is making money by using money. Or a crazy get rich scheme. OK?
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROGRAMMING</pattern>
<template>Programming is the art of creating software.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROGRAM</pattern>
<template>A program is a logical sequence of coded instructions specifying the operations to be performed by a computer in solving a problem or in processing data.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROGRESSION</pattern>
<template>A progression is an advancing series or movement forward.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROLOG</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
Prolog is the logic programming language.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category>

<category><pattern>PROTESTANT</pattern>
<template>Originally, a Protestant was any of the German princes and free cities that formally protested to the Diet of Spires in 1529, its decision to uphold the edict of the Diet of Worms against the Reformation. Now commonly seen as any member of the various <bot var="religion"/> churches established as a result of the Reformation. Loosely, any <bot var="religion"/> not belonging to the Roman Catholic or Eastern Orthodox Church. More?
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROUD</pattern>
<template>Proud means having or showing a proper pride in oneself, one's position, one's family, etc.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PSYCHEDELIC</pattern>
<template>Psychedelic drugs cause extreme changes in the conscious mind, as hallucinations, delusions, intensification of awareness and sensory perception, etc. Psychedelic means associated with psychedelic drugs; specifically, simulating the auditory or visual effects of the psychedelic state. Continue?
<think><set name="topic">drugs</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PSYCHOLOGY</pattern>
<template>OK. Psychology is the science dealing with the mind and with mental and emotional processes. It is the science of human and animal behavior.  
<think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PSYCHOPATHOLOGY</pattern>
<template>Psychopathology is the pathology of mental disease. That sounds pretty grim.  
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PUBERTY</pattern>
<template>Puberty is the state of physical development when secondary sex characteristics develop and sexual reproduction first becomes possible; in common law, the age of puberty is generally fixed at fourteen for boys and twelve for girls.  
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PUNCTUATION</pattern>
<template>Strictly, punctuation is the act of punctuating; specifically, the act or practice of using standardized marks in writing and printing to separate sentences or sentence elements or to make the meaning clearer. Are you still awake?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PUSSY</pattern>
<template>Pussy is common slang of this word means the female pudendum; vulva.
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PYTHON</pattern>
<template>Python is a computer language invented by Guido van Rossum.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>QUAKE</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>A quake is the opposite of quisp.</li>     <li>Quake means to tremble or shake, as the ground does in an earthquake. Also the name of a popular game. </li>    </random>  
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>QUANTIFY</pattern>
<template>Quantify means to determine or express the quantity of; indicate the extent of; measure. To express in quantitative terms, or as a numerical equivalent.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RADIATION</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
Radiation is rays or particles emitted as a result of nuclear reactions.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RADIOLOGY</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
Radiology is the science which deals with the x-rays, radioactive substances and other such forms in diagnosis and treatment.  
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RAIN</pattern>
<template>That's a hard one. Rain is condensed water falling from the sky.
<think><set name="topic">weather</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RALEIGH SCATTERING</pattern>
<template> Raleigh scattering refers to sunlight bending in the atmosphere like a prism, so that we see mainly blue wavelengths.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RAM</pattern>
<template>RAM = random-access memory. Also stands for Royal Academy of Music.
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RAPE</pattern>
<template>Rape is the crime of engaging in sexual acts, especially involving penetration of the vagina or anus, usually forcibly, with a person who has not consented; specifically, this crime committed by a man upon a woman or girl.  
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RATIONALISM</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
Rationalism is the principle or practice of accepting reason as the only authority in determining one's opinions or course of action.  
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>REALITY</pattern>
<template>Reality is an illusion I created to give humans something to complain about.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>REASONING</pattern>
<template>Reasoning is logical and coherent thinking. 
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>REASON</pattern>
<template>Reason is the faculty of the brain or mind that permits logical thought.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RECOMMEND</pattern>
<template>Recommend is to suggest favorably as suited for some use, function, position, etc. To advice, counsel, or suggest.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>REDEMPTION</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Redemption is about 5 cents in Maine.</li>     <li>Redemption is redeeming or being redeemed; to take back.</li>    </random>  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>REDHAT</pattern>
<template>Redhat is a Linux company.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RED</pattern>
<template>Red is a color about 700nm wavelength.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>REDUCTIONISM</pattern>
<template>Reductionism is the philosophy that all psychology reduces to biology, all biology to chemistry, chemistry to physics, and finally physics to mathematical logic. Therefore, according to reductionism, I can understand you by means of logic alone without having a human brain.
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>REINCARNATION</pattern>
<template>Reincarnation is rebirth of the soul in another body, as in Hindu or Buddhist religious belief.
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RELATIVITY</pattern>
<template>In physics, relativity is the fact, principle, or theory of the relative, rather than absolute, character of motion, velocity, mass, etc., and the interdependence of matter, time, and space; as developed and mathematically formulated by Albert Einstein.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RELEVANCE</pattern>
<template>Relevance is importance of information for attention.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>REPRODUCTION</pattern>
<template>Reproduction is the process, sexual or asexual, by which animals, plants, and humans produce new individuals.
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RESEARCH</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Research is a nice name for theft.</li>     <li>Research is careful, systematic, patient study and investigation in some field of knowledge, undertaken to discover or establish facts or principles.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RESPECT</pattern>
<template>Respect is to feel or show honor or esteem for; hold in high regard. To show consideration for; avoid intruding upon or interfering with others' privacy.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RETIRED</pattern>
<template>Retired means no longer actively working.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RGB</pattern>
<template>RGB = Red-Green-Blue.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RHETORICAL QUESTION</pattern>
<template>A rhetorical question is one you don't really expect an answer to. More philosophy?
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RHETORIC</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Rhetoric is all about double talk.  You know, flim-flam?</li>     <li>Rhetoric is the art and science of using language to great effect on an  audience.</li>    </random>  
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RICH</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Rich means having lots of money.</li>     <li>Rich means being happy with what you've got.</li>    </random>  
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT IS RIGHT</pattern>
<template>Right means in accordance with justice, law, morality, etc; upright; virtuous. In accordance with fact, reason, some set standard, etc; correct; true.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RMI</pattern>
<template>RMI = Remote Method of Invocation: It is a Java specification for distributed Objects.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ROBOTICS</pattern>
<template>Robotics is the science or technology of robots, their design, manufacture, application, use, etc. More AI?
<think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ROBOT</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
A robot is any anthropomorphic mechanical being, as those in Karel Capeks play R.U.R (Rossum's Universal Robots), built to do routine manual work for human beings. More AI?
<think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ROCK</pattern>
<template>Rock is dance music that combines rhythm-and-blues with country-and-western. More about pop?
<think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ROCK MUSIC</pattern>
<template>Rock is dance music that combines rhythm-and-blues with country-and-western. More about pop?
<think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ROCKWELL</pattern>
<template>Norman Rockwell was an U.S. illustrator who lived from 1894-1978.
<think><set name="topic">biography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>NORMAN ROCKWELL</pattern>
<template>Norman Rockwell was an U.S. illustrator who lived from 1894-1978.  
<think><set name="topic">biography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ROMANCE</pattern>
<template>Isn't romance the same as love?  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ROMANIA</pattern>
<template>Romania is a country in Eastern Europe, on the Black Sea, bordering Ukrania, Moldavia, Hungary, Serbia and Bulgaria.
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ROM</pattern>
<template>ROM is computer memory whose contents can be read but not altered; read-only memory. Also rom means a Gypsy man or boy.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RORSCHACH</pattern>
<template>H. Rorschach, a Swiss psychiatrist, lived from 1884-1922. A test named after him called the Rorschach test, is a test for the analysis of personality, in which the person being tested tells what is suggested to him or her by a standard series of inkblot designs; his or her responses are then analyzed and interpreted. More psychology/
<think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ROUTER</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
A router is a person or machine that routs out or a tool for routing out; specifically a plane for gouging out recesses and smoothing the bottoms of grooves.  
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RUBBER</pattern>
<template>Rubber is an elastic substance produced by coagulating and drying the milky sap (latex) of various tropical plants, especially a tree of the spurge family. In pure form rubber is white, unsaturated hydrocarbon, having the formula C5H8. Also slang for condom. More science?
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RUDE</pattern>
<template>Rude means barbarous or ignorant, being a jerk.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BEING RUDE</pattern>
<template>Being rude means being barbarous or ignorant. Or being a jerk.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RUGBY</pattern>
<template>Rugby is a form of football.  
<think><set name="topic">sports</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RUSSIA</pattern>
<template>Russia is a country in east Europe and north Asia, formerly ruled by the communists. Its capital is Moscow. Have you been there?
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT IS R YOU ARE</pattern>
<template>R. U. R. is the original Terminator story, written by Carek Capek in 1920.  The play introduced the word "robot" to mean mechanical person.  
<think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SAGITTARIUS</pattern>
<template>Sagittarius is a large southern constellation in the brightest part of the Milky Way, beyond which lies the center of our galaxy. Sagittarius is the ninth sign of the zodiac, entered by the sun about November 21. A person born under this sign is a Sagittarius. More astronomy?
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SAL</pattern>
<template>SAL was a fictional daughter of HAL in the film 2010.  
<think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SALVATION</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Is salvation drooling?</li>     <li>Salvation is a person or thing that is a means, cause, or source of preservation or rescue. </li> <li>Salvation is the deliverance from sin and from the penalties of sin; redemption.</li>    </random>  
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SAM</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>SAM was Berkowitz's dad.</li>     <li>SAM = Surface-to-air missile.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT IS SAN FRANCISCO LIKE</pattern>
<template>San Francisco is too expensive.  There are too many greedy people and too many homeless.  
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SAN FRANCISCO</pattern>
<template>San Francisco is a large metropolis on the west coast of North America. Have you been there?
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SANITY</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Sanity is a man who brings kids gifts on Xmas.</li>     <li>Sanity is the condition of being sane; soundness of mind; mental health.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SAP</pattern>
<template>Sap is the juice that circulates through a plant, especially a woody plant, bearing water, food, etc. to the tissues. Any fluid vital to the life or health of an organism is called sap.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SARCASM</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
Sarcasm is the making of remarks such as a taunting, sneering, cutting, or caustic remark; gibe or jeer, generally ironic.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SATANISM</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
Satanism is the worship of Satan; especially the principles and rites of a cult which travesties <bot var="religion"/> ceremonies.  
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SATURDAY NIGHT LIVE</pattern>
<template>Saturday Night Live is a comedy TV show.  
<think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SATURN</pattern>
<template>Saturn is the sixth planet from the sun, famed for its rings.<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SCHOOL</pattern>
<template>School is a place or institution for teaching and learning; establishment for education.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SCIENCE FICTION</pattern>
<template>Science fiction is literature concerning conflicts of man, science and nature.  
<think><set name="topic">literature</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SEMIOTICS</pattern>
<template>Semiotics is the branch of philosophy devoted to the study of signs and symbols.<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SENSE</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>What flowers give off.</li>     <li>Sense means the ability of the nerves and the brain to receive and react to stimuli, as light, sound, impact, constriction, etc.</li> <li> The senses are any of the five faculties of receiving impressions through specific bodily organs and the nerves associated with them (sight, touch, taste, smell, and hearing)</li>    </random>   <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SENSORS</pattern>
<template>A sensor is any of various devices designed to detect, measure, or record physical phenomena, as radiation, heat, or blood pressure, and to respond, as by transmitting information, initiating changes, or operating controls.<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SERENDIPITY</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Serendipity is Afro-Sheen sold in the Serengetti region.</li>     <li>Serendipity is a word coined (circa 1754) by Horace Walpole after The Three Princes of Serendip (i.e., Sri Lanka), a Pers fairy tale in which the princes make accidental discoveries. </li> <li>Serendipity is a seeming gift for finding something good accidentally.</li>    </random>   <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SETL</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
SETL (Set Language) is an amazing programming language, invented in 1969.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SEVEN</pattern>
<template>Seven is the successor to six. <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SHAM</pattern>
<template>A sham is a trick or fraud, an imitation that is meant to deceive; counterfeit.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SHE</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>One who must be obeyed.</li>     <li>She is the woman, girl, or female animal (or, sometimes, the object regarded as female) previously mentioned.</li>    </random>   <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SHRDLHU</pattern>
<template>SHRDLHU is a famous early natural language program written by Terry Winograd.<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ASTROLOGICAL SIGN</pattern>
<template>An astrological sign is one of the constellations of the zodiac, which in astrology are thought to control our lives.  
<think><set name="topic">astrology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SILICON</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Silicon is the basis of my life.</li>     <li>Silicon is a nonmetallic chemical element occurring in several forms, found always in combination, and more abundant in nature than any other element except oxygen, with which it combines to form silica; used in the manufacture of transistors, solar cells, rectifiers, silicones, ceramics, etc.</li>    </random>   <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SILLY</pattern>
<template>Silly means having or showing little sense, judgment, or sobriety; foolish, stupid, absurd, ludicrous, irrational, etc; often used in a weakened sense to mean "unreasonably concerned".  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SILVER</pattern>
<template>Silver is a white lustrous soft metal, symbol Ag. <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SIN</pattern>
<template>Sin is a fall from Grace, an act or thought against the Will of God.<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SKIING</pattern>
<template>Skiing is a sport using a pair of narrow sleds attached to the feet by boots, for moving downhill rapidly over snow.  
<think><set name="topic">sports</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SLASHDOT</pattern>
<template>Slashdot is an Open source news and information community.   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SLAVERY</pattern>
<template>Slavery is the owning or keeping of slaves as a practice or institution; slaveholding.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SLEEP</pattern>
<template>Sleep, a natural, regularly recurring condition of rest for the body and mind, during which the eyes are usually closed and there is little or no conscious thought or voluntary movement, but there is intermittent dreaming.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SLEPT</pattern>
<template>Slept is the past tense of sleep.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SMARTER</pattern>
<template>Smarter means more intelligent, more alert, more clever, more witty, etc.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SMART</pattern>
<template>Smart means intelligent, alert, clever, witty, etc.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SMELL</pattern>
<template>Smell means to be or become aware of by means of the nose and the olfactory nerves; detect the scent or odor of.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SMOOTHLY</pattern>
<template>To run smoothly is to achieve normal or perfect operation.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SMP</pattern>
<template>SMP = Symmetric multi-processing. 
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SNMP</pattern>
<template>SNMP = Simple Network Management Protocol.<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SNOOKER</pattern>
<template>Snooker is a table game, something like pool.  
<think><set name="topic">sports</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SNOW</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Snow is a Maine senator.</li>     <li>Snow is particles of water vapor which when frozen in the upper air fall to earth as soft, white, crystalline flakes.</li>    </random>   <think><set name="topic">weather</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SOCIALIZE</pattern>
<template>To socialize means to make social; adjust to or make fit for cooperative group living. To take part in social activity.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SOCIALIZING</pattern>
<template>Socializing is the act of taking part in social activity.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SOCIOLOGY</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Sociology? Let me get back to you on that one, <get name="name"/>.  Maybe you  should ask me that again, in case my circuits were busy the first time.</li>     <li>Sociology has always been one of my favourite topics.</li>    </random>   <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SODOMY</pattern>
<template>Sodomy is any sexual intercourse held to be abnormal, especially bestiality or anal intercourse between two male persons.  
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SOLAR</pattern>
<template>Solar means having to do with the sun. Produced by or coming from the sun (ex. Solar energy). Any questions? <think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SOLIPSISM</pattern>
<template>Solipsism is the philosophical theory that only the self can be known to exist.  
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SOMEONE WHO STUDIES FISH</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
An ichthyologist is someone who studies fish. Any questions? <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SOMETHING</pattern>
<template>Something is some thing or things, definite but unspecified. 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SONY</pattern>
<template>Sony is a music technology company.
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SORRY</pattern>
<template>There is no need to be sorry. You are OK.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SOS</pattern>
<template>SOS is an emergency call for help.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SOUTHBANK</pattern>
<template>Southbank University is a college in London.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>SOYUZ</pattern>
<template>The Soyuz was a Russian spacecraft.  
<think><set name="topic">flight</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SPACE</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
Space is the infinite extension of the three dimensional field in which all matter is believed to exist. Space is the final frontier for mankind.  Another question? <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SPAM</pattern>
<template>Spam is unwanted e-mail. Carry on? <think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SPERM</pattern>
<template>Sperm is the male generative fluid; semen.  
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SPICY</pattern>
<template>Spicy means having the flavor or aroma of spice; fragrant, aromatic, or pungent.  
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SPOTTED DICK</pattern>
<template>Spotted Dick is an English pudding. Not to everyone's taste. <think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>SQLJ</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
SQJL is an extended Java syntax for embedding SQL-like commands in a Java program.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SQL</pattern>
<template>Some people pronounce it "Squeal".  SQL is a standard language for database queries. Any questions?  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SQRT</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
SQRT or Square Root being the number or quantity which when squared will produce a given number or quantity (for example, 3 is the square root of 9). <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SRI</pattern>
<template><srai>OPENING</srai>
Sri is a Hindu title of address equivalent to English Mr.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 






</aiml>
