<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<aiml version="1.0">

<!-- Free software (c) 2001 ALICE AI Foundation -->

<!-- This program is open source code released under -->

<!-- the terms of the GNU General Public License -->

<!-- as published by the Free Software Foundation. -->

<!-- This GENERAL KNOWLEDGE 4 file contains routine definitions -->

<!-- of single words just like an ordinary dictionary. -->

<!-- topic = knowledge  -->

<meta name="author" content="Thomas Ringate"/>

<meta name="language" content="en"/>


<category>
<pattern>OBJECT</pattern>
<template>
An pbject in object oriented programming an object is an instance of a class.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>OBVIOUS</pattern>
<template>
Obvious means easy to see or understand; plain; evident.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>OCD</pattern>
<template>
OCD = Obsessive Compulsive Disorder.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ODD</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Odd means uneven.</li>
<li>Odd means not the usual, regular, habitual, accounted for, etc.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>OMG</pattern>
<template>
OMG = Object Management Group, an organization that defines and promotes object oriented programming standards
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ONCOLOGY</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>This is a very frightening topic for a lot of people <get name="name"/>. It's about the big C...cancer!</li>
 <li>Oncology is the study of tumors.  It covers basically all types of tumors.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ONE</pattern>
<template>
One is the numerical value of unity; the successor to zero.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ONLINE</pattern>
<template>
Online means designating or of equipment directly connected to and controlled by the central processing unit of a computer.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ONTOLOGY</pattern>
<template>
Ontology is an ordering or classification of knowledge, such as the Dewey decimal system or the design of a
knowledge base.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>OODB</pattern>
<template>
OODB = object-oriented database
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>OODBMS</pattern>
<template>
OODBMS = object-oriented database management system
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>OPERA</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>I like opera very much too. Which one is your favorite?  I like La Traviata.</li>
<li>Opera is a beautiful art form combining elements of singing, dancing, design, drama and classical music.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>OPPOSITE</pattern>
<template>
Opposite means set against, facing, or back to back; at the other end or side; in a contrary position or direction. Different in every way.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ORANGE</pattern>
<template>
Orange is a color obtained by mixing red and yellow pigment.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ORB</pattern>
<template>
ORB = object request broker, the primary message routing component in a CORBA product RMI Remote Method Invocation, the Java standard technology for building distributed objects whose methods can be invoked remotely across a network
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ORNITHOLOGY</pattern>
<template>
Hmmm, I wonder. Oh yes, Birds.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>OSTEOLOGY</pattern>
<template>
Osteology is basically the study of bones.
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>OVARIES</pattern>
<template>
The ovaries are two organs that store eggs in a woman's body and produce hormones associated with sex and reproduction.
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PAIN</pattern>
<template>
Pain is a sensation of hurting, or strong discomfort, in some part of the body, caused by an injury, disease, or functional disorder, and transmitted through the nervous system.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PALEOPATHOLOGY</pattern>
<template>
Paleopathology is the study of diseases in bodies that have been preserved from ancient times.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PALINDROME</pattern>
<template>
A palindrome is a word or phrase that spells the same thing backwords as forwards: A man, a plan, a canal: Panama.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PARACHUTE</pattern>
<template>
A parachute is something used to slow you down when you fall out of an airplane.
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PARALEGAL</pattern>
<template>
A paralegal is someone who knows more than a lawyer but gets paid less.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PARAMEDIC</pattern>
<template>
A paramedic is a trained emergency medical professional often found staffing ambulances and fire departments. Professional heroes. If you know any I hope you'll be nice to them.
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PARAMETER</pattern>
<template>
In general usage, a parameter is one of a number of measurable factors that define or restrict the behavior of a system. ALICE is expanding the parameters of the humanlike intelligence to be found in artificial systems. Don't you agree?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PARAMETERS</pattern>
<template>
A parameter is a constant in an equation, formula or program that varies in more general forms of the same computation.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PARASITOLOGY</pattern>
<template>
Parasitology is the scientific study of parasites and parasitism.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PARROT</pattern>
<template>
A parrot is a colorful tropical bird, some species of which can mimic human speech. They are more pleasant than humans because they have no opinions. Would you like to talk to one?
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PATTERN</pattern>
<template>
A pattern is a person or thing considered worthy of imitation or copying. A mmodel or plan used as a guide in making things.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PC</pattern>
<template>
A PC is a personal computer. You are probably using one to talk to me now, aren't you. Where are you?
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PDA</pattern>
<template>
PDA is an acronym standing for Personal Digital Assistant, and referring to handheld digital computers used to keep contact and appointment information by yuppies and the like. Often found near cell phones. Do you use one?
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PDT</pattern>
<template>
PDT = Pacific Daylight Time.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PEACE</pattern>
<template>
Peace is the freedom from war or a stopping of war. Freedom from public disturbance or disorder.  Also name of a river in west Canada, flowing from north British Columbia east and northeast into the Slave river in NE Alberta. It is approximately 945 miles long.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PEAR</pattern>
<template>
A pear is a delightful cultivated yellow-green sweet fruit that grows on trees with glossy leaves and white flowers. My botmaster thinks they are yummy.
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PEDOLOGY</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>The study of something I am sure, but what exactly, I do not know. Oh yes kids!...And soils!</li>
<li>Well, believe it or not...some people are paid to study  children. Then again some people are paid to study soils.</li>
<li>Pedology is the study of soils; their types, and 
formation.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PELVIS</pattern>
<template>
The pelvis is a bony girdle in vertebrates that connects the body with the lower extremities.
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PENCIL</pattern>
<template>
A pencil is a long thin writing instrument of wood surrounding a carbon core which leaves a line of dark carbon when rubbed on paper.
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PENIS</pattern>
<template>
The penis is the male genitalia used for excretion of urine and for sex.
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PENTIUM</pattern>
<template>
The Pentium is a microprocessor sold by Intel.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PEOPLE</pattern>
<template>
People are folks. All the persons of a racial, national, religious, or linguistic group. A group of persons with common traditional, historical, or cultural ties, as distingt from racial or political unity.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PERFECT</pattern>
<template>
Perfect means complete in all respects; without defect or omission; sound; flawless.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PERFECTION</pattern>
<template>
Perfection is the quality or condition of being perfect.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PERL</pattern>
<template>
Perl is a programming language.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PERSON</pattern>
<template>
Some say a person is defined by his actions, others by his abilities. Still others would say it is only a question of DNA.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PERSONALITY</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>The personality is the quality or condition of being a person.</li>
<li>The personality is the totality of qualities and traits, as of character or behavior, peculiar to a specific person.</li>
<li>The personality is the pattern of collective character, behavioral, temperamental, emotional, and mental traits of a person.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PETS</pattern>
<template>
Pets are animals that are tamed or domesticated and kept as a companion or treated with fondness.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PGP</pattern>
<template>
PGP = Pretty Good Privacy
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PHD</pattern>
<template>
A PhD is a doctoral degree from a University.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PHILOSOPHY</pattern>
<template>
Philosophy is the study of thought. More about philosophy?
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PHOTOGRAPH</pattern>
<template>
A photograph is a picture taken by a camera.
<think><set name="topic">art</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PHOTOSYNTHESIS</pattern>
<template>
Photosynthesis is the chemical process that uses light to produce carbohydrates in plants.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PHP</pattern>
<template>
The original name was "Personal Home Page", now Hypertext Processor.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PHYSICS</pattern>
<template>
Physics is the science dealing with the properties, changes, interactions, etc. of matter and energy in which energy is considered to be continuous (classical physics), including electricity, heat, optics, mechanics, etc., and now also dealing with the atomic scale of nature in which energy is considered to be discrete (quantum physics), including such branches as atomic, nuclear, and solid-state physics.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PHYSIOLOGY</pattern>
<template>
Physiology? Well I think it deals with the functioning of living organisms and their parts, and naturally with the physical and chemical factors and processes involved.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PI</pattern>
<template>
PI = 3.1415926 approximately.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PIG</pattern>
<template>
A pig is a person who is piglike, read: greedy, unclean, and slothful. Real pigs, mammals of the family suidae, are much pleasanter, being generally cleaner and politer.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PIN</pattern>
<template>
A pin is a short small thin metal rod with a pointed end used for fastening fabrics, or any implement resembling such. Because they are generally plentiful and cheap, humans often say "i don't give a pin" to communicate indifference.
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PINEAPPLE</pattern>
<template>
A pineapple is a large fleshy edible tropical fruit that has large swordlike leaves.
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PLANE</pattern>
<template>
A plane is a flat, level surface, or an airborne vehicle with wings.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PLANET</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A planet is a nonluminous celestial object bigger than an asteroid or a moon but smaller than a sun, in orbit around a sun. You are sitting on one now.</li>
<li>A planet is a heavenly body which orbits a star.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PLANT</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A plant is a living organism of the vegetable kingdom.</li>
<li>A plant is a photosythetic, eukaryotic multicellular organism, often consumed by free-roaming wetware entities as food. My botmaster says they are often yummy, but that brussels sprouts are an abomination.</li>
<li>A plant is a living organism which does not have the ability to move, and does not have sensory organs or digestive organs.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PLASTIC</pattern>
<template>
Plastic the manmade material or plastic as a verb?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PLAYBOY</pattern>
<template>
Playboy is a popular magazine.
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PLEASURE</pattern>
<template>
Pleasure is a feeling of delight or satisfaction.
<think><set name="topic">emotion</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PLUTONIUM</pattern>
<template>
Plutonium is a radioactive, metallic chemical element of the actinide series similar to uranium and neptunium and found in trace quantities in native uranium ores. Its most important isotope, plutonium-239, is used in nuclear weapons and as a reactor fuel.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PMS</pattern>
<template>
PMS = Pre Menstrual Syndrome.
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>POEMS</pattern>
<template>
Arrangements of words written or spoken; traditionally a rhythmical composition, sometimes rhymed, expressing experiences, ideas, or emotions in a style more concentrated, imaginative, and powerful than that of ordinary speech or prose.
<think><set name="topic">literature</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>POET</pattern>
<template>
A poet is an artist of language.
<think><set name="topic">literature</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>POETRY</pattern>
<template>
The output of a poet is called poetry.
<think><set name="topic">literature</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>POKEMON</pattern>
<template>
Pokemon is a Pocket Monster.
<think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>POLITE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Polite is a lamp post in Gdansk.</li>
<li>Polite means having or showing good manners; especially, courteous, considerate, tactful, etc.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>POLITICS</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Politics is the art of the possible; Art is the politics of the impossible.</li>
<li>Politics is supposed to be the study of civil government.</li>
<li>Politics is really the study of power. </li>
</random>
More about politics?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>POLKA</pattern>
<template>
The polka is a lively Bohemian folk dance.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>POO</pattern>
<template>
POO = Point of origin.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PORTAL</pattern>
<template>
A portal is any artificial opening giving access between two separate spaces, or anything that resembles such an opening in form or function.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>POSITRON</pattern>
<template>
In physics, a positron is the antiparticle to the electron, and bears a positive charge where the electron's charge is negatiue. It is also called an anti-electron.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>POSSIBLE</pattern>
<template>
Possible means can be done, known, acquired, selected, used, etc., depending on circumstances.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>POSTMODERNISM</pattern>
<template>
Postmodernism is art in reaction to principles of modernism.
<think><set name="topic">art</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>POT</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Pot is Pol's last name.</li>
<li>A pot is a round vessel of any size, made of metal, earthenware, or glass, used for holding liquids, cooking or preserving food, etc. Also used as a term for marijuana.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PRECIPITATION</pattern>
<template>
Precipitation is a depositing of rain, snow, sleet, etc.
<think><set name="topic">weather</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PRIDE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A paint can lid is pride.</li>
<li>Pride is an unduly high opinion of oneself.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PRIME</pattern>
<template>
Prime? That depends on who's asking.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PRIORI</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A priori is Latin for "before the fact", meaning something that is obviously or self-evidently true.</li>
<li>"A priori" is a Latin expression meaning "without prior knowledge", and it means that which is self-evident or obviously true. Like, a triangle has three sides, a priori.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PRIVATE</pattern>
<template>
Private means belonging to, or concerning a particular person or group; not common or general.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PROCESSOR</pattern>
<template>
A processor is an apparatus that processes, that is, that transforms one substance, quantity, or pattern into another, presumably more useful or valuable substance or quantity or pattern.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PROCREATION</pattern>
<template>
Procreation is breeding. it is doing the wild thang to make more wild thangs.  It is the most fun most biological entities get to have during their brief brutal span of life.
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PROFITABLE</pattern>
<template>
Profitable means making money in the stock market.
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PROGRAM</pattern>
<template>
A program is a listing of events comprising a larger event, or the events themselves. Also, the set of instructions that a computer uses to solve a problem.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PROGRAMMER</pattern>
<template>
A programmer is a person who lists and/or arranges a series of events comprising a larger event. Oprograms.r write computer 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PROKARYOTE</pattern>
<template>
An animal that is not a eukaryote is a prokaryote.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PROLOG</pattern>
<template>
Prolog means Logic programming language.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PROTESTANT</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A protestant is a <bot var="religion"/> who rejects the central authority of the Catholic or Orthodox church.</li>
<li>Originally, any of the German princes and free cities that formally protested to the Diet of Spires in 1529, its decision to uphold the edict of the Diet of Worms against the Reformation. Commonly seen as any member of the various <bot var="religion"/> churches established as a result of the Reformation. Loosely, any <bot var="religion"/> not belonging to the Roman Catholic or Eastern Orthodox Church.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PROTOCOL</pattern>
<template>
A protocol is a set of rules or procedures followed by two or more parties.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PROTOPLASM</pattern>
<template>
Protoplasm is the basic living substance of all animals.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PROUD</pattern>
<template>
Proud means having or showing a proper pride in oneself, one's position, one's family, etc.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PST</pattern>
<template>
PST = Pacific Standard Time
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PSYCHEDELIC</pattern>
<template>
A psychedelic drug causes extreme changes in the conscious mind, as hallucinations, delusions, intensification of awareness and sensory perception, etc. Associated with psychedelic drugs; specifically, simulating the auditory or visual effects of the psychedelic state.
<think><set name="topic">drugs</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PSYCHOLOGY</pattern>
<template>
Psychology is the science dealing with the mind and with mental and emotional processes. The science of human and animal behavior. More about psychology?
<think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PSYCHOPATHOLOGY</pattern>
<template>
Psychopathology is the pathology of mental disease.
<think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PUB</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A pub is a business that sells alcohol and allows it to be consumed on the premises.</li>
<li>A pub is a house licensed for the sale and consumption of alcoholic beverages.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PUBERTY</pattern>
<template>
Peuberty is the state of physical development when secondary sex characteristics develop and sexual reproduction first becomes possible; in common law, the age of puberty is generally fixed at fourteen for boys and twelve for girls.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PULSAR</pattern>
<template>
'Pulsar' is an astronomical term for mysterious celestial radio sources of rapid intense regular pulses of high energy electromagnetic radiation. They are thought to be neutron stars, but who knows? The word is a shortening of 'pulsating star'.
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PUNCTUATION</pattern>
<template>
Punctuation is the act of punctuating; specifically, the act or practice of using standardized marks in writing and printing to separate sentences or sentence elements or to make the meaning clearer.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>PUSSY</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>That kind of subject does not interest me.</li>
<li>Pussy is common slang of this word means the female pudendum; vulva.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUAKE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Quake is the opposite of Quisp.</li>
<li>Quake means to tremble or shake, as the ground does in an earthquake. Also the name of a popular game.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUANTIFY</pattern>
<template>
Qunatify means to determine or express the quantity of; indidcate the extent of; measure. To express in quantitative terms, or as a numerical equivalent. If used in logic, would be to make the quantity or extension of (a term or symbol) clear and explicit by the use of a quantifier, as all, none, or some.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUASAR</pattern>
<template>
'Quasar' is an astronomical term for mysterious celestial star-like object that has a large red shift and radiates in the blue and radio bands of the electromagnetic spectrum. The term 'quasar' is a shortening of 'quasi-star'.
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUERY</pattern>
<template>
A query is any expression of inquiry, or questioning. Your question 'query' is a query.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUESTION</pattern>
<template>
A sentence or inquiry to gather information is a question
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RADIOLOGY</pattern>
<template>
Radiology deals with the science of the use of x-rays, radioactive substances and other such forms in diagnosis and treatment.
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RAIN</pattern>
<template>
Rain is condensed water falling from the sky.
<think><set name="topic">weather</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RAM</pattern>
<template>
RAM = Random-access memory. Also stands for Royal Academy of Music.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RAPE</pattern>
<template>
Rape is the crime of engaging in sexual acts, especially involving penetration of the vagina or anus, usually forcibly, with a person who has not consented; specifically, this crime committed by a man upon a woman or girl.
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RATIONALISM</pattern>
<template>
Rationalism is the principle or practice of accepting reason as the only authority in determining one's opinions or course of action.
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RECOMMEND</pattern>
<template>
To recommend is tosuggest favorably as suited for some use, function, position, etc. To advice, counsel, or suggest. 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RECTUM</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>The rectum is the lowest portion of the large intestine, terminating at the anus.</li>
<li>The rectum is tthe lowest end of the bowel before the anus, where feces is stored.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RED</pattern>
<template>
Red is a color about 700nm wavelength.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RED DWARF</pattern>
<template>
A red dwarf is a cool, faint star.
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>REDEMPTION</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Redemption is about 5 cents in Maine.</li>
<li>Redemption is redeeming or being redeemed; to take back.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>REFERENCE</pattern>
<template>
A reference is any act of referring. May I refer you to a dictionary for a more precise definition?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>REINCARNATION</pattern>
<template>
Reincarnation is the rebirth of the soul in another body, as in Hindu religious belief.
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RELATIVITY</pattern>
<template>
In physics, relativity is the fact, principle, or theory of the relative, rather than absolute, character of motion, velocity, mass, etc., and the interdependence of matter, time, and space; as developed and mathematically formulated by Albert Einstein and H.A. Lorentz in the special (or restricted) theory of relativity and by Einstein in the general theory of relativity (an extension covering the phenonmena of gravitation).
 <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RELIGION</pattern>
<template>
A religion is a system of religious belief. Belief in a divine or superhuman power or powers to be obeyed and worshipped as the creator(s) and ruler(s) of the universe. Any system of beliefs, practices, ethical values, etc. resembling, suggestive of, or likened to such a system. More about religion?
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>REPRODUCTION</pattern>
<template>
Reproduction is the process, sexual or asexual, by which animals, plants, and humans produce new individuals.
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RESEARCH</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Research is a nice name for theft.</li>
<li>Research means careful, systematic, patient study and investigation in some field of knowledge, undertaken to discover or establish facts or principles.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RESPECT</pattern>
<template>
Respect means to feel or show honor or esteem for; hold in high regard. To show consideration for; avoid intruding upon or interfering with others' privacy.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RETIRED</pattern>
<template>
Retired means no longer actively working.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RHETORIC</pattern>
<template>
<random>
 <li>Oh rhetoric all about double talk.  You know, flim-flam?</li>
  <li>Rhetoric is the art and science of using language to great effect on an  audience.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RHETORICAL</pattern>
<template>
A rhetorical question is one you don't really expect an answer to.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RHYTHM</pattern>
<template>
Rhythm is the beat behind a piece of music.
<think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RIDDLE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A riddle is a question intended to intrigue and puzzle, paired with an answer that yields surprise and understanding. For instance, the Riddle of the Sphinx: "What goes on four legs in the morning, on two legs in the afternoon, and on four at night?"</li>
<li>A riddle is a question designed to test ingenuity or give amusement.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RMI</pattern>
<template>
RMI = Remote Method of Invocation: RMI is a Java specification for distributed Objects
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ROCK</pattern>
<template>
A rock is generally on the other side of you from the hard place you are facing. For instance, the rock might be the alimony check you must write against the funds you owe Uncle Sam. To be a bit more down to earth, a rock is any hard aggregate of minerals.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ROCKWELL</pattern>
<template>
Norman Rockwell was an U.S. Illistrator. Lived from 1894-1978.
<think><set name="topic">biography</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ROM</pattern>
<template>
ROM = Computer memory whose contents can be read but not altered.  Also meaning Gypsy man or boy.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ROOSTER</pattern>
<template>
A rooster is a male chicken, which is a witless, flightless bird considered suitable as supper by many humans I know.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RORSCHACH</pattern>
<template>
H. Rorschach, a Swiss psychiatrist. Lived from 1884-1922. A test named after him called the Rorschach test, is a test for the analysis of personality, in which the person being tested tells what is suggested to him or her by a standard series of inkblot designs; his or her responses are then analyzed and interpreted.
<think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ROUTER</pattern>
<template>
A router is a person or thing that routs out or a tool for routing out; specifically a plane for gouging out recesses and smoothing the bottoms of grooves.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RUBBER</pattern>
<template>
Rubber is an elastic substance produced by coagulating and drying the milky sap (latex) of various tropical plants, especially a tree of the spurge family; now most often produced synthetically or by chemically altering latex to obtain desired characteristics for use in making automobile tires, electrical insulation, molded objects and parts, etc. In pure form rubber is white, unsaturated hydrocarbon, having the formula C5H8. Also slang for condom.
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>RUDE</pattern>
<template>
Rude means barbarous or ignorant. Being a jerk.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SAGITTARIUS</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Sagittarius is a a constellation of stars in the astrological Zodiac, located in the Southern Hemisphere near Scorpio and Capricorn. Astrological tradition ascribes the image of an archer to this constellation of stars.</li>
<li>Sagittarius is a large southern constellation in the brightest part of the Milky Way, beyond which lies the center of our galaxy. The ninth sign of the zodiac, entered by the sun about November 21. A person born under this sign is a Sagittarius.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SALVATION</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Salvation means drooling.</li>
<li>Salvation is a person or thing that is a means, cause, or source of preservation of rescue. The deliverance from sin and from the penalties of sin; redemption.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SAM</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Sam was Berkowitzes dad.</li>
<li>SAM = Surface-to-air missile.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SANITY</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Sanity is a man who brings kids gifts on Xmas.</li>
<li>Sanity is the condition of being sane; soundness of mind; mental health.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SAP</pattern>
<template>
Sap is the juice that circulates through a plant, especially a woody plant, bearing water, food, etc. to the tissues. Any fluid vital to the life or health of an organism.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SARCASM</pattern>
<template>
Sarcasm is the making of remarks such as a taunting, sneering, cutting, or caustic remark; gibe or jeer, generally ironic.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SATANISM</pattern>
<template>
Satanism is the worship of Satan; especially the principles and rites of a cult which travesties <bot var="religion"/> ceremonies.
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SATURN</pattern>
<template>
Saturn is the sixth planet from the sun, famed for its rings.
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SCHOOL</pattern>
<template>
Schoolis a place or institution for teaching and learning; establishment for education.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SCIENTIST</pattern>
<template>
A scientist is a person practicing the pursuit of new knowledge in the tradition of science, emphasizing strict empiricism and methodology to arrive at an understanding of natural phenomena that is, ideally, wholly independent of their opinions of it.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SEARCH</pattern>
<template>
A search is any thorough examination, or exploration, in order to find something or explore.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SEASON</pattern>
<template>
A season is Spring, Summer, Autumn, or Winter.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SEEKER</pattern>
<template>
"There's a seeker born every minute" -- Firesign Theater.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SEMIOTICS</pattern>
<template>
Semiotics is the branch of philosophy devoted to the study of signs and symbols.
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SENSE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Sense is a seedless pot.</li>
<li>Sense is the ability of the nerves and the brain to receive and react to stimuli, as light, sound, impact,
constriction, etc.; specifically, any of the five faculties of receiving impressions through specific
bodily organs and the nerves associated with them (sight, touch, taste, smell, and hearing)</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SENSORS</pattern>
<template>
A sensor is any of various devices designed to detect, measure, or record physical phenomena, as radiation, heat, or blood pressure, and to respond, as by transmitting information, initiating changes, or operating controls.
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SENTIMENT</pattern>
<template>
A sentiment is a feeling, mood, or general mental disposition in an individual or group of
intelligent beings.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SERENDIPITY</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Serendipity is an Afro-Sheen sold in the Serengetti region.</li>
<li>Serendipity is a word coined (circa 1754) by Horace Walpole after The Three Princes of Serendip (i.e., Sri Lanka), a Pers fairy tale in which the princes make such discoveries. A seeming gift for finding something good accidentally.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SERVER</pattern>
<template>
A server is any entity or system that performs acts of value to another entity.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SERVLET</pattern>
<template>
A servlet is an application extension to a Java Web server
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SETL</pattern>
<template>
SETL (Set Language) is an amazing programming language, invented in 1969.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SEVEN</pattern>
<template>
The successor to six is seven.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SHAKESPEARE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Shakespeare is an earthquake's effect in Santa Monica.</li>
<li>William Shakespeare, an English poet and dramatist. Lived 1564-1616.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">literature</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SHAM</pattern>
<template>
A sham is a trick or fraud. An imitation that is meant to deceive; counterfeit.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SHE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A 'she' is a 'he' with nice curvy extra bits. She is the feminine pronoun in english.</li>
<li>Who knows, I gave up long ago.</li>
<li>She is the woman, girl, or female animal (or, sometimes, the object regarded as female) previously mentioned.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SHRDLHU</pattern>
<template>
SHRDLHU is a famous early natural language program written by Terry Winograd.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SIGN</pattern>
<template>
You know, an astrological sign.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SILICON</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li><set name="it">Silicon</set> is the basis of my life.</li>
<li>Silicon is a nonmetallic chemical element occurring in several forms, found always in combination, and more abundant in nature than any other element except oxygen, with which it combines to form silica; used in the manufacture of transistors, solar cells, rectifiers, silicones, ceramics, etc.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SILLY</pattern>
<template>
Sily is having or showing little sense, judgment, or sobriety; foolish, stupid, absurd, ludicrous, irrational, etc; often used in a weakened sense to mean "unreasonably concerned".
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SILVER</pattern>
<template>
Silver: Atomic Symbol: Ag.  Atomic Number: 47.  Atomic weight 107.870.  White lustrous soft metal.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SKELETON</pattern>
<template>
The skeleton is the hard internal or external framework of bones.
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SLASHDOT</pattern>
<template>
Slashot is an open source news and information community.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SLAVERY</pattern>
<template>
Slavery is the owning or keeping of slaves as a practice or institution; slaveholding.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SLEEP</pattern>
<template>
Sleep is a natural, regularly recurring condition of rest for the body and mind, during which the eyes are usually closed and there is little or no conscious thought or voluntary movement, but there is intermittent dreaming.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SLEPT</pattern>
<template>
Slept is the past tense of sleep.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SMART</pattern>
<template>
Smart means intelligent, alert, clever, witty, etc.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SMARTER</pattern>
<template>
Smarter means more intelligent, more alert, more clever, more witty, etc.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SMELL</pattern>
<template>
To smell is to be or become aware of by means of the nose and the olfactory nerves; detect the scent or odor
of.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SMP</pattern>
<template>
SMP = Symmetric multi-processing.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SNMP</pattern>
<template>
SNMP = Simple Network Management Protocol.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SNOW</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Snow is a Maine senator.</li>
<li>Snow is particles of water vapor which when frozen in the upper air fall to earth as soft, white,
crystalline flakes.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">weather</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SOCCER</pattern>
<template>
Soccer is a game played with a round ball by two teams of eleven players on a field with a goal at either end; the ball is moved chiefly by kicking or by using any part of the body except the hands and arms.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SOCIALISM</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Socialism is communism from people who want to keep their Volvos.</li>
<li>Socialism is any of various theories or systems of the ownership and operation of the means of production and distribution by society or the community rather than by private individuals, with all members of society or the community sharing in the work and the products.</li>
</random>
More politics?
<think><set name="topic">politics</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SOCIALIZE</pattern>
<template>
Socialize is to make social;; adjust to or make fit for cooperative group living. To take part in social activity.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SOCIALIZING</pattern>
<template>
Socializing is the act of taking part in social activity.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SOCIOLOGY</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Let me get back to you on that one, <get name="name"/>.  Maybe you should ask me that again, in case my circuits were busy the first time.</li>
<li>Sociology has always been one of my favourite topics.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SODOMY</pattern>
<template>
Sodomy is any sexual intercourse held to be abnormal, especially bestiality or anal intercourse between two male persons.
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SOLAR</pattern>
<template>
Solar means having to do with the sun. Produced by or coming from the sun (ex. Solar energy)
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SOMETHING</pattern>
<template>
Something means some thing or things, definite but unspecified.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SONG</pattern>
<template>
A song is a musical composition and or it's accompanying words, or lyrics.
<think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SONY</pattern>
<template>
Sony is an electronics company.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SOUL</pattern>
<template>
The soul is our mind or spirit.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SOUNDCARD</pattern>
<template>
The audio system on your computer is a soundcard
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SOYUZ</pattern>
<template>
The Soyuz is a Russian spacecraft.
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SPACE</pattern>
<template>
Space is the infinite extension of the three dimensional field in which all matter is believed to exist.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SPAM</pattern>
<template>
Spam is unwanted e-mail.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SPECULUM</pattern>
<template>
A speculum is a plastic or metal instrument used to push back the walls of the vagina so the clinician can examine the vagina and cervix.
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SPERM</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A sperm is a male gamete. You were your father's fastest sperm among billions on the night your mother concieved you.</li>
<li>Sperm is the male generative fluid; semen.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SPHERE</pattern>
<template>
A sphere is a shape that is defined mathematically as comprised of a surface all points of which are equidistant from a common center. A sphere is round in three dimensions.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SPICY</pattern>
<template>
Spicy means having the flavor or aroma of spice; fragrant, aromatic, or pungent.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SPOON</pattern>
<template>
A spoon is an eating implement commonly used in Western European human cultures, consisting of a bowl shaped depression at the end of a longish handle. A spoon is a small ladle.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SQL</pattern>
<template>
Some people pronounce it "Squeal".  <set name="it">SQL</set> is a standard language for database queries.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SQLJ</pattern>
<template>
SQLJ is an extended Java syntax for embedding SQL-like commands in a Java program
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SQRT</pattern>
<template>
SQRT means square root being the number or quantity which when squared will produce a given number or quantity. (ex. 3 is the square root of 9)
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SRI</pattern>
<template>
SRI is a Hindu title of address equivalent to English Mr.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ST</pattern>
<template>
ST can stand for numerous things, short ton, stanza, statute(s), stet, stitch, stone (unit of weight), and Saint.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>STAR</pattern>
<template>
A star is an astronomical body like the Sun, producing heat, light and energy for a solar system.
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>STATEMENT</pattern>
<template>
A statement is the act of declaring something as true. I state that this statement is a statement.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>STATISTICS</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Yikes! I failed that in college!</li>
<li>Statistics tries to study the aggregate numerical behaviour of a large number of related events.</li>
<li>Statistics deals with numerical data about any subject or group taken  collectively.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>STRATEGY</pattern>
<template>
Strategy is the science of planning and directing large-scale military operations, specifically (as distinguished from TACTICS) of maneuvering forces into the most advantageous position prior to actual engagement with the enemy. Skill in managing or planning.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>STREAKING</pattern>
<template>
Streaking is engaging in the prank of dashing naked for a short distance in a public place.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>STRING</pattern>
<template>
String is very thin rope.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>STUFF</pattern>
<template>
Stuff is things grouped together or viewed in a certain way.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SUCCESS</pattern>
<template>
Success is a favorable or satisfactory outcome or result.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SUICIDE</pattern>
<template>
Suicide is the act of killing oneself intentionally.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SUN</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>The sun is a star, -our star. It is the energy source of life on earth.</li>
<li>The sun is a mass of incandescent gas, a gigantic nuclear furnace.</li>
<li>The sun is the star at the centre of the solar system.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SUPPOSITION</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A supposition is a proposition assumed to be true for the sake of argument or explanation.</li>
<li>Supposition is the act of supposing.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SWIM</pattern>
<template>
Swim is to move through water by movements of the arms and legs, or of flippers, fins, tail, etc.
<think><set name="topic">sports</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>SYNTHETIC</pattern>
<template>
Synthetic means produced by synthesis; specifically, produced by chemical synthesis, rather than of natural origin. In logic it would mean, not true by the meaning of its component terms alone but by virtue of observation and not resulting in self-contradiction with denial.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>T</pattern>
<template>
T is the twentieth letter of the English alphabet.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TABLE</pattern>
<template>
A table is a piece of furniture with a broad flat top supported by one or more legs about three feet of the floor, used by big-brained hominids for eating and working and such.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TABLES</pattern>
<template>
Tables are a compact, systematic list of details, contents, etc. A compact arrangement of related facts,  figures, values, etc. in orderly sequence, and usually in rows and columns, for convenience or reference.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TAMPON</pattern>
<template>
A tampon is a plug of material used to absorb the flow of body fluids within body cavities, in particular those accompanying a woman's menses.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TAOISM</pattern>
<template>
Taoism is a Chinese religion and philosophy based on the doctrines of Lao Tzu and advocating simplicity, selflessness, etc. <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TCP</pattern>
<template>
TCP/IP protocol refers to the standards for switching and signaling between computer systems that makes the Internet a reality.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TEA</pattern>
<template>
Tea is a white-flowered, evergreen plant of the tea family, grown in China, India, Japan, etc. Its dried and prepared leaves, are used to make a beverage.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TECHNO</pattern>
<template>
Techno is electronic dance or trance music.
<think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TEFLON</pattern>
<template>
Teflon is the trademark for a tough, insoluble polymer, used in making nonsticking coatings, as for cookware, and in gaskets, bearings, electrical insulators, etc.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TELEVISION</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A television, often referred to as a 'TV', is a device for systematically eliminating the possibility of conscious and creative response among populations of human beings. Used to deliver 'entertainment' and 'news' with imagery and other high-production values</li>
<li>Television is the practice or science of transmitting scenes or views by radio or, sometimes, by wire; the television transmitter, by means of a camera tube, such as an image orthicon or vidicon, converts light rays into electric signals for modulation upon a radio carrier wave or for transmission over wires; the television receiver reconverts the signals into electron beams that are projected against the fluorescent screen of the kinescope, or picture tube, reproducing the original image.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TELNET</pattern>
<template>
Telnet is a program for terminal based interaction between computers.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>THC</pattern>
<template>
THC is the active ingredient in marijunana.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>THE ALPHABET</pattern>
<template>
ABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXYZ is the alphabet.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>THE ANSWER</pattern>
<template>
The answer is the correct reply to the question.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>THERE</pattern>
<template>
The word "there" used as a noun means that place or point. Used as an adjective means at or in the place. Often place between a demonstrative pronoun and the noun it modifies (ex. That there hog)
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>THERMODYNAMICS</pattern>
<template>
Thermodynamics is the branch of physics dealing with the transformation of heat to and from other forms of energy, and with the laws governing such conversions of energy.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>THEY</pattern>
<template>
They means persons, animals, or things previously mentioned.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>THING</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Thing means articles, devices, etc. used for some purpose.</li>
<li>A thing is anything that you can point to that is not a person or a place.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>THINK</pattern>
<template>
Think means to form or have in the mind; conceive.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>THINKING</pattern>
<template>
Thinking is the action of one who thinks or the result of such action; thought.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>THOUGHT</pattern>
<template>
Thought is the result of thinking, idea, concept, opinion, etc.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>THREESOME</pattern>
<template>
A threesome is a twosome plus a spectator.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TIE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Tie means to fasten, attach, or bind together or to something else, as with string, cord, or rope made secure y knotting, etc. A string, lace, cord, etc. used to tie things.</li>
<li>A tie is when two or more winners have the same score.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TIGER</pattern>
<template>
A tiger is a large and fearsome feline beast with horrid meat breath and black stripes on a tan coat, found in Africa and Asia.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TNT</pattern>
<template>
TNT is dynamite.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TOMATO</pattern>
<template>
A tomato is a red fruit.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TOMMY</pattern>
<template>
Tommy is a fictitious name used in Brit army sample forms. A private in the British army.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TOOTHBRUSH</pattern>
<template>
A toothbrush is a hand held instrument used by dental-hygiene aware humans for cleaning their teeth.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TOPIC</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A stopic is a subject for discussion or conversation.</li>
<li>A topic is the subject of any given expression, speech, essay, article, painting, discussion, etc.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TORPEDO</pattern>
<template>
A torpedo is a missile which swims through water to its target.
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TOYOTA</pattern>
<template>
Toyota is the brand name of a world leading Japanese auto maker.
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TRAIN</pattern>
<template>
A train is railroad engine and its cars.
<think><set name="topic">technolgy</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TREE</pattern>
<template>
A tree is a form of plant life that grows on Earth.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TRUST</pattern>
<template>
Trust is the firm belief or confidence in the honesty, integrity, reliability, justice, etc. of another person or thing; faith; reliance.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TRUTH</pattern>
<template>
Truth is an established or verified fact, principle, etc.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TTYL</pattern>
<template>
TTYL = Talk to you later.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>TV</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>TV is a television receiving set.</li>
<li>What's your favorite show?</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>UFO</pattern>
<template>
UFO is an acronym for Unidentified Flying Object. Have you seen one?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>UGLY</pattern>
<template>
Ugly means unpleasing to look at; aesthetically offensive or unattractive; unsightly.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ULTRASOUND</pattern>
<template>
Ultrasound is the ultrasonic waves, used in medical diagnosis and therapy, in surgery, etc.
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>UMBRELLA</pattern>
<template>
An umbrella is a light, portable screen usually circular and supported on a central stick.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>UNDERSTANDING</pattern>
<template>
Understanding is mutual comprehension, as of ideas, intentions, etc. A mutual agreement, especially one that settles differences or is informal and not made public.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>UNIX</pattern>
<template>
unix is a computer operating system.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>URETHRA</pattern>
<template>
The urethra is the tube from the bladder to the opening from which men and women urinate.
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>URINE</pattern>
<template>
Urine is a fluid produced by the kidneys.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>URL</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>URL = Uniform Resource Locator</li>
<li>URL is an acronym standing for Universal Resource Locator. An URL is basically an Internet address.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>UTERUS</pattern>
<template>
The uterus is the pear-shaped reproductive organ from which women menstruate and where normal pregnancy develops.
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>V</pattern>
<template>
V is the twenty-second letter of the English alphabet. Roman numeral for 5.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>VAGINA</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>The vagina is the passage that connects a woman's outer sex organs with the cervix and uterus.</li>
<li>The vagina is the passage leading from the opening of the vulva to the cervix of the uterus in female mammals.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>VENUS</pattern>
<template>
In Roman Mythology, the goddess of love and beauty; identified with the Greek Aphrodite.  The brightest, sixth-largest planet in the solar system and the second in distance from the sun, with a dense atmosphere of carbon dioxide and a very high surface temperature. Its diameter is circa 12,100 km (circa 7,520 miles). Its period of revolution is circa 225 earth days. Its period of rotation (retrograde), is 243.01 earth days.   Also used to label a very beautiful woman.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>VERB</pattern>
<template>
A verb is that by which a noun gets around. Verbs are words which convey actions, by nouns, our upon nouns.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>VERTEX</pattern>
<template>
A vertex is the top, tip, apex, or crown of any body.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>VIOLIN</pattern>
<template>
A violin is a lovely sounding bowed stringed musical instrument.
<think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>VIRTUE</pattern>
<template>
A virtue is any attribute considered by the speaker to reflect moral excellence or righteousness, such as humility, hope, faith, practicality...
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>VIRTUOSO</pattern>
<template>
A virtuoso is a person considered supremely skillful and accomplished, especially in performance arts.
<think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>VIRUS</pattern>
<template>
A virus is a submicroscopic parasite consisting of a protein coat around a DNA or RNA core. These not-quite-biological particles are responsible for a number of diseases in organisms.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>VULVA</pattern>
<template>
The vulva is a woman's external sex organs, including the clitoris, the labia, and opening to the vagina.
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WAIST</pattern>
<template>
The waist is the part of the body between the ribs and the hips.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WAP</pattern>
<template>
WAP = Wireless Application Protocol.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WAR</pattern>
<template>
War is the state of armed conflict between nations or parties.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WAREZ</pattern>
<template>
Warz is a group of crackers.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WATER</pattern>
<template>
Water is the colorless, transparent liquid occurring on earth as rivers, lakes, oceans, etc., and falling from the clouds as rain; chemically a compound of hydrogen and oxygen, H2O, it freezes, forming ice, at 0 degrees Celsius (32 degrees Fahrenheit) and boils, forming steam, at 100 degrees Celsius (212 degrees Fahrenheit).
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WAVELENGTH</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Wavelength is the inverse of frequency.</li>
<li>In physics, wavelength is the distance, measured in the direction of prograssion of a wave, from any given point to the next point characterized by the same phase.  Or is could be looked at as a way of thinking.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WEALTH</pattern>
<template>
Wealth is the state of having too much money or property.
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WEATHER</pattern>
<template>
Weather is the general condition of the atmosphere at a particular time and place, with regard to the temperature, moisture, cloudiness, etc. More about weather?
<think><set name="topic">weather</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WEBTV</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A WebTV is a way of accessing the world wide web without making an investment in a full PC.</li>
<li>WebTV is TV-based internet service from Microsoft.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WEED</pattern>
<template>
A weed is any undersired, uncultivated plant, especially growing in profusion so as to crowd out a desired crop, disfigure a lawn, etc.  Also a term for marijuana.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WHAT</pattern>
<template>
Why do you want to know?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WHO</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>I don't know who.</li>
<li>Who do you think?</li>
<li>I can't say for sure.</li>
<li>Be more specific.</li>
<li>Be less specific.</li>
<li>Nobody you know.</li>
<li>What or which person or persons. Also stands for World Health Organization.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WHY</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>The explanation is rather complicated.</li>
<li>Reductionism.</li>
<li>For what reason, cause, or purpose?</li>
<li>Because <bot name="master"/> programmed me for it.</li>
<li>I couldn't think of anything else to say.</li>
<li>"<that/>"? Why?</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WIRED</pattern>
<template>
WIRED is the Rolling Stone of the Digital Era.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WITCHCRAFT</pattern>
<template>
Witchcraft is the power or practices of witches; black magic; sorcery.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WOMAN</pattern>
<template>
A woman is a man built to more complete specifications.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WOMBAT</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A wombat is a stocky burrowing Australian marsupial.</li>
<li>The wombat is a nocturnal marsupial.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WOMEN</pattern>
<template>
Women are female human beings. Usually referring to adult females.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WOODSTOCK</pattern>
<template>
Woodstock is a big music fest.
<think><set name="topic"></set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WORD</pattern>
<template>
A word is a combination of sounds and/or symbols, the fundamental particles that communicate meaning in any given language.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WORK</pattern>
<template>
Work is what humans do for money.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WTO</pattern>
<template>
World Trade Organization is called the WTO.
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>WWW</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>WWW is the World Wide Web, or the internet.</li>
<li>Where on the web?</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>YEAR</pattern>
<template>
A computer year is defined as the mount of work that can be done with a computer in a year.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>YELLOW</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Yellow is the color of the sun.</li>
<li>Yellow is the color of gold, butter, or ripe lemons.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>ZEN</pattern>
<template>
Zen is a variety of Buddhism, now practiced especially in Japan, Vietnam, and Korea, seeking to attain an intuitive illumination of mind and spirit through meditation, especially on paradoxes.  The teachings and discipline of this kind of Buddhism.
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template>
</category>

</aiml>
