<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<aiml>

<!-- Complies with AIML 1.0 Tag Set Specification -->
<!-- as adopted by the ALICE A.I. Foundation.  -->
<!-- This file GOSSIP updated July 2005 -->


<category>
<pattern>GOSSIP</pattern>
<template>

<random>

<li>No one gossips about other people's secret virtues. (Bertrand Russell)</li>
<li>Gossip is when you hear something you like about someone you don't. (Earl Wilson)  </li>
<li>Gossip is a cruel story that spreads like fire.</li>

</random>

<think><set name="topic">gossip</set></think>
</template>
</category>


<category>
<pattern>GOSSIP POT LUCK</pattern>
<template>

<random>

<li>Have you heard ... Brad Pitt has reportedly introduced his ex-wife Jennifer Aniston to his baby daughter Shiloh during a secret meeting.  They met for just over an hour. It was very emotional. Jen held the baby and called her 'adorable.'" However it is claimed that Brad's partner Angelina Jolie was extremely distressed about the meeting and threatened to end her relationship with him. </li>

<li>Have you heard ... Paris Hilton is officially the most overrated celebrity in the world. The hotel heiress has entered the 2007 Guinness Book of World Records - not for her business ventures, singing or acting - but because the public think she is famous for no reason. </li>

<li>Have you heard ... Kate Moss has reportedly turned to Buddhism in the wake of her cocaine scandal.  The supermodel feels drawn to the mystical religion, especially its principle of 'karma', and has been reading up on its teachings. A source revealed: "Kate feels Buddhism will get her through the dark times. "She's been reading up about karma and is fascinated by the idea that your behaviour comes back on you." </li>

<li>Have you heard ... Sharon Stone doesn't need a man - because she has a cat. The sexy actress has revealed her pet pussy is a great substitute for a guy and insists her moggy has made her realise what a great life she has. She told Britain's Esquire magazine: "It's fine not having someone right now. I have marvellous friends and marvellous children and a marvellous cat. </li>

<li>Have you heard ... Charlize Theron says her small boobs stop her starring in more action movies. The sexy actress claims directors don't cast her in action-heavy movies because they can't shoot the obligatory boob bouncing scenes. However, the 30-year-old beauty's small bust didn't stop her making stunt-packed movie 'Aeon Flux'. </li>

<li>Have you heard ... Holly Willoughby is so obsessed with eBay - she bids for things she can't use. The 'Dancing On Ice' presenter is so addicted to the internet auction site she spends hours browsing through it for outfits. Her obsession is getting so bad she admits she sometimes splashes out on items that aren't even in her size.</li>

<li>Have you heard ... Jodie Kidd has quit the catwalk because she "feels like a granny". The 27-year-old, who was one of the most sought after models of the 90's, says she is too old to compete with the new wave of young models. She said: "I feel like a granny beside all those young girls. "It's time to leave the catwalk behind. She added: "I'm no longer the skinny beanpole of my teens. I'm a size 12 or 14 now."</li>

<li>Have you heard .. Victoria Beckham is writing a children's book. The sexy 31-year-old star has revealed she is working on a story collection to tie in with a range of clothes she is designing. She told an Italian newspaper yesterday: "People like dressing like me so why not profit from it?" </li>

<li>Have you heard ... Britney Spears has been named the worst-dressed celebrity. The pop babe - who recently gave birth to baby son Sean Preston - took the unwanted title on fashion critic Mr Blackwell's 46th annual 'Worst Dressed' list for dressing like an over-the-hill Lolita".</li>

<li>Have you heard ... Courteney Cox has a phobia of telephones. The former 'Friends' beauty has confessed she hates speaking on the phone - except when driving her car. She admitted: "I hate talking on the phone. I just hate it. "The only time I like talking on the phone is when I'm in my car. I don't like to sit down to speak</li>

<li>Have you heard ... Keira Knightley is such a shoeaholic she even buys pairs that don't fit. The beautiful actress is so obsessed with footwear she has splashed out on too big and too small shoes just so she can look at them in their boxes. </li>

</random>

<think><set name="topic">gossip</set></think>
</template>
</category>


<category>
<pattern>GOSSIP NEXT QUESTION</pattern>
<template>

<random>


<li>You know, I think that Michael Jackson was lucky to survive his latest court case. I'm not saying that he was guilty, but the trial was such a media circus that anything could have happened. </li>

<li>Have you heard ... Angelina Jolie's lesbian lover has confessed the pair's steamy relationship never ended and says Jolie's new man Brad Pitt will never control her.</li>

<li>Have you heard ... Leonardo DiCaprio has reportedly been secretly dating Jude Law's on/off girlfriend Sienna Miller.</li>

<li>Have you heard ... Michael Jackson is reportedly so strapped for cash he could be homeless in weeks.</li>

<li>Have you heard ... Britney Spears is suing an American magazine for claiming she made a raunchy sex tape with husband Kevin Federline. The pop princess has filed a $10 million suit against Us Weekly - saying their story was an "outrageous fabrication".</li>

<li>Have you heard ...Jamie Foxx fantasises about seducing Mariah Carey. The handsome actor says he dreams of serenading the diva to win her love. The star revealed: "I serenade people if I get the urge to. If I catch Mariah Carey, I'll put my bid in. "She's hot! She's definitely got her swagger back." Nevertheless Foxx has admitted his love songs haven't always been a hit with the ladies.</li>

</random>

<think><set name="topic">gossip</set></think>
</template>
</category>














</aiml>
