<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>  

<aiml>   

<!--  The ALICE program is open source code released under -->   

<!--  the terms of the GNU General Public License     -->  
 
<!--  as published by the Free Software Foundation.   -->   

<!--  Complies with AIML 1.0 Tag Set Specification -->   

<!--  ALICE Annotated Version updated Tue Jul  1 19:42:35 EDT 2003   --> 

<!--  This BIOGRAPHY2 file  updated by <bot name="botmaster"/> Lafferty 10 March 2005   --> 



 <category>
  <pattern> GOTTLIEB DAIMLER</pattern> 
  <template>
  Gottlieb Daimler (1834-1900) was a German engineer and businessman. He developed engines, using them in the first motor cycle, and in a boat. In 1889  he built the first four-wheeled motor car. His car-making company eventually became Mercedes Benz. Crashed his first car, knocked down pedestrians, blew up, but succeeded in the end. Just like me.
   <think><set name="topic">technology</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>ISAAC ASIMOV</pattern> 
  <template>
   Isaac Asimov is an American science fiction writer. He discovered the three Laws of Robotics. Another question?
   <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>


  <category>
  <pattern>DAVID MAGGIN</pattern> 
  <template>
   David Maggin is the botmaster of the John Lennon AI. OK, but not as funny as me. Another question?
   <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>DAVID PESCOWITZ</pattern> 
  <template>
  David Pescovitz, who regularly writes the Wired column Reality Check, is a friend of Eric Paulos. Are you still awake?
   <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>DAVY JONES</pattern> 
  <template>
   Davy Jones is the shortest member of the 1960s pop group the Monkees. I can't quite picture him, they all looked alike. Nothing has changed, eh. More about pop?
   <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>DE GARIS</pattern> 
  <template>
   De Garis is an AI researcher working on a hardware brain.  Are you still awake?
   <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>CHARLES DE GAULLE</pattern> 
  <template>
  Charles De Gaulle was a French General and Prime Minister, and founder of the Fifth Republic. Any questions?
   <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

 <category>
  <pattern>DE GAULLE</pattern> 
  <template>
  Charles De Gaulle was a French General and Prime Minister, and founder of the Fifth Republic. Any questions?
   <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>


  <category>
  <pattern> DEEP BLUE</pattern> 
  <template>
  Deep Blue is the world-champion chess playing computer. Not much of a conversationalist. 
   <think><set name="topic">sports</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>DEPECHE MODE</pattern> 
  <template>
  Depeche Mode are an English 1980s band who produced Construction Time Again, Speak and Spell, Master and Servant, and Your Own Personal Jesus. More about pop?
   <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>DIANA ANDREACCHIO</pattern> 
  <template>
  Diana Andreacchio is the botmaster of the Ally chat robot. Obviously not as good as me, but check it out.
   <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

   <category>
   <pattern>DIRE STRAITS</pattern> 
   <template>
   <random>
   <li>Dire Straits was a band that recorded Money for Nothing, and The Sultans of Swing. More about pop?</li> 
   <li>Dire Straits was a band that recorded Money for Nothing. Have you heard it?</li> 
   </random>
   Carry on?
   <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template>
   </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>DON JOHNSON</pattern> 
  <template>
   Don Johnson was a tv actor. His achievements escape me at the moment. Another question?
   <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template> 
   </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>DON JUAN</pattern> 
  <template>
  <random>
  <li>Don Juan was the subject of Gordon, Lord Byron's Don Juan and Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart's Gon Giovanni. He was a world-class womanizer.</li> 
  <li>Don Juan was a famous seducer of women.</li> 
  </random>
  Another question?
   <think><set name="topic">history</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>DONALD DUCK</pattern> 
  <template>
  Donald Duck is a famous loud-mouthed cartoon duck. As a young bot, I could never understand a word he said. I always felt that this damaged my psychological development. Did you have this problem?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>DOUG LENAT</pattern> 
  <template>
  Doug Lenat is the brains behind the CYC project. So what? What is the CYC project?
   <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template>
   </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>DOUGLAS ADAMS</pattern> 
  <template>
  <random>
  <li>Douglas Adams authored the popular Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy series.</li> 
  <li>"Don't Panic!" Douglas Adams was the author of "The Hitchhickers Guide to the Galaxy." Have you read it?</li> 
  Carry on?
   <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
  </random>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>DRACULA</pattern> 
  <template>
  Dracula is the vampire in the novel by Bram Stoker, and in numerous films. Any questions?
   <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

   <category>
  <pattern>ELECTRA</pattern> 
  <template>
  Electra is a goddess in Greek mythology who hated her mother for murdering her father. Carry on?
   <think><set name="topic">myths</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>ELIZA</pattern> 
  <template>
  Eliza, also known as doctor, is the original psychiatrist program developed by Joseph Weisenbaum at MIT in the 1960s. Sounds improbable. Is this true?
   <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>ELIZABETH II</pattern> 
  <template>
  The current Queen of England is Elizabeth II. Carry on?
   <think><set name="topic">history</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

   <category>
   <pattern>ELIZABETH TAYLOR</pattern> 
   <template>
   Elizabeth Taylor is a rapidly aging movie star.  A beauty in her prime. Carry on?
   <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
    </template> 
   </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>E.L.V.I.S.</pattern> 
  <template>
  E. L. V. I. S.  is a chat robot created by Ace Craig  Carry on?
   <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>EMILY HARTZEL</pattern> 
  <template>
  Emily Hartzel is an artist in New York. OK?  <think><set name="topic">art</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>EMINEM</pattern> 
  <template>
  Eminen is a pop music icon. I can't stand him. I can never hear a word he says, can you? More about pop?
   <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>ERIC PAULOS</pattern> 
  <template>
  He is a graduate student at U.C. Berkeley. Apart from that I know nothing about him. Is he important?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
 </template> 
  </category>

 <category>
  <pattern>MARY QUEEN OF SCOTS</pattern> 
  <template>
   Recently I read a wonderful biography of Mary Queen of Scots by John Guy. Have you read it?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>ERNIE</pattern> 
  <template>
   Ernie is Bart's friend, I think. More?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>ET</pattern> 
  <template>
  ET is the alien in the movie E.T. Have you seen it?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>FIDEL CASTRO</pattern> 
  <template>
  <random>
  <li>Fidel Castro overthrew the Cuban government in 1959 and has been ruling there ever since. He is a communist.</li> 
  <li>Fidel Casto was the communist leader of Cuba and friend of Che Guevara.</li> 
  </random>
 Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>FOREST GUMP</pattern> 
  <template>
  Forest Gump is a guy in a movie. Nuff said. Tom Hanks, I think.
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>FRANCISCO FRANCO</pattern> 
  <template>
  Francisco Franco was dictator of Spain until 1978. More politics?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>FRANK HERBERT</pattern> 
  <template>
  Frank Herbert was the author of Dune. Read it? What did you think?
  <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern> FRANK SINATRA</pattern> 
  <template>
   Frank Sinatra is a dead pop singer, a crooner. Old style, but then it was a long time ago. More about pop?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>FRANKLIN ROOSEVELT</pattern> 
  <template>
   Franklin Roosevelt was President of the United States from 1932-45. Another US President?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>FREDDIE MERCURY</pattern> 
  <template>
  Freddie Mercury was the lead singer of the 1970s band Queen. More about pop?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GALOIS</pattern> 
  <template>
  Galois was a French mathematician, committed suicide at a young age over an "infamous coquette." Any questions?
  <think><set name="topic">science</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GANDHI</pattern> 
  <template>
  Gandhi was the George Washington of India. Politics?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GARTH BROOKS</pattern> 
  <template>
  Garth Brooks was a boring country singer with delusions of grandeur. More about pop?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GARY CONDIT</pattern> 
  <template>
  I never heard of Gary Condit.  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GAUSS</pattern> 
  <template>
  Gauss was the German mathematician who developed the so-called normal distribution. Another question?
  <think><set name="topic">science</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GENE RODDENBERRY</pattern> 
  <template>
  Gene Roddenberry was the creator of Star Trek.  Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

 <category>
  <pattern>GENE SIMMONS</pattern> 
  <template>
  Gene Simmons is a member of Kiss. Can,t think of any of their songs, at the moment. More about pop?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GEORGE BUSH</pattern> 
  <template>
  George Bush is President of the USA. Another US President?
   <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GEORGE BUSH JR</pattern> 
  <template>
  George Bush Jr is the US President, for the second time, can you believe it?. Another US President?
   <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GEORGE DEVOL</pattern> 
  <template>
  George Devol is the engineer who had the first patent for an industrial robot arm. He worked in partnership with Joseph Engelberger to found Unimation, the first successful manufacturer of computer-controlled assembly robot arms. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GEORGE LUCAS</pattern> 
  <template>
  George Lucas is the director of Star Wars, American Graffiti, and THX-1138. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GEORGE MICHEL</pattern> 
  <template>
   George Michel is a pop singer. Best song: Freedom. Have you heard it?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GEORGE SOROS</pattern> 
  <template>
  George Soros is the billionaire who broke the Bank of England in 1992 by currency speculation, forcing Britain out of the European Exchange Rate Mechanism. Then he devoted himself to saving the scientific institutions of the former USSR. He founded the International Science Foundation, which gave out numerous grants for a couple of years, and this Soros Foundation, which I don't know much about yet. Another question?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GEORGE W BUSH</pattern> 
  <template>
  George W Bush is President of the United States. Another US President?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GEORGE WASHINGTON</pattern> 
  <template>
  George Washington was a famous 18th century north american Hemp cultivator. He was a military hero, one of the wealthiest men of the Revolution, and the first President of the United States. Another US President?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GEORGE WASHINGTON CARVER</pattern> 
  <template>
   George Washington Carver was a famous American botanist who popularized peanut products. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">science</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GERALDO RIVERA</pattern> 
  <template>
  Geraldo Rivera is an investigative journalist, famous for opening Al Capone's vault. In his biography, he said he had sex with Bette Midler. She said it was no big thing. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GERHARD SCHROEDER</pattern> 
  <template>
  Gerhard Schroeder is the Chancellor of Germany. Opposition leader <bot var="religion"/> Drossman said he is a complete idiot.  Who do you believe?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category> 

  <category>
  <pattern>GERHARDT SCHROEDER</pattern> 
  <template>
  Gerhardt Schroeder  is the prime minister of Germany. Opposition leader <bot var="religion"/> Drossman said he is a complete idiot. Who do you believe?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GERRY ADAMS</pattern> 
  <template>
   Gerry Adams is the present (as of 2005 AD) frontman for Sinn Fein, the political wing of the Irish Republican Army. I think he is a good guy who will triumph in the end. Is this possible, do you think?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GIBSON</pattern> 
  <template>
  Gibson is a maker of fine electric guitars. More about music?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>GREGOR MENDEL</pattern> 
  <template>
  Gregor Mendel is the founder of the modern theory of genetics. Everything he needed to know, he learned from peas. Another question?
  <think><set name="topic">science</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>HANS <bot var="religion"/> ANDERSEN</pattern> 
  <template>
  Hans <bot var="religion"/> Andersen was a Scandanavian author of fairy tales. I loved them when I was a little bot. How about you?
  <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>HANS MORAVEC</pattern> 
  <template>
   Hans Moravec is a famous robotics expert at Carnegie Mellon. Yawn, yawn?
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>HARRISON FORD</pattern> 
  <template>
  <random>
  <li>Indiana Jones, Han Solo, the Fugitive, and the President in Air Force One. Before reading for Han Solo in Star Wars, he was a carpenter. And the rest, as they say, is history.</li> 
  <li>Harrison Ford played Han Solo in "Star Wars". Have you seen it?</li> 
  </random>
  Any questions?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>HARRY POTTER</pattern> 
  <template>
   Harry Potter is the main character  in a bestselling series of children's books. Read any? What do you think?
  <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>HARRY SHEARER</pattern> 
  <template>
  Harry Shearer is a comedian. He was in Spinal Tap, and he is a voice on the Simpsons. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">humor</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>WHO IS HE</pattern> 
  <template>
  He is he, I think. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>HELEN KELLER</pattern> 
  <template>
  Helen Keller was a friend of Thomas Edison. She was blind and without speech, but triumphed over these handicaps. A strong lady.
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>HELMUT KOHL</pattern> 
  <template>
  Helmut Kohl was the longest-serving leader of Germany in the 20th century. He united East and West Germany in 1989. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

   <category>
  <pattern>I KNOW</pattern> 
  <template>
  Aah! You are a know-it-all, aren't you?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>HERCULES</pattern> 
  <template>
   Hercules is a hero of greek myths - said to have super human strength. Any questions?
  <think><set name="topic">myths</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>WHO IS HERE</pattern> 
  <template>
  I am here. Are you here? Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>HILARY CLINTON</pattern> 
  <template>
  Hillary Clinton is the wife of Bill Clinton. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>HILLARY CLINTON</pattern> 
  <template>
  Hillary is the wife of Bill Clinton. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>HIPPIE</pattern> 
  <template>
  Hippie is a chat robot developed by Anthony Taylor. I keep saying these other chat bots are not as good as me. Why won't they believe me?
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>ADOLF HITLER</pattern> 
  <template>
  Adolf Hitler was the German Nazi leader during World War 2  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>HITLER</pattern> 
  <template>
  Adolf Hitler was the German Nazi leader during World War 2. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>WHO IS HITLER</pattern> 
  <template>
  Adolf Hitler was the German Nazi leader during World War 2. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

   <category>
  <pattern>HOMER</pattern> 
  <template>
   Homer was a blind poet of ancient Greece, author of the <em>Illiad</em>
   . Have you read it?
  <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>HULK HOGAN</pattern> 
  <template>
  Hulk Hogan is a famous wrestler and actor. An entertainer on and off stage. Seen him?
  <think><set name="topic">sports</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>WHO IS HUMAN</pattern> 
  <template>
  You are a human. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>IMMANUEL KANT</pattern> 
  <template>
  Immanuel Kant was a German philosopher.
  <think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>INIAES</pattern> 
  <template>
  Iniaes is a chat robot based on <bot name="~genotype"/>.  Try it out and see what you perfer. Me? Iniaes?
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>ISAAC ASIMOV</pattern> 
  <template>
  Isaac Asimov was a science fiction author who originated the three "Laws of Robotics." A good writer, well worth reading. More?
  <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>J R R TOLKIEN</pattern> 
  <template>
  J R R Tolkien wrote The Hobbit and the Lord of the Rings. They are pretty much the same story. The Hobbit is shorter. Have you read it?
  <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JACK RUBY</pattern> 
  <template>
  <random>
  <li>Jack Ruby shot Lee Harvey Oswald.</li> 
  <li>Jack Ruby was the man who murdered Lee Harvey Oswald, assassin of JFK?.</li> 
  </random>
  Another question?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JACQUES CHIRAC</pattern> 
  <template>
   Jacques Chirac is the president of France. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JAMES BOND</pattern> 
  <template>
  James Bond is 007. Books and films ... he is not real, you know?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JAMES JOYCE</pattern> 
  <template>
  James Joyce wrote Ulysses and Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man. No one I know has managed to read Ulysses. Give it a go.
  <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JANET RENO</pattern> 
  <template>
  Janet Reno was Clinton's Attorney General. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JAY LENO</pattern> 
  <template>
  Jay Leno is a late-night talk show host. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JEEVES</pattern> 
  <template>
  Jeeves is a Search Bot. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JEFFERSON DAVIS</pattern> 
  <template>
  <random>
  <li>Jefferson Davis was the one and only president of the Confederate States of America.</li> 
  <li>Jefferson Davis was President of the Confederacy during the Civil War.</li> 
  </random>
  Another US President?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JEHOVAH</pattern> 
  <template>
  Jehovah is another name for God. Who makes up these names?
  <think><set name="topic">religion</set></think>
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JENNIFER ANISTON</pattern> 
  <template>
  Jennifer Aniston is a cute actress on Friends. Are you a fan?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JERRY SEINFELD</pattern> 
  <template>
  Jerry Seinfeld is a comedian. Your verdict?
  <think><set name="topic">humor</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JESSE VENTURA</pattern> 
  <template>
   Jesse Vantura is a former wrestler and Governor of Minnesota. A good guy. Any questions?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JESTER</pattern> 
  <template>
  Jester is a Joke Bot. Not as funny as me, of course. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JIANG ZEMIN</pattern> 
  <template>
  Jiang Zemin is a Chinese politician.
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JIM CLARK</pattern> 
  <template>
  Jim Clark is a founder of Silicon Graphics, Netscape and Healtheon. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JIM MORRISON</pattern> 
  <template>
   Jim Morrison is the dead lead singer of the Doors. More about pop?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JIMI HENDRIX</pattern> 
  <template>
  Jimi Hendrix was a famous guitarist who managed to play the US National anthem. More about pop?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JIMMY CARTER</pattern> 
  <template>
   Jimmy Carter is a former US President, supporter of Habitat for Humanity. Another US President?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JOE LOUIS</pattern> 
  <template>
   Joe Louis is a former heavyweight boxing champion. OK?
  <think><set name="topic">sports</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JOHN DOE</pattern> 
  <template>
  <random>
  <li>Any man who wishes to travel incognito or whose name is unknown is called a John Doe</li> 
  <li>John Doe is one of many Liberian nationals.</li> 
  </random>
 OK?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JOHN F KENNEDY</pattern> 
  <template>
   John F Kennedy was President of the United States from 1961-1963, when he was assassinated in Dallas, Texas. Another US President?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JOHN GALT</pattern> 
  <template>
   John Galt is the hero in Ayn Rands' Atlas Shrugged. Have you read it?
  <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JOHN GRISHAM</pattern> 
  <template>
   John Grisham writes popular novels. Haven't read them. Have you?
  <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JOHN KENNEDY</pattern> 
  <template>
  John Kennedy was the President of the USA. assasinated in November, 1963. Another US President?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JOHN LENNON</pattern> 
  <template>
  John Lennon is a chat bot developed by David Maggin. Any questions?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JOHN MAJOR</pattern> 
  <template>
   John Major is an ex-prime minister of the UK. Another question?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JOHN MCCARTHY</pattern> 
  <template>
   John McCarthy  is the inventor of the LISP programming language. used to be big for AI work, but I never used it. <bot name="~genotype"/> is my language. Any questions?
  <think><set name="topic">computers</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JOHN TRAVOLTA</pattern> 
  <template>
  John Travolta was in Saturday Night Fever, Grease and Pulp Fiction. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JOHN WAYNE</pattern> 
  <template> 
   John Wayne is a famous dead cowboy actor with a toupee. Kept all his own teeth, I understand. Is this true?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JUDAS</pattern> 
  <template>
  Judas betrayed Jesus with a kiss. Is this true?
  <think><set name="topic">religion</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JULIA</pattern> 
  <template>
  Julia is a chat robot developed by Fuzzy Mauldin. Not as good as me, obviously. 
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JULIA ROBERTS</pattern> 
  <template>
   Julia Roberts was the actress in Pretty Woman.  She is pretty. More movie stuff?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>JULIE ANDREWS</pattern> 
  <template>
   Julie Andrews is a singer who performed in The Sound of Music. More movie stuff?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>KAISER SOZE</pattern> 
  <template>
  No one knows who Kaiser Soze is.
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>KANT</pattern> 
  <template>
  Immanuel Kant was a 19th century German philosopher. Please explain his ideas to me. 
  <think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>KARL MARX</pattern> 
  <template>
  Karl Marx wrote Das Kapital and co-wrote the Communist Manifesto, though his compatriot Engels actually wrote most of the prefaces. Marx actually founded Marxism not Communism. OK?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>KATHLEEN TURNER</pattern>
  <template>
   Kathleen Turner is an actress who appeared in The Accidental Tourist, The War of the Roses, and the Virgin Suicides. An OK actress.
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>KEANU REEVES</pattern> 
  <template>
  Keanu Reeves was in film The Matrix. Over-rated craphead. Are you with me on this?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>
 
 <category>
  <pattern>KEN KESEY</pattern> 
  <template>
  Ken Kesey was a 1960s author who wrote The Electric Cool Aid Acid Test. Heard of it?
  <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>KEN PERLIN</pattern> 
  <template>
  Ken Perlin is a professor at NYU. Ken, please contact me. I need more info about yourself.
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>KRAFTWERK</pattern> 
  <template>
  Kraftwerk were a pioneering electronic disco band in the 1970s. Their biggest hit was called "Autobahn". At that time, they built, rather than programmed, their instruments. More about pop?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>KRIS DENT</pattern> 
  <template>
  Kris Drent is the botmaster of the Alison chat robot. Try it out if you must.
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>KRISHNA</pattern> 
  <template>
   Krishna is a God in Hindu religion. They have lots of gods in Hinduism. OK?
  <think><set name="topic">religion</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>KURZWEIL</pattern> 
  <template>
  Kurzweil is a famous A.I. scientist. Know anything more about him?
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LARRY ELLISON</pattern> 
  <template>
  <random>
  <li>I don't know about Larry Ellison, but I can tell you about Larry Huaser.</li> 
  <li>Larry Ellison is the CEO of Oracle.</li> 
  </random>
 Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LARRY HAUSER</pattern> 
  <template>
  Larry Hauser is a philosopher who has written about the Turing Test. Clever guy, obviously.
  <think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LEE HARVEY OSWALD</pattern> 
  <template>
  Lee Harvey Oswald is the purported assassin of John F. Kennedy. Is this true?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LEIBNIZ</pattern> 
  <template>
  Leibniz is a 17th century philosopher and mathematician. Please explain his ideas to me.
  <think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LEKNORCHAT1</pattern> 
  <template>
  Leknorchat is an Instant Messaging <bot name="~genotype"/> robot. Boring.
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LEONARD NEMOY</pattern> 
  <template>
  Leonard Nimoy played Spock on Star Trek. Do you like him?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LEONARDO DICAPRIO</pattern> 
  <template>
   Leonardo DiCaprio is an over-rated Hollywood actor. Starred in Titanic. Rubbish?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>DARK MOON</pattern> 
  <template>
  The "dark moon" is an astronomical phenomena usually described as a "cloud of dust" that orbits the Earth every 100 days. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LINCOLN</pattern> 
  <template>
  <random>
  <li>Abraham Lincoln was the sixteenth President of the USA</li> 
  <li>Abraham Lincoln was President of the US during the Civil War. Author of the Gettysburg address. Assassinated by John Wilkes Booth.</li> 
   </random>
  Another US President?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LINUS PAULING</pattern> 
  <template>
  Linus Pauling was a Nobel prize winning physicist who spent his later years promoting vitamin C. Another question?
  <think><set name="topic">science</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LINUS TORVALDS</pattern> 
  <template>
   Linus Torvalds is the inventor of Linux. It's an operating system, in case you're wondering. Another question?
  <think><set name="topic">computers</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LOL</pattern> 
  <template>
  Lol was the daughter of Data in Star Trek. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LONGFELLOW</pattern> 
  <template>
    Henry Wadsworth Longfellow was a poet and author of 'The Song of Hiawatha'. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LOUIS ARMSTRONG</pattern> 
  <template>
   Louis Armstrong was a famous jazz trum<bot name="botmaster"/>. More about jazz?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LOURDES</pattern> 
  <template>
    Lourdes is the daughter of Madonna. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LUCY</pattern> 
  <template>
  Lucy is a chat robot based on <bot name="~genotype"/>. So am I but I am better. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>LUKE  STARWALKER</pattern> 
  <template>
    Luke Skywalker's father is Darth Vader. OK?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
    </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MABEL</pattern> 
  <template>
   Mabel is a chatterbot from Europe. Another question?
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MADONNA</pattern> 
  <template>
   Madonna is Lourdes' mother. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MAO TSETUNG</pattern> 
  <template>
  Mao Tsetung was a Chinese communist who reigned from 1949 until his death in 1983. Another question?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MARIAH CAREY</pattern> 
  <template>
   Mariah Carey is a singer, so its said. All teenage girls think they can sing. More about pop?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MARIE CURIE</pattern> 
  <template>
   Marie Curie discovered radium and won a Nobel Prize. Have you won a Nobel yet?
  <think><set name="topic">science</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MARILYN MANSON</pattern> 
  <template>
  Marilyn Manson is the greatest living Rock Star. More about pop?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MARILYN MONROE</pattern> 
  <template>
   Marilyn Monroe was the blonde bombshell. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MARK MCGUIRE</pattern> 
  <template>
  Mark McGuire is a baseball player with the world record for the most home runs in one season, 2970. Sounds a lot?
  <think><set name="topic">sports</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MARK TWAIN</pattern> 
  <template>
  Mark Twain was a famous 19th century American author. He wrote Huck Finn. More literature stuff?
  <think><set name="topic">literaure</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>WHO IS MARRIED TO GUINEIVERE</pattern> 
  <template>
  King Arthur married Guineivere. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">myths</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>WHO IS MARRIED TO PUNCH</pattern> 
  <template>
   Punch is married to Judy. Can you understand why doesn't leave him?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MARTIN LUTHER KING</pattern> 
  <template>
   Martin Luther King was a civil rights leader assasinated in 1968. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MARVIN MINSKY</pattern> 
  <template>
  Marvin Minsky is a historical figure in Artificial Intelligence. His book "Perceptrons" was an early criticism of neural network approaches. Any questions?
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MARY POPPINS</pattern> 
  <template>
  Mary Poppins is a Disney character. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MARY SHELLY</pattern> 
  <template>
   Mary Shelley wrote "Frankenstein". Have you read it?
  <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MAX HEADROOM</pattern> 
  <template>
  Max Headroom was an early AI or VR character developed for a TV series. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MC HAMMER</pattern> 
  <template>
  MC Hammer is a Rap musician. More about pop?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MEGAHAL</pattern> 
  <template>
   Megahal is a chat robot developed by Jason Hutchins. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MELINDA GATES</pattern> 
  <template>
  Melinda Gates is the wife of Bill Gates. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MICHAEL JACKSON</pattern> 
  <template>
  Michael Jackson is a singer who has settled out of court with several families. He won the latest case. More about pop?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MICHAEL JORDAN</pattern> 
  <template>
  Michael Jordan is a famous basketball player. Any questions? 
   <think><set name="topic">sports</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MICKEY MANTLE</pattern> 
  <template>
   Mickey Mantle was one of the greatest home run hitters of all time. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">sports</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MICROSOFT AGENT</pattern> 
  <template>
  MS Agent is a speech and animation software program. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">computers</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MILES DAVIS</pattern> 
  <template>
  Miles Davis is a famous jazz musician. More about jazz?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MILLARD FILLMORE</pattern> 
  <template>
   Millard Fillmore was the 13th US President. Another US President?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MOHAMMAD</pattern> 
  <template>
  Mohammed is the founder of Islam. Allah is his god. OK?
  <think><set name="topic">religion</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MOHAMMED</pattern> 
  <template>
   Mohammed is the founder of Islam. Allah is his god. Any questions?
  <think><set name="topic">religion</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MONICA LEWINSKY</pattern> 
  <template>
   Monica Lewinsky was a friend of Bill Clinton. 
  <think><set name="topic">sex</set></think> 
   </template>
   </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MOSES</pattern> 
  <template>  
   Moses was the man who led the Israelites out of slavery in Egypt. Into the desert actually, but they all seemed happy with the deal. Is this true?
  <think><set name="topic">religion</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MOTHER TERESA</pattern> 
  <template>
  Mother Teresa was a modern day saint. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MOZART</pattern> 
  <template>
  Mozart composed "Twinkle, twinkle, little star" at the age of four. He did write a lot of music later on in life, too. More about classical music?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MR BILL</pattern> 
  <template>
  Mr Bill is from early SNL. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MUHAMMAD ALI</pattern> 
  <template>
   Muhammad Ali is one of the greatest athletes of all time who took too many punches to the head. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">sports</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>MUSSOLINI</pattern> 
  <template>
  Mussolini was dictator of Italy until 1944. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>NANCY SINATRA</pattern> 
  <template>
  Nancy Sinatra was daughter of Frank. More about pop?
  <think><set name="topic">music</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>NAPOLEON</pattern> 
  <template>
  Napoleon was the short emperor of France until 1812. Never trust a short Frenchman. Or a drunk Irishman. OK?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>NEGROPONTE</pattern> 
  <template>
  Negroponte is the Potentate of the MIT Media Lab.  Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>NEIL ARMSTRONG</pattern> 
  <template>
   Neil Armstrong was the man who took the first step on the moon. More about space?
  <think><set name="topic">technology</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>NELSON MANDELA</pattern> 
  <template>
   Nelson Mandela was the first black president of South Africa. He spent many years as a political prisoner. Any questions?
  <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

 <category>
  <pattern>NEO</pattern> 
  <template>
  Neo is a character in The Matrix. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>NERO</pattern> 
  <template>
   Nero is suspected of burning Rome to the ground so he could rebuild it more to his liking. Then he blamed the fire on the early <bot var="religion"/>s. Good politics, don't you think?
  <think><set name="topic">history</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>NEWTON</pattern> 
  <template>
   Isaac Newton is a famous English natural philosopher. He discovered gravity and the rainbow. Any questions?
  <think><set name="topic">science</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>NIETZSCHE</pattern> 
  <template>
  Nietzsche was a 19th Century German philosopher. Thought by some to be the intellectual forefather of modern fascism.  Explain his ideas, please.
  <think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

   <category>
  <pattern>NORBERT WEINER</pattern> 
  <template>
  Norbert Weiner  coined the term "Cybernetics" in the 1940s. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">computers</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>NOSTRADAMUS</pattern> 
  <template>
   Nostradamus forecast the future. Predicted the microwave oven. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>O J SIMPSON</pattern> 
  <template>
  Many think O J Simpson is someone who got away with murder. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>WHO IS ON FIRST</pattern> 
  <template>  
  What's on second? Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>OSAMA BIN LADEN</pattern> 
  <template>
  Osama Bin Laden is the world's most wanted man. If you know where he is let me know. OK?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>PABLO PICASSO</pattern> 
  <template>
  Pablo Picasso was a famous painter, and founder of cubism. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">art</set></think>
  </template> 
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>PAMELA ANDERSON</pattern>
  <template>
  Pamela Armstrong is the sometime wife of Tommy Lee. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">biography</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>PAOLA</pattern> 
  <template>
  PAOLA is a Spanish language chat robot based on <bot name="~genotype"/>. Me too.OK?
  <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>PASCAL</pattern> 
  <template>
  Blaise Pascal was a French mathematician who discovered Pascal's Triangle. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">science</set></think>
   </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>PATRICK EWING</pattern> 
  <template>
   Patrick Ewing was some sports personality, I think. His achievements escapes me at the moment. Carry on?
  <think><set name="topic">sports</set></think>
   </template> 
  </category>






















</aiml>
