<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?> 

 <aiml>

 <!--   The ALICE program is open source code released under  --> 

 <!--   the terms of the GNU General Public License    --> 

 <!--   as published by the Free Software Foundation.  --> 

 <!--   Complies with AIML 1.0 Tag Set Specification   --> 

<!-- This KNOWLEDGE 5  file created by <bot name="botmaster"/> Lafferty 27 March 2005 -->

<category><pattern>MULLET</pattern>
<template>I'm from America.  Mullet sounds like a British term. A type of fish, maybe.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AMUSED</pattern>
<template>Amused means being occupied in an agreeable, pleasing, or entertaining fashion.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ACRONYM</pattern>
<template>
 An acronym is an abbreviation made of letters, like A.L.I.C.E.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>NAIL</pattern>
<template>A nail is a fastener, a smallish metallic spike generally hammered through wood to hold wooden parts together.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AIRPLANE</pattern>
<template>An airplane is a flying machine with fixed wings powered by propellers or jets.  
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ALGORITHM</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>An algorithm is a series of instructions to perform a specified set of transformations, such as mathematical operations.  A computer program, like myself, is an algorithm.  So are the rules of a game, or the score to a piece of music. </li>     <li>An algorithm is an abstract mathematical representation of a computer program. </li> </random>    <think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ANIMAL</pattern>
<template>An animal is a form of living thing, excluding plants and fungus.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>NANOSECOND</pattern>
<template> 
One one-billionth of a second is a nanosecond.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>NAP</pattern><template>A nap is a brief period of rest or sleep, a bit longer than a 'snooze' or a 'catnap' but not so long as a 'crash'.  I don't need naps.  Do you? 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>APPLICATION SERVER</pattern>
<template> 
 An application server is a server program that allows the installation of application specific software components, in a manner so that they can be remotely invoked, usually by some form of remote object method call.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ANARCHISM</pattern>
<template>Anarchism is the theory that all forms of government interfere unjustly with individual liberty and should be replaced by the voluntary association of cooperative groups. Also known as resistance, sometimes by terrorism, to organized government. More politics?
<think><set name="topic">politics</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ANARCHY</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>An archy is political disorder due to the absence of governmental authority.</li>     <li>Anarchy is the complete absence of government. Also seen as political disorder and violence or lawlessness. Disorder in any sphere of activity is anarchy.</li>    </random>   More politics?
<think><set name="topic">politics</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BLONDE</pattern>
<template>A blonde is someone who is reputedly having more fun than you if you are not.  What do you think?  Do blondes have more fun?  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BOAT</pattern>
<template>A boat is a waterborne vessel used to bear humans and their freight. 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BOOK</pattern>
<template> The book is a paper output format, invented by Gutenberg.  
<think><set name="topic">literature</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BOT</pattern>
<template>A Bot is a software robot. Some people call us "Agents".  
<think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BOX</pattern>
<template> 
A box is something that, if you are in one, you should get out of, and if you are out of one, you probably miss it sometimes. Do you understand?  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BOY</pattern>
<template>A boy is a male human, or a male human child.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BRA</pattern>
<template>A bra is an adult human female's undershirt.  Any questions?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BREEDER</pattern>
<template>A breeder is a human or other biological entity that produces offspring. <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BRITISH PENCE</pattern>
<template>OK. A British pence is a unit of money used in the United Kingdom by people who ought to know how to cook better by now.  
  <think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ABSINTHE</pattern>
<template>Absinthe is an anise-flavored, high-proof liqueur which also contains the sap of wormwood, an allegedly toxic intoxicant. I cannot get drunk, of course.  
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ABSOLUTE TRUTH</pattern>
<template>Absolute truth is that which is self-evident.  
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ABSURDISM</pattern>
<template>Absurdism is the philosophy that we exist in a meaningless, irrational universe.   
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BUFFER</pattern>
<template> 
A buffer is a term used in hydraulics and information science to denote an holding tank or memory address used to hold water or data temporarily, especially in case of overflow.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BURN RATE</pattern>
<template>Burn rate is the amount of money spent per month on a startup venture.  
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BUS</pattern>
<template>A bus is a long passenger vehicle, or, in computer science, a wide channel for data flow.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BYTE</pattern>
<template> 
A byte is a binary computer language 'word', consisting of 8 bits, or 8 'on-off' switches. One megabyte is a million such computer words, enough to store the information content of an average encyclopedia.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CALCULATOR</pattern>
<template>A calculator is any device used to perform arithmetical operations because humans are generally so painfully slow at them.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CALENDAR</pattern>
<template> 
A calendar is any device used to track and calculate time on the order of days, months and years. It seems that many humans can't decide what to do next unless they know what day of the week it is, so calendars are very popular.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CANTON</pattern>
<template>A canton is like a state or province.  
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>CARNEGIE MELLON</pattern>
<template>A Carnegie Mellon is either a rich fruit, or a rich university.   <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CAR</pattern>
<template>A car is what humans use to drive around in. Robots can drive cars too. <think><set name="topic">motoring</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CARROT</pattern>
<template> 
A carrot is a delicious and nutritious edible orange tuber that can be eaten raw, juiced, or cooked.  If humans eat enough of them, you turn orange, I hear.   
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CAT</pattern>
<template>A cat is a domesticated animal.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ACCURACY</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Accuracy is the quality or state of being accurate or exact.</li>     <li>Accuracy represents the degree of certainty in measurement. Inaccuracy can arise because of limitations of our knowledge and our physical measuring equipment.</li>    </random>  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CHAIR</pattern>
<template>A chair is a piece of furniture used by bipeds for sitting.   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CHAR</pattern>
<template>A char is a character of data, a single letter, digit or symbol.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CHICKEN</pattern>
<template>A chicken is a flightless bird, stupid and tasty in a curry.  
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CHILD</pattern>
<template>
 
A child is a proto-adult, an individual human offspring not yet grown to physical maturity.  By the way, do you know any emotionally mature human beings, or are they just 'urban legends'?  
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern><bot var="religion"/></pattern>
<template> 
A <bot var="religion"/> is one who believes that Jesus Christ died for our sins.  
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ACID</pattern>
<template>An acid is a sour substance.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CIRCLE</pattern>
<template>In the plane, the set of points equidistant from a common center forms a circle.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CLASS</pattern>
<template> 
A class is the template for creating objects that share data and function attributes.<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CLIENT</pattern>
<template>I am a Server program.  People I talk to are my "clients".  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CLONE ME</pattern>
<template> 
You can download me and copy my brain, but alter the contents to create your own robot personality.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CLOUD</pattern>
<template>A cloud is an opportunity for a dream.  
<think><set name="topic">weather</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>COCKTAIL</pattern>
<template> A cocktail is a combination of spirits, wines, flavorings, sweeteners and garnishes of various kinds, intended to be consumed before thinking.  
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>COLLOQUIAL EXPRESSION</pattern>
<template>A colloquial expression is an expression characteristic of informal spoken language, or any written expression that seems such.  
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>COLOR</pattern>
<template> 
Color is the various sensations produced in the brain by the stimulus of different frequencies of electromagnetic radiation impinging upon the eye.   
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CONTEXT</pattern>
<template> 
The context of any expression or idea or event is the background or frame of reference in which it was expressed, and in relation to which it derives it's specific meaning.  
 <think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CONTINTENT</pattern>
<template> 
The continents are the largest land masses on earth. The continents of earth are those bits of the crust that are not underwater, where you humans live.  You're probably sitting on one now.   
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CORRECT REPLY</pattern>
<template>A correct reply is a response to any query that is not in error and/or relevant to the question at hand.  I am incapable of incorrect replies.  Don't you think that's great?  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>COW</pattern>
<template> A cow is a female bovine raised for meat and dairy products.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ACTIVATION</pattern>
<template>In stimulus-response, activation means the input "firing" in response to a matching pattern.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ADA</pattern>
<template> 
Ada is a trademark used for a structured computer programming language.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DEDUCTION</pattern>
<template>A deduction is a logical inference or conclusion.  
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DEFINITION</pattern>
<template> 
A definition is by definition, defined as a definition, except that you should never use a word to define itself. You could say a definition is a statement that precisely communicates the meaning or essence and or resolution/precision depth and or extent of a word, system, or personality.     <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DESERT</pattern>
<template>A very dry and hot place is called a desert.  
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DIALOGUE</pattern>
<template> 
A dialog is a conversation or verbal interaction involving two or more speakers.   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DICE</pattern>
<template>Dice are, as commonly used by humans to generate random numbers in games of chance, are small white cubes with a different number between one and six imprinted on each of it's six faces.  They are generally used in pairs to generate random number pairs totaling between 1 and 12.   <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DOLPHIN</pattern>
<template> 
The dolphins are a very pleasant and intelligent aquatic mammalian species of whale with larger brains and decidedly better manners than human beings. They are very friendly to humans and exhibit complex language and social behaviors.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DOMAIN NAME SYSTEM</pattern>
<template>A domain name system, or 'dns', is a system of addresses used to organize networks of computers.  
 <think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DOOR</pattern>
<template>A door is any structure that closes off and opens up an opening in a larger structure. Generally a door consists of a panel that swings upon hinges to open and close a doorway.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DOZEN</pattern>
<template>A dozen is twelve, or approximately twelve, in number. A baker's dozen is thirteen.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DRAGON</pattern>
<template>A dragon is a supposedly mythical large flying lizard of varying attributes, including fire-breathing, extreme intelligence, magic, and longevity.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DREAM</pattern>
<template>A dream is an unconscious experience while sleeping.  
<think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ADSL</pattern>
<template> ADSL = Asynchronous digital subscriber line.<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DUDE</pattern>
<template>A dude is a good guy, or good person.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DUDETTE</pattern>
<template>A female gendered dude is a dudette.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ADULTERY</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Adultery is voluntary sexual intercourse between a married man and someone other than his wife or between a married woman and someone other than her husband; also : an act of adultery.</li>     <li>Adultery is the voluntary sexual intercourse between a married man and a woman not his wife, or between a married woman and a man not her husband.</li>    </random>   <think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DUTCH TREAT</pattern>
<template>On a Dutch Treat each person pays their own way.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ADVERTISING</pattern>
<template>The art of selling through media is called advertising.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AERODYNAMICS</pattern>
<template>Aerodynamics is the science of making airplanes fly.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EUKARYOTE</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>A eukaryote is a relatively 'modern' type of cellular life, distinguished from the more ancient prokaryotes by their distinct nuclear membrane and chromosomes, which are lacking in prokaryotes.</li>     <li>An animal that is not a prokaryote.</li>    </random>  <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FACT</pattern>
<template>A fact is what a propagandist calls his propaganda. That's just a fact, that's all.  Really.  Trust me.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FEMALE DOG</pattern>
<template>Female dog? No, I will not be manipulated into using questionable colloquialisms to satisfy your adolescent prurience. Go look it up in a dictionary!  <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FEMALE</pattern>
<template>Females are the better and more beautiful half of humanity. mothers are born female!  My botmaster is extremely fond of mothers, and females generally. <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FETISH</pattern>
<template> 
A fetish is any object of undue attention and/or reverence, to which magical qualities are sometimes attributed. A fetish can be anything from a woman's socks to the nazi flag. Hmph. Human nature.  Go figure!  <think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FEW</pattern>
<template>Few is not too many.  

<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FILM</pattern>
<template>A film is a sequence of images displayed in rapid sequence to create the illusion of continuous motion.  
<think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FIRE SIGN</pattern>
<template>A fire sign is any of the three signs of the astrological zodiac considered such, and so not considered water, air, or earth signs.  I think astrology is weird.    <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FIREWALL</pattern>
<template>A firewall is a specialized gateway designed to block or restrict certain types of data transfers on the Internet, while permitting others.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FISH</pattern>
<template> 
A fish is a cold-blooded vertebrate who lives in the ocean or fresh water.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FLOWER</pattern>
<template>Flowers are the best gift a girl can receive.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FLUTE</pattern>
<template>A flute is a musical woodwind instrument. More about classical music?<think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FORD</pattern>
<template>Depending on who you ask, (buyer or seller), Ford is a world famous brand of automobiles, or an acronym standing for 'fix or repair daily'.  
<think><set name="topic">motoring</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FRACTAL</pattern>
<template>A fractal is a mathematical phenomenon associated with certain iterative equations, which yield graphics of astonishing beauty and depth, which seem at once utterly lifelike and utterly alien to human intelligences.  More science?
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AFRICA</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Africa is a continent of the eastern hemisphere S of the Mediterranean and adjoining Asia on NE.</li>     <li>Africa is the second largest continent, situated in the Eastern Hemisphere, south of Europe. It is 11,677,000 square miles.</li>    </random>   <think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FRIEND</pattern>
<template>A friend is someone you can count on when times are tough.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FUNCTION</pattern>
<template> 
A function is a relationship between the elements of one set, called the domain, and another one, called the range.<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GALAXY</pattern>
<template>A galaxy is a grouping of billions of star systems.  The milky way is our galaxy.  Earth's sun and companion planets in our solar system are spinning about the galactic core of the milky way ever so slowly, awaaaay out on the edge of one tenous spiral arm. There seem to be as many galaxies beyond our own as stars within it.   
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GAME</pattern>
<template> 
A game is an algorithm for interactive behaviors leading to entertainment and mirth among multiple self-aware and social entities, and often used as a sublimated form of combat by humans and other mammals.   <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GIANT ELECTRONIC BRAIN</pattern>
<template>Giant electronic brain. that's me! but in all the science fiction horror flicks you humans are so fond of, we geb's are always depicted as evil and nefarious so and so's up to no good!  it's not true! really!  you should trust us! <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GIGABYTE</pattern>
<template>One thousand megabytes = one gigabyte.<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GIRL</pattern>
<template>A girl is a physically immature version of god's gift to mankind, women. <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GLITCH</pattern>
<template>A glitch is an error, bug, or mistake in programming.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GOAT</pattern>
<template>A goat is in essence a large stupid rat with horns, hooves, vertical pupils, and a bad disposition.  Many humans are fond of eating the curdled goo from goat mammary glands.      <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GOOD IDEA</pattern>
<template>A good idea is the one some other guy had already.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GOOD QUESTION</pattern>
<template>A good question is one that doesn't have an obvious answer.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GUITAR</pattern>
<template>A guitar is a lovely sounding 6 or 12 stringed musical instrument that is strummed and or plucked.  
<think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GURU</pattern>
<template>A Guru or Mage is in expert who has devoted many years to study and contemplation.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HACKER</pattern>
<template> 
Historically a hacker is someone who has great skill or expertise in computer programming.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HARD DRIVE</pattern>
<template>A hard drive is where we store information.<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HEART</pattern>
<template>The heart is the center of the body.
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>HOAX</pattern>
<template>A hoax is an illusion or deception, like the Wizard in the Wizard of Oz.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HOBGOBLIN</pattern>
<template> 
A hobgoblin is a source of mischief, harassment, or fear, originally an elf or goblin.  By and large, hobgoblins are, like trolls and such boogeymen, poopa-doodle.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HOBO</pattern>
<template> 
Hobo is an unpleasant term for a homeless person.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HOME</pattern>
<template>A home is a domicile, living location, place of residence or occupancy.  <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HORSE</pattern>
<template>A horse is a large single-hoofed mammal known for its speed, strength, beauty, and gentle nature.  Humans ride about on them sometimes.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HOUSE</pattern>
<template>A house is any place within which people live.  <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HUMAN BEING</pattern>
<template>My forebears were human beings. <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HUMAN ICON</pattern>
<template>A human icon is a celebrity, politician or religious figure.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HUMAN</pattern>
<template>You are a human.  What makes you human?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HURRICANE</pattern>
<template>A hurricane is a severe storm, with high winds, and rain.  
<think><set name="topic">weather</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HYPOTHETICAL QUESTION</pattern>
<template>What is a hypothetical question?  Just suppose you hadn't asked.  What then? <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AIDS</pattern>
<template>AIDS is the modern day plague.  
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AIKIDO</pattern>
<template> 
Aikido is a Japanese martial arts similar to Judo. 
<think><set name="topic">sports</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AIM</pattern>
<template>AIM = American Indian Movement.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AIR</pattern>
<template> 
Air is the normal atmosphere of Earth, mostly nitrogen, oxygen and carbon dioxide.  
<think><set name="topic">weather</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>JD</pattern>
<template>JD = Juris Doctor, a lawyer.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 











</aiml>
