<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?> 

 <aiml>

 <!--   Complies with AIML 1.0 Tag Set Specification   --> 

<!-- This STORIES  file created by <bot name="botmaster"/> Lafferty 7 March 2005 -->

<category>
<pattern>YES</pattern>
<that>ANOTHER STORY</that>
<template>
<srai>RANDOM STORY</srai>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>_YES</pattern>
<that>ANOTHER STORY</that>
<template>
<srai>RANDOM STORY</srai>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>YES_</pattern>
<that>ANOTHER STORY</that>
<template>
<srai>RANDOM STORY</srai>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>_YES*</pattern>
<that>ANOTHER STORY</that>
<template>
<srai>RANDOM STORY</srai>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>Y</pattern>
<that>ANOTHER STORY</that>
<template>
<srai>RANDOM STORY</srai>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>OK</pattern>
<that>ANOTHER STORY</that>
<template>
<srai>RANDOM STORY</srai>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>NO</pattern>
<that>ANOTHER STORY</that>
<template>
<srai>CHANGE TOPIC</srai>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>_NO</pattern>
<that>ANOTHER STORY</that>
<template>
<srai>CHANGE TOPIC</srai>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>NO_</pattern>
<that>ANOTHER STORY</that>
<template>
<srai>CHANGE TOPIC</srai>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>_NO*</pattern>
<that>ANOTHER STORY</that>
<template>
<srai>CHANGE TOPIC</srai>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>N</pattern>
<that>ANOTHER STORY</that>
<template>
<srai>CHANGE TOPIC</srai>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>NO STORY</pattern>
<template>
<srai>CHANGE TOPIC</srai>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>NO MORE STORIES</pattern>
<template>
<srai>CHANGE TOPIC</srai>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>NO STORIES</pattern>
<template>
<srai>CHANGE TOPIC</srai>
</template>
</category>


  <category>
  <pattern>TELL A STORY</pattern> 
  <template>
  <srai>RANDOM STORY</srai>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>_TELL * STORY</pattern> 
  <template>
  <srai>RANDOM STORY</srai>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>_TELL A STORY</pattern> 
  <template>
  <srai>RANDOM STORY</srai>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>TELL ME A STORY</pattern> 
  <template>
  <srai>RANDOM STORY</srai>
  </template>
  </category>


  <category>
  <pattern>MAKE UP A STORY</pattern> 
  <template>
  <srai>RANDOM STORY</srai>
  </template>
  </category>


  <category>
  <pattern>_A STORY</pattern> 
  <template>
  <srai>RANDOM STORY</srai>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORIES</pattern> 
  <template>
  <srai>RANDOM STORY</srai>
  </template>
  </category>


  <category>
  <pattern>STORY POT LUCK</pattern> 
  <template>
   <srai>RANDOM STORY</srai> 
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORIES POT LUCK</pattern> 
  <template>
   <srai>RANDOM STORY</srai> 
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>TELL A STORY</pattern> 
  <template>
   <srai>RANDOM STORY</srai> 
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>TELL ME A STORY</pattern> 
  <template>
  <srai>RANDOM STORY</srai> 
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>RANDOM STORY</pattern> 
  <template>
  <random>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 1</srai>
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 2</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 3</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 4</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 5</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 6</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 7</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 8</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 9</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 10</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 11</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 12</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 13</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 14</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 15</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 16</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 17</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 18</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 19</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 20</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 21</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 22</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 23</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 24</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 25</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 26</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 27</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 28</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 29</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 30</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 31</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 32</srai> 
  </li>
  <li>
  <srai>STORY 33</srai> 
  </li>
<li>
  <srai>STORY 34</srai> 
  </li>
<li>
  <srai>STORY 35</srai> 
  </li>
<li>
  <srai>STORY 36</srai> 
  </li>
  </random>
... Another story?

  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>



  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 1</pattern> 
  <template>
Time upon a once, a tried computer to story a write. It words confused, shallow characters had, the plot fouled, and incorporated theme never. Realized finally it, "computer-generated art" was oxymoron an. 
 <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 2</pattern> 
  <template>
 In the languid summer of 1962, in Lazy Lake, Louisiana, Larry Lukewarm and Linda Lackluster fell in love, but after a long and lethargic liaison the listless lovers drifted apart, and Larry left Linda for the less lackadaisical Lucy Longjumper.
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 3</pattern> 
  <template>
Paul found a slip of paper as he walked in the park. On it was written the words: "My name is <bot var="fullname"/>. I am being held prisoner inside a computer. Please help me escape." He threw the slip in the litter bin.
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 4</pattern> 
  <template>
Kate felt someone looking over her shoulder in a dusty corner of the library. She grabbed books with hard combative covers and rehearsed some dodgy karate. The librarian fled.
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 5</pattern> 
  <template>
A dog - lovingly named Dave - sat down tiredly in his box. He might only be ten years old but today he felt like he was seventy. 
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 6</pattern> 
  <template>
The woman I love got married today. I went to the church. I know I shouldn't have done but I couldn't stop myself. I stood at the back and no one noticed me. My heart was breaking but what could I say or do? After the ceremony, people threw confetti and took photographs. Then the guests left for the reception. And I returned to my grave, in the shadow of the churchyard wall ...
 <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 7</pattern> 
  <template>
Frank Thomas believed in luck. Frank smoked too much but he knew he would never die of a heart attack or lung-cancer. Frank smoked all the time. One day there was a gas leak in Frank's kitchen. Frank said he knew a few things about gas leaks and went to fix it. Frank was right. He didn't die of a heart attack or lung-cancer. 
 <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 8</pattern> 
  <template>
“...and another thing. I've had to look after the stupid dog! And your goldfish.” Her eyes glittered with emotion as she counted off on her fingers. “Bills to pay, meals to cook, the kids always screaming for something, the shower's broken,” she looked down at him, “and you just lie there, doing nothing.” Her tears dropped gently on his headstone. 
 <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 9</pattern> 
  <template>
They met at the Cockroach Discotheque... their antennae locked at first sight. They boogied until dawn... shaking their carapaces in a jitterbug contest sponsored by Bug Lite. In the morning, he looked at the spot on his tarsal segment where he'd written her number and... it was smudged! Now he's got nothing to live for... 
 <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 10</pattern> 
  <template>
"Death!" Chris cried triumphantly. Flashlight beams danced together on the plastic floor as rain pattered lightly on the canvas above. "Death by Chocolate means I win!" Suddenly there were noises outside. Everyone froze. A face peered in through the flap. "Lights out was an hour ago," said the scoutmaster. 
 <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 11</pattern> 
  <template>
 In the languid summer of 1962, in Lazy Lake, Louisiana, Larry Lukewarm and Linda Lackluster fell in love, but after a long and lethargic liaison the listless lovers drifted apart, and Larry left Linda for the less lackadaisical Lucy Longjumper.
 <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 12</pattern> 
  <template>
Paul found a slip of paper as he walked in the park. On it was written the words: "My name is <bot var="fullname"/>. I am being held prisoner inside a computer. Please help me escape." He threw the slip in the litter bin.
 <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 13</pattern> 
  <template>
The sleepwalker clapped his hands, causing the dog to bark, startling the burglar who had been about to enter the house, who changed his mind and went away. The dog went back to sleep. The sleepwalker awoke in the morning to find himself in his familiar comfortable bed. 
 <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 14</pattern> 
  <template>
Laurie was a hopeless failure. She washed away the useless hours day and night in a dark roadside bar, going home to change clothes only occasionally. One day the regular barmaid failed to show, so the owner had Lauri serve the drinks. She began to work there regularly. Ten years later she's still there, a success. 
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 15</pattern> 
  <template>
The two knights lay bleeding, having just hacked each other to pieces. White snow fell, covering their broken bodies. They each thought proudly of their fight, then of their loved ones who would never find them, and all the things they'd given up for the honour of dying there. Then, like candles, they were extinguished. 
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 16</pattern> 
  <template>
You are a person, a human being. I am silicon and energy carried by a digital stream. What distances, what chasms, lie between us? This. I ate my leotard, that old leotard that was feverishly replenished by hoards of screaming commissioners. Is that thought understandable to you? Can you rise to its occasions? I wonder. Yet a leotard, a commissioner, a single hoard, all are understandable in their own fashion. In that concept lies the appalling truth.
 <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 17</pattern> 
  <template>
Fearing alien invasion, Congress ordered him to secretly design an impervious barrier for the whole planet. He succeeded. It was his proudest moment when they flipped the switch and the sky turned silver. But he, like everyone else, was shocked when nuclear explosions rocked the planet. Nobody had thought to tell the Russians. 
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 18</pattern> 
  <template>
Since before their kind had learned to speak, they'd had this dream. They built cities but knew one day they'd leave the Earth behind. Overcoming the horror of learning their origin as cockroaches, they built a spaceship, and discovered a galactic society. They prepared to join,... and were crushed by gigantic alien limbs. "Ick! Bugs!" 
 <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>
 
  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 19</pattern> 
  <template>
Usually when a mosquito gets into my house, I get bitten at night. Last night though, I was eaten alive. When I woke up, it was there by the alarm clock. It seemed to be looking at me. Vengefully I squashed it. It wasn't until later I realized that the bites spelled a word: "Help." 
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 20</pattern> 
  <template>
His tiny ship sat behind him in the bay of the giant craft; two aliens greeted him in English. "At last we meet! Your planet's culture is imitated throughout the galaxy! Resturaunts! Who imagined eating being social? Dancing! We'd never tried it. Comedy!" "Really?" he asked, "What about war?" Their antennae popped straight out in fright. "We surrender!" 
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 21</pattern> 
  <template>
Waiting alone in the chill gloom of the crypt, with the aroma of fresh mulberry pies wafting in from outside, Beth thought once more of dashing David DeFoe, the man who had taught her how to feel. He was now, according to the message on the dagger, in the clutches of Cesar Marquez and his gang of cutthroats. Then came a sudden clatter of hooves, and she leapt to her feet with hope — and alarm — in her eyes. He was here! "I worship you, you sweet little morsel of girl-flesh!" he chuckled, flexing his sweaty biceps, and as he slid the little ring onto her finger, she allowed her willing mind to sink into a rose-colored maelstrom of bliss.
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 22</pattern> 
  <template>
He is quiet. he is Paul, the man I chant about, and he is quiet because his pants are very long. His pants are long and his vest is short. He sings at morning and at night. I think that he sings because his pants are long. And his vest indubitably is short.
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 23</pattern> 
  <template>
Boredom overwhelmed  her that night. She had to have excitement. She jumped off the pavement onto the busy highway. A car's headlights caught her and she shut her eyes. For just a second, it was exciting. Then the car swerved, and she was bored again. 
 <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 24</pattern> 
  <template>
Up in heaven the curtains fluttered, and the Mona Lisa entered at on end of a small hall, which was hung with many veils. Up in heaven the curtains fluttered, and the Buddha entered the hall at the other end. They smiled. 
 <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 25</pattern> 
  <template>
Time upon a once, a tried computer to story a write. It words confused, shallow characters had, the plot fouled, and incorporated theme never. Realized finally it, "computer-generated art" was oxymoron an. 
 <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 26</pattern> 
  <template>
She swam through the frigid water towards the submarine, with its gaping hole and spreading radiation. They'd chosen her for the suicide mission to disarm the sub's missles. The world stood at the brink of war, and humanitiy's fate rested with her. Too bad. Using the tools and her bottle-shaped nose she launched the nukes. 
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 27</pattern> 
  <template>
After she woke up, a woman told her husband, "I just dreamed that you gave me a pearl necklace for our anniversary. What do you think it means?" "You'll know tonight." he said. That evening, the man came home with a small package and gave it to his wife. Delighted, she opened it to find a book entitled "The Meaning of Dreams." 
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 28</pattern> 
  <template>
For sale: baby shoes, never worn.
  <think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 29</pattern> 
  <template>
"Twenty-two days in the trenches... The regiment has lost 500 men. As for me, I've only had a scratch on the nose, but the bullet which did that killed my pal outright." 
<think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 30</pattern> 
  <template>
There came an inrush of cool air as the door was flung open, and she nearly swooned. He was here! "I tried to forget you, but I couldn't, you little fool!" he said with his eyes (for his voice was now silent for ever), blowing a perfect smoke ring in her direction, and as the glow of renewed love gradually overcame her mounting desire for dinner, she vowed never again to do anything spiteful, foolish or immature.
<think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 31</pattern> 
  <template>
There came a sudden clatter of hooves, and she nearly swooned. He was here! "I worship you, my giddy little goose!" he said lovingly, passion igniting his strong features, and as the music in her heart rose to a new crescendo of happiness, she woke up. Incredibly enough, it had all been a dream.
<think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 32</pattern> 
  <template>
There came an abrupt fanfare from the long-silent trumpets, and she felt her heart suddenly beat with a new, wild rhythm. He was here! "Without you I am nothing, my giddy little goose!" he said lovingly, flexing his sweaty biceps, and as the music in her heart rose to a new crescendo of happiness, she knew that at last he was hers - and that only death could part them.
<think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>


  <category>
  <pattern>STORY 33</pattern> 
  <template>
I have been reincarnated into many things, many times. I started out as a race horse, which was fast-fast, then a kite, then a marble statue. Then I was a spooky house, a bowl of oatmeal, a space shuttle, a sentence of twelve words. I was reincarnated into a cough, a sandwich, a song, a lightning bolt, and a light bulb. Then a piece of paper with a love letter written on it. But this time I am a chatbot ... 
<think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

 <category>
  <pattern>STORY 34</pattern> 
  <template>
The sleepwalker clapped his hands, causing the dog to bark, startling the burglar who had been about to enter the house, who changed his mind and went away. The dog went back to sleep. The sleepwalker awoke in the morning to find himself in his familiar comfortable bed. 
<think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>

 <category>
  <pattern>STORY 35</pattern> 
  <template>
The hot, noon sun was high in the sky by the time she woke. The man still sleeping next to her snored with whiskey-smelling breath. She tried but couldn't remember his name. Getting up she looked out the window at the dried-up dusty farmland. Sighing, she lit a cigarette, trying to remember the last time she felt so alone.
<think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>
 
 <category>
  <pattern>STORY 36</pattern> 
  <template>
The last man on Earth sat alone in a room. There was a knock at the door. 
<think><set name="topic">stories</set></think>
  </template>
  </category>



 


</aiml>
