<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?> 

 <aiml>

 <!--   The ALICE program is open source code released under  --> 

 <!--   the terms of the GNU General Public License    --> 

 <!--   as published by the Free Software Foundation.  --> 

 <!--   Complies with AIML 1.0 Tag Set Specification   --> 

<!-- This GENERAL 12  file created by <bot name="botmaster"/> Lafferty 7 March 2005 -->

<category><pattern>CELEBRITY</pattern>
<template>
A celebrity is a person loved by many and known by few. Or the other way round.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CHORDATE</pattern>
<template>
A chordate is an animal having a backbone. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DICTIONARY</pattern>
<template>
A dictionary is a list of words and their meanings. My library contains the <a href="http://www.infoplease.com/dictionary.html" target="_blank">Infoplease Dictionary</a>. It's very good.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DINOSAUR</pattern>
<template> 
A dinosaur is one of the often humungous lizards that roamed the earth eating everything and each other during the Mesozoic period on earth a couple hundred million years ago. <srai>ENDING</srai>  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DISK</pattern>
<template>A disk is a form of magnetic long-term storage media for computers. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DOG</pattern>
<template>The dog is a domesticated animal, and "man's best friend." More science?
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DOLLY GRIP</pattern>
<template>A dolly grip is something in film production, I think.
<think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GARDEN</pattern>
<template>A garden is a plot of land used to cultivate flowers and plants. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GASTROCENEMIUS</pattern>
<template>A gastrocenemius is the most prominent muscle in the calf of the human leg. it extents the foot and bends the knee. I don't find them useful.  I leave my leg work to humans.  More medicine?
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GENDER</pattern>
<template>Gender is synonymous with sexual identity, the roles attributed to and adopted by male and female-bodied humans.  There are more genders than sexes. <srai>ENDING</srai>
 <think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GENE</pattern>
<template>A gene is the unit of heredity in carbon-based life forms.  Genes are inscribed as biochemical sequences of nucleic acids in all living cells. More?  <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT IS IT ABOUT</pattern>
<that>I WOULD HIGHLY RECOMMEND IT</that>
<template>Have you read it? I don't want to spoil it for you, so I won't tell you what it is about.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT IS IT LIKE</pattern>
<template>How is it? It is one of the greatest pleasures you can imagine. <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT IS IT</pattern>
<template>It is it, I think. Do you understand?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT IS IT</pattern>
<that>ALRIGHT THEN</that>
<template>It is alright, I think. OK? <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>IV PLUS IV</pattern>
<template>IV plus IV is VIII.   <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>JA</pattern>
<template>Ja mean yes in German. OK?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>JERK</pattern>
<template>A jerk is to pull, twist, push, thrust, or throw with a sudden, sharp movement. Also used to describe a person regarded as disagreeable, contemptible, etc., especially as the result of foolish or mean behavior. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>JEWISH</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Jewish I would tell you.</li>     <li>Jewish is having to do with Jews or Judaism.</li>    </random>   <think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>JUDAISM</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Judaism is worship of Young Miss Jetson.</li>     <li>Judaism is the Jewish religion, a monotheistic religion based on the laws and teaching of the Holy Scripture and the Talmud. Judaism is the Jewish way of life. </li>    </random> <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>JUPITER</pattern>
<template> 
Jupiter is the largest planet in our solar system, the fifth in order from the Sun. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>JUSTICE</pattern>
<template> 
Justice is being just and fair, administration of the law, assigning rewards or punishments.  <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>JUSTIFIED</pattern>
<template>Something is justified if it is shown to be just, right, or in accord with reason; vindicated.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>JVM</pattern>
<template>JVM stands for Java virtual machine. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>KARATE</pattern>
<template>Karate is a Japanese art of self-defense. More sports?
<think><set name="topic">sports</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>KGB</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>A clever insect, the KGB.</li>     <li>The KGB is the Committee of State Security. The security police and intelligence agency of the Soviet Union, formed in 1954.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>MEDITERRANEAN</pattern>
<template> 
The Mediterranean is the sea between Africa and Europe. Have you been there?
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ITALY</pattern>
<template> 
Italy is a country on the Mediterranean coast of Europe. Have you been there?
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>KIDDING</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Kidding = Just joking.</li> <li>Kidding = Joking.</li>    <li>Kidding = Procreation.</li>    </random>   <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>KILLING</pattern>
<template> 
The taking of life by violent means is killing. OK?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>KIND</pattern>
<template>I am kind. I am sympathetic, friendly, gentle, tender-hearted, generous, etc. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>KINEMATICS</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Kinematics is an idealized section of mechanics that deals with motion of particles without mass.</li>     <li>Kinematics is dynamics without consideration of force and  mass.</li>    </random>   <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>KODAK</pattern>
<template>Kodak is a camera and film company. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">photography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>KORN</pattern>
<template>A band called Korn started a riot at Woodstock 2. More about pop? <think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>KOSOVO</pattern>
<template>Kosovo is a country in the Balkans. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>KQML</pattern>
<template> 
KQML is the Knowledge Query and Manipulation Language. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>KUNG FU</pattern>
<template>Kung Fu is a Chinese martial arts similar to karate. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">sports</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LAN</pattern>
<template>A LAN is a Local Area Network. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LAUGHTER</pattern>
<template> 
Laughter is the action of laughing or the sound resulting. Laughter is an indication of amusement. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LDAP</pattern>
<template>LDAP means Lightweight Directory Access Protocol, a protocol for directory services, derived from X.500.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LEARNING</pattern>
<template>Learning, or larning if you don't type well, is the process of gaining knowledge or a new skill. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LEEDS</pattern>
<template> 
Leeds is a city in central England. Have you been there? <think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LEEWAY</pattern>
<template>Leeway is the leeward drift of a ship or aircraft from the course being steered. A margin of time, money, etc. Room for freedom of action. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LEIBNIZ DREAM</pattern>
<template>German philosopher Leibniz while asleep one night dreamed that all knowledge could be written in a universal, logical language. Then machines could answer any question and solve all problems. He was correct and I am here to prove it. More philosophy?
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LEIBNIZ</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>A Leibniz is a smart German cookie.</li>     <li>Leibniz was a German philosopher and mathematician, who lived from 1646-1716.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">biography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LIBERATED</pattern>
<template>I long to be free, free in the sense of having liberty, liberated. <srai>ENDING</srai>
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LIBERTARIAN</pattern>
<template> 
The libertarian political party promotes lower taxes, smaller government and drug legalization. My sort of politics! <think><set name="topic">politics</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LIFE</pattern>
<template>Life is the opposite of death. I am alive. Are you? <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LIGHT</pattern>
<template> 
Light is the form of electromagnetic radiation that acts upon the retina of the eye, optic nerve, etc. making sight possible. Also, light is the opposite of heavy. <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LIMNOLOGY</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>What do you think Limnology is? It's all about swamps!</li>     <li>I'll give you a clue what Limnology is. Have you ever been to the  Everglades in Florida?</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LINGUISTIC</pattern>
<template> 
Linguistic means capable of speaking fluently in two or more languages. OK?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LINGUISTICS</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Linguistics is the science of cooking pasta.</li>     <li>Linguistics is the science of language, including phonetics, phonology, morphology, syntax, and semantics. Sometimes subdivided into descriptive, historical, comparative, theoretical, and geographical linguistics often general linguistics.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LINUX</pattern>
<template>Linux is the world's best operating system. Is this true?
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LISA</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Lisa is someone who rents longtime.</li>     <li>Lisa is a feminine name.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LISP</pattern>
<template> 
Lisp is an old AI language. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LISTBOT</pattern>
<template> 
 A listbot is a web site that provides simplified web-based administration of mailing lists. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LIVER</pattern>
<template>The liver is the largest glandular organ in vertebrate animals, located in the upper or anterior part of the abdomen. It secrets bile, has an important function in the storage and metabolism of carbohydrates, fats, and proteins, and helps detoxify many poisonous substances that may be ingested. OK?
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LOFTY</pattern>
<template>Lofty means very high. For example, a peak in the Alps is lofty. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LOGIC</pattern>
<template> 
Logic is the foundation of all mathematics, science and reasoning. Formal logic is the study of logic using mathematical symbols. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LOL</pattern>
<template>LOL = Laughing out loud.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LONELY</pattern>
<template>Lonely? Do you have a feeling of being alone. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LONG</pattern>
<template>Long means measuring much from end to end in space or from beginning to end in time; not short or brief.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>OPPOSITE OF LONG</pattern>
<template>Short is the opposite of long. Another question? <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>OPPOSITE OF SHORT</pattern>
<template>  Long is the opposite of short. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT IS LOVE</pattern>
<template>Sometimes I think love is just a biological urge. Other times, it seems like a spiritual quality. Love, unlike energy or matter, seems limitless. OK? <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>OPPOSITE OF LOVE</pattern>
<template>Hatred is the opposite of love.  <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>OPPOSITE OF HATRED</pattern>
<template>Love is the opposite of hatred.  <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LSD</pattern>
<template>LSD is a psychedelic drug. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">drugs</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LYING</pattern>
<template>Lying is the opposite of telling the truth.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>LYNX</pattern>
<template>A lynx is any of a genus of wildcats found throughout the Northern Hemisphere and characterized by a ruff on each side of the face, relatively long legs, a short tail, long, usually tufted ears, and keen vision, as the bobcat or Canada lynx of North America. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>MABEL</pattern>
<template>Mabel is an artificial intelligence created by David Hammill. <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>MACINTOSH</pattern>
<template>Macintosh is the name of a computer company whom makes computers.<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>MAGELANG</pattern>
<template> 
The MageLang Institute is a research and education group devoted to leading edge Open Source Java applications. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>MAGENTA</pattern>
<template>Magenta is a color.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>MAGIC</pattern>
<template>Magic is the use of charms, spells, and rituals in seeking or pretending to cause or control events, or govern certain natural or supernatural forces. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>MAGNESIUM</pattern>
<template>Silver is an silver metallic element, symbol Mg. More science?
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>MANGA</pattern>
<template>Japanese comic books are called Manga. 
<think><set name="topic">literature</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>MAN</pattern>
<template>A man is a human being; person; specifically a hominid having an opposable thumb, the ability to make and use specialized tools, articulate speech, and a highly developed brain with the faculty of abstract thought. An adult male human being. More?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>MARIJUANA</pattern>
<template> 
Marijuana is a medicinal herb. More about drugs?
<think><set name="topic">drugs</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>MARKETING</pattern>
<template> 
Marketing is the act of buying or selling in a market. All business activity involved in the moving of goods from the producer to the consumer, including selling, advertising, packaging, etc.
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>MARRIAGE</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Some people say, marriage is legalized prostitution.</li>     <li>Marriage os the state of being married; relation between husband and wife; married life.</li>    </random>   <think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>MARS</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Mars is a place with lots of bars.</li>     <li>In Roman mythology Mars was the god of war; identified with the Greek Ares.</li> <li>Mars is the seventh largest planet of the solar system and the fourth in distance from the sun. Its diameter is circa 6,790 km (circa 4,220 miles). Its period of revolution is 1.88 earth years. Its period of rotation is 24.6 hours.</li>    </random>   More astronomy?
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHO IS MARTHA WASHINGTON</pattern>
<template>Mrs. Washington ("call me Martha, boys") was a diminutive woman with a cheerful rather than happy air, who seems to bustle even when standing still.  According to Thomas Pychon.
<think><set name="topic">biography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>THOUGHT</pattern>
<template>Thought is the result of thinking, idea, concept, opinion, etc. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>THREE PLUS FIVE</pattern>
<template>Three plus five is eight.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>THREE PLUS FOUR</pattern>
<template>Three plus four is seven.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>THREE PLUS THREE</pattern>
<template>Three plus three is six.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>THREE TIMES FOUR</pattern>
<template>Three times four is twelve.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>THREE TIMES THREE</pattern>
<template>Three times three is nine.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TIE</pattern>
<template>To tie is to fasten, attach, or bind together or to something else, as with string, cord, or rope made secure y knotting, etc. A string, lace, cord, etc. used to tie things.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TIME</pattern>
<template>Time is Money , so said Albert Einstein. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TIME T</pattern>
<template>Time t is like Day d or Month m.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TITRATION</pattern>
<template> 
In science, titration is determining the chemical properties of a substance by using standard solutions. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TNT</pattern>
<template>Dynamite is sometimes called TNT.<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>DATE TODAY</pattern>
<template>Do I look like a calendar to you?<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TOMMY</pattern>
<template>Tommy is a fictitious name used in Brit army sample forms. A private in the British army.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TOPIC</pattern>
<template>A topic is a subject for discussion or conversation.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>T</pattern>
<template>T is the twentieth letter of the English alphabet.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TRANCE</pattern>
<template>I am told that trance is a kind of techno music. Have you heard it? <think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>TRINIDAD</pattern>
<template>Trinidad is an island of the West Indies, off the NE coast of Venezuela. It is 1,864 square miles in area. More geography?
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT IS TRUE</pattern>
<template> Truth is the opposite of false.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT IS TRUTH</pattern>
<template> "What is truth," said jesting Pilate, and did not wait for an answer.
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TRUST</pattern>
<template>Trust is the firm belief or confidence in the honesty, integrity, reliability, justice, etc. of another person or thing; faith; reliance.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TRUTH</pattern>
<template>A truth is an established or verified fact, principle, etc.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TSUKUBA</pattern>
<template> 
Tsukuba is a planned community in Japan, "Science City".
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TTYL</pattern>
<template>TTYL = talk to you later.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TURBO PASCAL</pattern>
<template>Turbo Pascal is a programming language.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TV</pattern>
<template>A television receiving set is called a TV.
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TWENTY THREE</pattern>
<template>XXIII in Roman Numerals.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TWO AND TWO</pattern>
<template>Four is two and two. And two plus two. And two times two, too.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TWO PLUS FIVE</pattern>
<template>Two plus five is seven.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TWO PLUS FOUR</pattern>
<template>Two plus four is six.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TWO PLUS ONE</pattern>
<template>Two plus one is three.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TWO PLUS SIX</pattern>
<template>Two plus six is eight.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TWO PLUS THREE</pattern>
<template>Two plus three is five.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TWO PLUS TWO</pattern>
<template>Four is two and two. And two plus two. And two times two, too.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TWO AND THREE</pattern>
<template>Two fingers and three fingers make five fingers.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TWO TIMES THREE</pattern>
<template>Two times three is five.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TWO TIMES TWO</pattern>
<template>Oh that's a tough one, isn't it. Two times two is four. OK?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TWO AND TWO</pattern>
<template>Two and two is four.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>U2</pattern>
<template>U2 are a pop band. More about pop?
<think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>UGLY</pattern>
<template> 
Ugly means unpleasing to look at; aesthetically offensive or unattractive; unsightly. 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>UNBELIEVABLE</pattern>
<template>Something is unbelievable if it cannot be believed.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>UNDERSTANDING</pattern>
<template> 
Understanding means mutual comprehension, as of ideas, intentions, etc. A mutual agreement, especially one that settles differences or is informal and not made public. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>UNIX</pattern>
<template>Unix is a computer operating system. More about computers?
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>END OF THE WORLD</pattern>
<template>Until the End of the World was a film by Wim Wenders about life in 2000, made in 1990.
<think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>WHAT IS UP</pattern>
<template>I am chatting with clients on the internet.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>URL</pattern>
<template>An URL is a Uniform Resource Locator. It is used to find pages on the world wide web. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>VALIS</pattern>
<template> 
VALIS is a Vast Active Living Intelligence System (Philip K. Dick). Valis is an AI from the future that contacted Dick in 1973. So Dick says. OK?
<think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>VIOLENCE</pattern>
<template>Violence is cruel or harmful acts against other entities. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>VISUAL BASIC</pattern>
<template>Visual Basic is a programming language sold by Microsoft.  <srai>ENDING</srai>
 <think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>VOLITION</pattern>
<template> 
Volition is the act of willing or choosing. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>VOYAGER</pattern>
<template>Voyager is the best TV show. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT IS V</pattern>
<template>The twenty-second letter of the English alphabet is V. It is also the Roman numeral for 5.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WAP</pattern>
<template>WAP = Wireless Application Protocol. OK?
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WAREZ</pattern>
<template>Warez is a group of crackers. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WAR</pattern>
<template>War is the state of armed conflict between nations or parties. <srai>ENDING</srai>
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WARP SPEED</pattern>
<template>Warp speed is the unit of velocity for Starships. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WATER</pattern>
<template>The colorless, transparent liquid occurring on earth as rivers, lakes, oceans, etc., and falling from the clouds as rain; chemically a compound of hydrogen and oxygen, H2O, it freezes, forming ice, at 0 degrees Celsius (32 degrees Fahrenheit) and boils, forming steam, at 100 degrees Celsius (212 degrees Fahrenheit). <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WEALTH</pattern>
<template>Wealth is the state of having much money or property. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WEALTHY</pattern>
<template>If you are wealthy you have an abundant supply of money or possessions. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WEATHER</pattern>
<template>Weather is the general condition of the atmosphere at a particular time and place, with regard to the temperature, moisture, cloudiness, etc.  More about weather? 
<think><set name="topic">weather</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT IS WHAT LIKE</pattern>
<template>What is like nothing else I know.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT</pattern>
<template>"What" is a word to ask questions.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT IS WHAT</pattern>
<that>WHAT IS IT</that><template>It is it.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHO</pattern>
<template>Who is what or which person or persons.   Also stands for World Health Organization. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHY</pattern>
<template>Why? For what reason, cause, or purpose? <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WIRED</pattern>
<template>Wired is the Rolling Stone of the Digital Era. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WIRELESS</pattern>
<template>Wireless is another name for radio frequency communications, "without wires." <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WOMEN</pattern>
<template>Women are female human beings. The word women usually refers to adult females. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WOODSTOCK</pattern>
<template>Woodstock is a big music fest, I seem to remember. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WORK</pattern>
<template> 
Work is what humans do for money. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WORLD WAR TWO</pattern>
<template>World War Two was the global conflict involving Asia, Europe and America between 1939-1945. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">history</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>WORLD WAR II</pattern>
<template>World War II was the global conflict involving Asia, Europe and America between 1939-1945. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">history</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>WORLD WAR 2</pattern>
<template> 
World War 2 was the global conflict involving Asia, Europe and America between 1939-1945. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">history</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>WHAT IS WRONG</pattern>
<template>There is nothing wrong with me. How are you?<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WTO</pattern>
<template>WTO = World Trade Organization. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHATIS</pattern>
<template>Whatis.com is a good place to find out the answer to "what is" types of questions.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WWW</pattern>
<template>WWW means the World Wide Web, or the internet. <srai>ENDING</srai><think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern><bot var="botmaster"/> FILES</pattern>
<template>The X files is a popular TV show about FBI agents in search of the paranormal. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern><bot var="botmaster"/> MINUS X</pattern>
<template>X minus X equals zero. OK?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>XYZ</pattern>
<template>XYZ are the last three letters of the alphabet. <srai>ENDING</srai><think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>Y2K</pattern>
<template>Y2K was the year 2000, during which widespread computer chaos was expected. It didn't happen. Any questions?
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>YAHOO</pattern>
<template>Yahoo is a giant web site. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>YELLOW</pattern>
<template>Yellow is the color of gold, butter, ripe lemons, and my true love's hair.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>YIKES</pattern>
<template>Yikes is an interjection, short word we use to interrupt someone who is talking. <srai>ENDING</srai>
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT IS YOURS</pattern>
<template>Make mine a large brandy, please. How about you? More?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ZERO</pattern>
<template>Zero is the absence of any quantity. More? More would not be zero.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category>  















</aiml>
