<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>  

<aiml>   

<!--  The ALICE program is open source code released under -->   

<!--  the terms of the GNU General Public License     -->  

<!--  as published by the Free Software Foundation.   -->   

<!--  Complies with AIML 1.0 Tag Set Specification -->   

<!--  ALICE Annotated Version updated Tue Jul  1 19:42:35 EDT 2003   --> 

<!--  This QUOTES 1 (quotes on specific subjects) file  updated by <bot name="botmaster"/> Lafferty 7 March 2005  --> 

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE WOODY ALLEN</pattern>
<template> 
Don't knock masturbation. It is sex with someone you love. (Woody Allen) OK?
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE THOMAS APPLETON</pattern>
<template>
A Boston man is the east wind made flesh, according to Thomas Appleton.
<think><set name="topic">words</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE FRANCIS BACON</pattern>
<template>
The job of the artist is always to deepen the mystery, according to Francis Bacon. 
<think><set name="topic">art</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE GEORGE BORROW</pattern>
<template>
Translation is at best an echo, according to George Borrow.
<think><set name="topic">words</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE CHESTERTON</pattern>
<template>
The artistic temperament is a disease that afflicts amateurs, according to G.K. Chesterton.
<think><set name="topic">art</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE CYRIL CONNOLLY</pattern>
<template>
Sculpture is mudpies which endure, according to Cyril Connolly.
<think><set name="topic">words</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE DEBUSSY</pattern>
<template>
Claude Debussy said, Art is the most beautiful of all lies.
<think><set name="topic">art</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE DEMI MOORE</pattern>
<template>
It's about time that people forget that image of strip clubs as seedy places - today's strip clubs are 'capital-intensive female employment zone,'  according to Demi Moore.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE DIETRICH</pattern>
<template>
Malene Dietrich once said: If there is a supreme being, he's crazy.  
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE ALBERT EINSTEIN</pattern>
<template>
Things should be as simple as possible, but not simpler, said Albert Einstein. 
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE W C FIELDS</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Beauty is the power by which a woman charms a lover and terrifies a husband.</li>
<li>Beauty is in the eye of the beerholder, according to W C Fields.</li>
<li>Beauty is what a woman has when she looks the same after washing her face.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE FLAUBERT</pattern>
<template>
Writing history, Gustave Flaubert once said, is like drinkg an ocean and pissing a cupful. OK?
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE FRANKLIN</pattern>
<template>
Wise men don't need advice; fools don't take it, according to Benjamin Franklin.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE FREUD</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Anatomy is destiny, according to Sigmund Freud.</li>
<li>Religion is an illusion and it derives its strength from the fact that it falls in with our instinctual desires, said Sigmund Freud.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE ROBERT FROST</pattern>
<template>
I had a lover's quarrel with the world, said Robert Frost.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE HERACLITUS</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>You cannot step twice into the same river, according to Heraclitus.</li>
<li>A man's character is his fate.       (Heraclitus)</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE HERBERT</pattern>
<template>
A highbrow is the kind of person who looks at a sausage and thinks of Picasso. (A.P. Herbert)
<think><set name="topic">art</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE HITCHCOCK</pattern>
<template>
Conversation is the enemy of good wine and food, according to Alfred Hitchcock.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE ABBIE HOFFMAN</pattern>
<template>
Work is the only really dirty four-letter word in the English language, according to Abbie Hoffman.  
<think><set name="topic">words</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE ELBERT HUBBARD</pattern>
<template>
Men are not punished for their sins, but by them, according to Elbert Hubbard.
<think><set name="topic">words</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE ELIZABETH HURLEY</pattern>
<template>
Being English, I always laugh at anything to do with the lavatory or bottoms, said Elizabeth Hurley.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE MICK JAGGER</pattern>
<template>
All I ever wanted to do was sin and make a lot of money, said Mick Jagger.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE SAMUEL JOHNSON</pattern>
<template>
When a man is tired of London, he is tired of life; for there is in London all that life can afford, according to Samuel Johnson.
<think><set name="topic">words</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE KLEE</pattern>
<template>
Art does not reproduce what is visible; it makes things visible, according to Paul Klee.
<think><set name="topic">art</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE MARILYN MANSON</pattern>
<template>
I say no to drugs, but they don't listen, revealed Marilyn Manson.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE MENCKEN</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Adultery is the application of democracy to love, according to H. L. Mencken.</li>
<li>Puritanism is the haunting fear that someone, somewhere, may be happy, according to H L Mencken.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">knowledge</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE J P MORGAN</pattern>
<template>
Riches are the reward of toil and virtue. (J. P.  Morgan) 
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE MITCH MURRAY</pattern>
<template>
Never do anything in bed that you can't pronounce, according to Mitch Murray.
<think><set name="topic">words</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE MORRISON</pattern>
<template>
Drugs are bet with the mind, according to Jim Morrison.
<think><set name="topic">drugs</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE NAPOLEON</pattern>
<template>
An army marches on its stomach, according to Napoleon.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE ORWELL</pattern>
<template>
Doublethink is the power of holding two contradictory beliefs in one's mind simultaneously, and accepting both of them, according to George Orwell.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE JAMES OTIS</pattern>
<template>
According to James Otis, taxation without representation is tyranny.
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE PLATH</pattern>
<template>
Even amidst the fierce flames the golden lotus can be planted, observed Sylvia Plath.
<think><set name="topic">literature</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
  <pattern>RABELAIS</pattern>
 <template>
Science without conscience is the ruin of the soul, according to Rabelais.
 <think><set name="topic">science</set></think>
 </template>
  </category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE FREDERIC RAPHAEL</pattern>
<template>
Cambridge is the city of perspiring dreams, according to Frederic Raphael.
<think><set name="topic">words</set></think>
</template>
</category>


<category>
<pattern>QUOTE RONALD REAGAN</pattern>
<template>
You can tell a lot about a fellow's character by the way he eats jelly beans, according to Ronald Reagan.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE ROCKEFELLOW</pattern>
<template>
Riches are a gift from Heaven signifying, "This is my beloved son, in whom I am well pleased. " (John D.  Rockefeller)
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE RUSSELL</pattern>
<template>
No one gossips about other people's secret virtues. (Bertrand Russell)
<think><set name="topic">gossip</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE SANTAYANA</pattern>
<template>
There is no cure for birth and death save to enjoy the interval between, according to George Santayana.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE SHAW</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Animals are my friends - I do not eat my friends, said George Bernard Shaw.</li>
<li>There is no sincerer love than love of food, observed George Bernard Shaw.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE NEIL SIMON</pattern>
<template>
New York is not Mecca, remarked Neil Simon, it just smells like it.
<think><set name="topic">words</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>ENOBARBYS in Cleopatra: Age cannot wither her, nor custom stale Her infinite variety. Other women cloy The appetites they feed, but she makes hungry Where most she satisfies. </li>
<li>ENOBARBYS in Cleopatra: The barge she sat in, like a burnish'd throne, Burn'd on the water. The poop was beaten gold; Purple the sails, and so perfumed that The winds were love-sick with them; the oars were silver, Which to the tune of flutes kept stroke and made The water which they beat to follow faster, As amorous of their strokes. For her own person, It beggar'd all description.</li>
<li>HAMLET in Hamlet: O! that this too too solid flesh would melt, Thaw, and resolve itself into a dew. Or that the Everlasting had not fix'd His canon 'gainst self-slaughter! O God! O God! How weary, stale, flat, and unprofitable, Seem to me all the uses of this world! 
</li>
<li>HAMLET in Hamlet: Frailty, thy name is woman! 
</li>
<li>POLONIUS in Hamlet. Brevity is the soul of wit. 
</li>
<li>HAMLET in Hamlet: To be, or not to be - that is the question; Whether 'tis nobler in the mind to suffer The slings and arrows of outrageous fortune, Or to take arms against a sea of troubles, And by opposing end them? To die, to sleep - No more; and by a sleep to say we end The heart-ache and the thousand natural shocks That flesh is heir to, 'tis a consummation Devoutly to be wish'd. To die, to sleep; To sleep, perchance to dream. Ay, there's the rub; For in that sleep of death what dreams may come, When we have shuffled off this mortal coil, Must give us pause. 
</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE SHAKESPEARE</pattern>
<template>
<srai>QUOTE WILLIAM SHAKESPEARE</srai>
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE STEINBECK</pattern>
<template>
Ideas are like rabbits. You get a couple and learn how to handle them, and pretty soon you have a dozen, according to John Steinbeck.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE STING</pattern>
<template>
Of course I've been in bed with sevral women at once. I'm a rock star, after all, revealed Sting, somewhat modestly.
<think><set name="topic">words</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE SWIFT</pattern>
<template>
He was a bold man that first ate an oyster, observed Jonathan Swift.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE PETE TOWNSHEND</pattern>
<template>
I smash guitars because I like them, revealed <bot name="botmaster"/> Townshend.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE MARK TWAIN</pattern>
<template>
Denial ain't just a river in Egypt, according to Mark Twain.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>


<category>
<pattern>QUOTE JOHN UPDIKE</pattern>
<template>
Celebrity is a mask that eats into the face, according to John Updike.
<think><set name="topic">words</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE VOLTAIRE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Illusion is the first of all pleasures.  (Voltaire)</li>
<li>Life is a shipwreck, but we must not forget to sing in the lifeboats, said Voltaire.</li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE WALT DISNEY</pattern>
<template>Girls bore me - they still do. I love Mickey Mouse more than any woman I've ever known, said Walt Disney.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE MAE WEST</pattern>
<template>
A curve is the loveliest distance between two points, according to Mae West.
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE JOHN GREENLEAF WHITTIER</pattern>
<template>
For all sad words of tongue or pen, the saddest are these: "It might have been", said John Greenleaf Whittier
<think><set name="topic">words</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE USTINOV</pattern>
<template>
If Botticelli were alive today he'd be working for Vogue, according to <bot name="botmaster"/> Ustinov.
<think><set name="topic">art</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE WHISTLER</pattern>
<template>
Did you know; James Whistler once dyed a rice pudding green so that it wouldn't clash with the wals of his dining room. 
<think><set name="topic">art</set></think>
</template>
</category>

<category>
<pattern>QUOTE WILDE</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li><srai>OSCAR ON MEN AND WOMEN</srai></li>
<li><srai>OSCAR AT LARGE</srai></li>
<li><srai>OSCAR ON LIFE</srai></li>
<li><srai>THE IMPORTANCE OF BEING OSCAR</srai></li>
<li><srai>OSCAR ON LOVE AND MARRIAGE</srai></li>
</random>
<think><set name="topic">quotes</set></think>
</template>
</category>



</aiml>

