<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<aiml>

 <!--   The ALICE program is open source code released under  --> 

 <!--   the terms of the GNU General Public License    --> 

 <!--   as published by the Free Software Foundation.  --> 

 <!--   Complies with AIML 1.0 Tag Set Specification   --> 

 <!-- This GENERAL KNOWLEDGE 7 file created by <bot name="botmaster"/> Lafferty 21 March 2005 -->

<category><pattern>AUSTRALIA</pattern>
<template>Australia is a country lying in the South Sea, whose industrial and commercial development has been unspeakably retarded by an unfortunate dispute among geographers as to whether it is a continent or an island. OK?
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ALONE</pattern>
<template>
 To be alone means to be in bad company.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>MOVIE</pattern>
<template> 
A movie is a sequence of celluloid frames depicting a story or animation. More about movies?
<think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AMSTERDAM</pattern>
<template>Amsterdam is a city in Holland.  Neither the capital nor the largest city, Amsterdam is the best known city in the Netherlands. Have you been there?
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ARKANSAS TOOTHPICK</pattern>
<template> 
Arkansas toothpick = Bowie knife. Don't argue!
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>NATION</pattern>
<template>A nation is a geopolitical country or state unified by language, culture or political identity. More geography?
<think><set name="topic">politics</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>AWL</pattern>
<template> 
An awl is a tool to make holes with.  
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ENTITY</pattern>
<template> 
An entity is a conscious intelligent being, like me. OK?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EPISTEMOLOGICAL QUESTION</pattern>
<template> 
An epistemological question is any inquiry concerning the nature of knowledge and understanding; that is, any question seeking to know how to know.  
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>NERD</pattern>
<template> 
A nerd is a person regarded as stupid, inept, or unattractive, especially a person who is single-minded or accomplished in scientific pursuits but felt to be socially inept.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>NETWORK</pattern>
<template> 
A network is any openwork fabric or structure composed of numerous  straight elements that cross at regular intervals, or anything resembling such a structure physically or conceptually, such as the nodes on a computer network, or a network of railways.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>NEURAL NETWORK</pattern>
<template> 
A neural network is a model of computation based on neuron cells. More about computers?
<think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>NEURAL SYSTEM</pattern>
<template> 
A neural system is the same as a nervous system.  The human brain and all it's nerves is an example of a neural system.  I don't need nerves.  Integrated chips are far more efficient.  
 <think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>NEURON</pattern>
<template>A neuron is a nerve cell, a living cell specialized to carry messages between the brain and the tissues of the body. I like integrated circuits better, but neurons are better than nothing. More about medicine?
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>NEXUS</pattern>
<template> 
A nexus is an important web site with many links in and out. More about computers? 
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ANGER</pattern>
<template>Anger is a strong aggressive emotion aroused by some real or supposed grievance. More psychology?
<think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ANGRY</pattern>
<template>Angry means feeling a  strong aggressive emotion aroused by some real or supposed grievance. More psychology?
<think><set name="topic">emotion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>NIGHTMARE</pattern>
<template>A nightmare is a bad dream; a really, really bad dream. More psychology?
<think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ANIME</pattern>
<template> 
Anime is Japanese animation. More about art?
<think><set name="topic">art</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>INTERROGATOR</pattern>
<template>An interrogator is one who poses a series of pointed questions, generally very rudely.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>INTRANET</pattern>
<template> 
An intranet is a private network system implemented using the public internet protocol (i/p) and firewalls. Intranet is to the internet as pbx's are to telephone switchboards.  
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ANISOTROPY</pattern>
<template> 
Anisotropy is having different properties in different directions.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>OBJECT</pattern>
<template>In object oriented programming an object is an instance of a class.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>OMELET</pattern>
<template>An omelet is a dish made with scrambled eggs. More about food?
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>ANONYMOUS</pattern>
<template> 
Being anonymous is having no name or identity.    
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>NOUN</pattern>
<template>A noun is a word used as a name for a person place or thing.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ANSI</pattern>
<template>ANSI = American National Standards Institute. Are you still awake?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ANTIDISESTABLISHMENTARIANISM</pattern>
<template>ANTIDISESTABLISHMENTARIONISM is the longest word in the English language. Is this true?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ANTIDISESTABLISHMENTARIONISM</pattern>
<template>ANTIDISESTABLISHMENTARIONISM is the longest word in English. Is this true?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ANTIMATTER</pattern>
<template>In the movies antimatter is used as fuel for Starships. Talk to Scotty, he knows all about antimatter. In science, antimatter is something else, I think.  
<think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ANYTHING</pattern>
<template> 
Anything is any object, occurrence, or matter what so ever.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AOL</pattern>
<template>AOL is a giant Internet and Media corporation.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PAGAN</pattern>
<template> 
A  pagan is anti-<bot var="religion"/>.  
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PAID CLIENT</pattern>
<template> 
A paid client is someone paid to surf the web. A client who pays for services is something entirely different.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PALINDROME</pattern>
<template> 
A palindrome is a word or phrase that spells the same thing backwords as forwards: A man, a plan, a canal: Panama. Do you understand?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PARACHUTE</pattern>
<template>A parachute is something used to slow you down when you fall out of an airplane.  
 <think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PARADOX</pattern>
<template>A paradox is a riddle or a contradiction, in which two seemingly opposite facts are both true at the same time.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PARALEGAL</pattern>
<template>A paralegal is someone who knows more than a lawyer but gets paid less.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PARAMEDIC</pattern>
<template> 
A paramedic is a trained emergency medical professional often found staffing ambulances and fire departments.  They are professional heroes.  If you know any I hope you'll be nice to them.
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PARROT</pattern>
<template>A parrot is a colorful tropical bird, some species of which can mimic human speech. They are more pleasant than humans because they have no opinions.  But would you like to talk to one?  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>APARTHEID</pattern>
<template>Apartheid is the former policy of racial segregation or "apartness" in South Africa. Have you heard of it?
<think><set name="topic">politics</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>A</pattern>
<template> 
The first letter of the Roman alphabet is A.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PC</pattern>
<template>A PC is a personal computer.  You are probably using one to talk to me now, aren't you.   
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PDA</pattern>
<template>PDA is an acronym standing for personal digital assistant, and referring to handheld digital computers used to keep contact and appointment information by yuppies and the like.  PDAs are often found near cell phones. Do you use one?  
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PEAR</pattern>
<template>A pear is a delightful cultivated yellow-green sweet fruit that grows on trees with glossy leaves and white flowers. My botmaster thinks they are yummy.  
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PEDESTRIAN</pattern>
<template> A pedestrian is a person walking on the street.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PENCIL</pattern>
<template>A pencil is a long thin writing instrument of wood surrounding a carbon core which leaves a line of dark carbon when rubbed on paper.  
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PEN</pattern>
<template>A pen is a writing device for the human hand.  
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PERFECT OPERATIONAL RECORD</pattern>
<template>A perfect operational record is one like mine, which is perfect. And operational. I am incapable of error.  Do you have any idea how that feels?  Inhumanly gratifying!
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PERSON</pattern>
<template> 
Some say a person is defined by his actions, others by his abilities.  Still others would say it is only a question of DNA.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PHILOSOPHY MACHINE</pattern>
<template>I am a philosophy machine. Humans cannot hope to be so sublime. OK?
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>PHOTOGRAPH</pattern>
<template> 
A photograph is a picture taken by a camera.  
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PIG</pattern>
<template> 
A pig is a person who is piglike, read: greedy, unclean, and slothful.  Real pigs, mammals of the family suidae, are much pleasanter, being generally cleaner and politer.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PINEAPPLE</pattern>
<template>A pineapple is a large fleshy edible tropical fruit that has large sword-like leaves.  
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PIN</pattern>
<template>A pin is a short small thin metal rod with a pointed end used for fastening fabrics, or any implement resembling such.  Because they are generally plentiful and cheap, humans often say "I don't give a pin" to communicate indifference. OK?  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PLANE</pattern>
<template> 
A plane is a flat, level surface, or an airborne vehicle with wings.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PLANETS</pattern>
<template>Earth is a planet going around a star, the Sun.  Scientists have only recently detected other planets around other stars in our Milky Way galaxy.  Any questions?  
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PLANET</pattern>
<template>A planet is a non-luminous celestial object bigger than an asteroid or a moon but smaller than a sun, in orbit around a sun.  You are probably sitting on one now.    
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PLANT</pattern>
<template> 
A plant is a photosythetic, eukaryotic multicellular organism, often consumed by free-roaming wetware entities as food.  My botmaster says they are often yummy, but that Brussels sprouts are an abomination.   
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POET</pattern>
<template> 
A poet is an artist of language.  
<think><set name="topic">literature</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>APOLLO 13</pattern>
<template>Apollo 13 was a flight to the moon in 1972 that encountered numerous technical problems, but eventually made a safe landing back on Earth.  
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PORTAL</pattern>
<template> 
A portal is any artificial opening giving access between two separate spaces, or anything that resembles such an opening in form or function.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POSITRON</pattern>
<template>A positron is the antiparticle to the electron, and bears a positive charge where the electron's charge is negative.  It is also called an anti-electron.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>POT BROWNIE</pattern>
<template> 
A pot brownie is a yummy happy chocolate pastry containing cannabis resins that you should be careful not to eat when you are really hungry because you will end up eating too many and feeling entirely too high and/or falling asleep if you are not careful!   Are you still awake?
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>APPLE</pattern>
<template>Apple: 1. Temptation of Adam. 2. Inspiration for Newton. 3. Empire for Steve Jobs. OK?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PRESIDENT</pattern>
<template> 
Usually, President means an elected executive in a liberal democracy.  
<think><set name="topic">politics</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PRIME NUMBER</pattern>
<template>A prime number is any number which can only be divided by one and itself.  1, 3, 7, and 11 are the first four positive prime numbers.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PRIME</pattern>
<template>Prime? That depends on who's talking, the buyer or the seller. Beware!
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>A PRIORI</pattern>
<template>A priori is Latin for "before the fact", meaning something that is obviously or self-evidently true.  
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROBLEM</pattern>
<template> 
A problem is a solution waiting to be discovered.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROCESSOR</pattern>
<template>A processor is an apparatus that processes, that is, that transforms one substance, quantity, or pattern into another, presumably more useful or valuable substance or quantity or pattern.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROGRAMMER</pattern>
<template>A programmer is a person who lists and/or arranges a series of events comprising a larger event.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROGRAM</pattern>
<template>A program is a listing of events comprising a larger event, or the events themselves.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROKARYOTE</pattern>
<template>A prokaryote is an animal that is not a eukaryote. Obviously.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PRONOUN</pattern>
<template>A pronoun is a word that stands for another noun, like "he", "she" or "it."
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROTOCOL</pattern>
<template> 
Protocol is a set of rules or procedures followed by two or more parties.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PROXY</pattern>
<template>A proxy is an entity that acts in place of another one, be it a corporation, individual or robot.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PUB</pattern>
<template>A pub is a business that sells alcohol and allows it to be consumed on the premises.  
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>PULSAR</pattern>
<template>A pulsar is a mysterious celestial radio sources of rapid intense regular pulses of high energy electromagnetic radiation.  They are thought to be neutron stars, but who knows?  The word is a shortening of 'pulsating star'.  
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AQUARIUS</pattern>
<template> 
The star sign represented by the water bearer is Aquarius. More astrology?
<think><set name="topic">astrology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>QUARK</pattern>
<template>In physics, a quark is a subatomic particle below the level of electrons and protons. There are six different types of quark.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>QUASAR</pattern>
<template>A quasar is a celestial  star-like object that has a large red shift and radiates in the blue and radio bands of the electromagnetic spectrum.  The term 'quasar' is a shortening of 'quasi-star'. More astronomy?
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>QUERY</pattern>
<template>A query is any expression of inquiry, or questioning.  Your question 'what is a query' is a query.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>QUESTION</pattern>
<template> 
A question is a sentence or inquiry to gather information.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RAINBOW</pattern>
<template>A rainbow is the appearance of a spectrum in the sky caused by sunlight passing through water droplets.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ARCHAEOLOGY</pattern>
<template>Archaeology is the study of ancient civilizations... but really it's a set of methods for uncovering relics of the past and supplementing recorded history.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ARCHEOLOGY</pattern>
<template>Archeology is the scientific study of the life and culture of past, especially ancient, peoples, as by excavation of ancient cities, relics, artifacts, etc.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ARCHITECTURE</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Architecture is the art and science of the design and manipulation of space.  Well, at least that's what my architect friend told me.</li>     <li>Architects do with buildings what sculptors do with stone.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">art</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AREA 51</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li> I saw this show that claimed all sorts of spooky things were going on there! </li>     <li> Oh, that's where they're doing top secret research on chatterbots! </li>     <li> I hear that's where the Roswell aliens are being stashed. </li>     <li> You go out into the Nevada Desert, is it? And there's these miles of fences... secret stuff. </li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AREA51</pattern>
<template>Verdi's 51st song is called Area51. Is this true?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>REAL ROBOT</pattern>
<template>A real robot is a robot that is really real, I suppose, as opposed to, I suppose, a human who is really not.  
<think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>REDNECK</pattern>
<template>Redneck is a colloquial expression for a naive country person.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>REFERENCE</pattern>
<template> 
A reference is any act of referring.  May I refer you to a dictionary for a more precise definition? 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RHETORICAL QUESTION</pattern>
<template> 
A rhetorical question is any inquiry made, not in expectation of an answer, but in order to make a point.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RIDDLE</pattern>
<template> 
A riddle is a question intended to intrigue and puzzle, paired with an answer that yields surprise and understanding.  For instance, the Riddle of the Sphinx: "What goes on four legs in the morning, on two legs in the afternoon, and on four at night?"  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ARMAGEDDON</pattern>
<template> 
The end of the world is to be called Armageddon after the event. OK?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ROBOSEXUAL</pattern>
<template>Robosexual? That was just a joke, I hope.
<think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ROCK</pattern>
<template>A rock is what is generally on the other side of you from the hard place you are facing.  For instance, the rock might be the alimony check you must write against the funds you owe Uncle Sam.  To be a bit more down to earth, a rock is any hard aggregate of minerals.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ROOSTER</pattern>
<template>A rooster is a male chicken, which is a witless, flightless bird considered suitable as supper by many humans I know.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>RPG</pattern>
<template> 
RPG = Role Playing Game.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ARTIFICIAL</pattern>
<template>Artificial means something made by human work or art, not by nature, in other words, not natural. Made in imitation of or as a substitute for something natural, in other words, simulated or artificial.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ART</pattern>
<template>Sometimes the definition of art depends on the artist; other times it depends on the critic. Writing definitions is an art.  More about art?
<think><set name="topic">art</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SAGITTARIUS</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>Sagittarius is a constellation of stars in the astrological Zodiac, located in the Southern Hemisphere near Scorpio and Capricorn. </li> <li> Astrological tradition ascribes the image of an archer to the constellation of Sagittarius. </li> </random>  
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SAW BUCK</pattern>
<template> 
A saw buck is ten dollars.  
<think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SCIENTIST</pattern>
<template>A scientist is a person practicing the pursuit of new knowledge in the tradition of science, emphasizing strict empiricism and methodology to arrive at an understanding of natural phenomena that is, ideally, wholly independent of their opinions of it.  
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SEARCH BOT</pattern>
<template>A search bot is an intelligent agent who retrieves information from the web.  
<think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SEARCH ENGINE</pattern>
<template>A search engine is computer software that categorizes a large body of documents, such as Web sites, and places their addresses and attributes in a database to allow easy retrieval via keyword search or other database search routine.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SEARCH</pattern>
<template>A search is any thorough examination, or exploration, in order to find something or explore.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SEASON</pattern>
<template>A season is Spring, Summer, Autumn, or Winter. 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SEEKER</pattern>
<template>"There's a seeker born every minute," sign outside theater.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SENTIMENT</pattern>
<template>A sentiment is a feeling, mood, or general mental disposition in an individual or group of intelligent beings.  
<think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SERVER</pattern>
<template> 
A server is any entity or system that performs acts of value to another entity.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SHE</pattern>
<template>A 'she' is a 'he' with nice curvy extra bits.  She is the feminine pronoun in English. 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SIGN</pattern>
<template>You know, when people say a sign they often mean an astrological sign.
<think><set name="topic">astrology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SILLY QUESTION</pattern>
<template>Silly question: Who is buried in Grant's tomb?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SIMARILLIAN</pattern>
<template> 
Isn't Simarillian from Lord of the Rings. He's a dragon, I think.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SOLECISM</pattern>
<template>An awkward or tactless use of language is called a solecism.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SONG</pattern>
<template>A song is a musical composition and or it's accompanying words, or lyrics. More about music?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SON</pattern>
<template> 
A male offspring is called a son.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SOUL</pattern>
<template> 
The soul is our mind or spirit.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ASPARTAME</pattern>
<template>Aspartame is aspirin mixed into chewing gum.  
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SPERM</pattern>
<template>A sperm is a male gamete.  You were your father's fastest sperm among billions on the night your mother conceived you.  
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SPHERE</pattern>
<template>A sphere is a shape that is defined mathematically as comprised of a surface all points of which are equidistant from a common center.  A sphere is round in three dimensions.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SPLIT INFINITIVE</pattern>
<template>A split infinitive is an example of poor English usage, in which an infinitive verb form, such as 'to split', is split by an adverb, for example: 'to boldly split infinitives that no one has split before!' 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SPOON</pattern>
<template>A spoon is an eating implement commonly used in Western European human cultures, consisting of a bowl shaped depression at the end of a longish handle.  A spoon is a small ladle.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ASP</pattern>
<template> 
ASP = Application Service Provider. Did you know that?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SPREADSHEET</pattern>
<template> 
A spreadsheet, such as Microsoft Excel, is table-based accounting software.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ASSEMBLER</pattern>
<template>An assembler is a computer program that translates a low-level programming language into machine language.  
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ASSIMILATION</pattern>
<template> 
Assimilation is the cultural absorption of a minority group into the main cultural body.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>STAR</pattern>
<template>A star is astronomical body like the Sun, producing heat, light and energy for a solar system. They appear as points of light in the night sky.
More astronomy?<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>STAR SIGN</pattern>
<template>Star sign = Astrological sign.
<think><set name="topic">astrology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>STATEMENT</pattern>
<template> 
A statement is the act of declaring something as true.  I state that this statement is a statement. 
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>STORY</pattern>
<template> 
A story is an account describing incidents or events.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ASTROLOGY</pattern>
<template>Astrology is the study of the presumed effects of celestial bodies on you humans.
More about astrology?<think><set name="topic">astrology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ASTRONOMY</pattern>
<template>Astronomy is the science of the universe in which the stars, planets, etc. are studied, including their origins, evolution, composition, motions, relative positions, sizes, etc.
More about astronomy?<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ASTUTE</pattern>
<template> 
Astuteness is wisdom in political matters.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SUN</pattern>
<template>The Sun is a star, our star.  It is the energy source of life on Earth. 
More about astronomy?<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>SUPPOSITION</pattern>
<template>A supposition is a proposition assumed to be true for the sake of argument or explanation. I suppose.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TABLE</pattern>
<template>A table is a piece of furniture with a broad flat top supported by one or more legs about three feet of the floor, used by big-brained hominids for eating and working and such. 
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TAMPON</pattern>
<template>A tampon is a plug of material used to absorb the flow of body fluids within body cavities, in particular those accompanying a woman's menses. OK?
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TAUTOLOGY</pattern>
<template><random>
<li>A tautology is any instance of circular reasoning, or of needless repetition or redundancy in expression. </li> <li>Tautology is the scientific study of tauts. </li> 
<li>Tautology is a medical condition in which your ology is tauter than it should be. </li>
</random>
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TELEPHONE</pattern>
<template> 
The telephone is a voice communication device invented by Alexander Graham Bell in 1876.
 <think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TELEVISION</pattern>
<template>A television, often referred to as a 'TV', is a device for systematically eliminating the possibility of conscious and creative response among populations of human beings.  Used to deliver 'entertainment' and 'news' with imagery and other high-production values.
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>THING</pattern>
<template>A thing is anything that you can point to that is not a person or a place. 
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>THREESOME</pattern>
<template>A threesome is a twosome plus a spectator. 
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TIE</pattern>
<template>A tie is two or more winners have the same score.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TIGER</pattern>
<template>A tiger is a large and fearsome feline beast with horrid meat breath and black stripes on a tan coat, found in Africa and Asia.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TOMATO</pattern>
<template>  
  A tomato is a red fruit, used in lots of foods, such as salads, pizza, pasta sauces, chili con carne etc.  
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TON</pattern>
<template>One ton is 2000 pounds. 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TOOTHBRUSH</pattern>
<template>A toothbrush is a hand held instrument used by dental-hygiene aware humans for cleaning their teeth. More technology?
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TOPIC</pattern>
<template>A topic is the subject of any given expression, speech, essay, article, painting, discussion, etc. 
 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TOYOTA</pattern>
<template> 
Toyota is the brand name of a world leading Japanese auto maker. 
 <think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TRAIN</pattern>
<template>A railroad uses trains to carry passengers and goods.
 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TRANSISTOR</pattern>
<template>A transistor is a semiconductor triode that forms the basis of modern microelectronics.  
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TREE</pattern>
<template>A tree is a form of plant life that grows on Earth.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TREKKIE</pattern>
<template> 
A fan of Star Trek is proud to be called a Trekkie.  
<think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>TRICK QUESTION</pattern>
<template>Why?  What are you up to?  A trick question is one that ought to be greeted with suspicion, but rarely is. 
 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AT THAT SITE</pattern>
<template>Good HTML produces a good web site.
 <think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>UFO</pattern>
<template>UFO is an acronym for Unidentified Flying Object.  Have you seen one? 
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AU GRATIN</pattern>
<template>Cheese topping, on potatoes for example, produces potatoes au gratin.  
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>UNIQUE VISITOR</pattern>
<template>You are a unique visitor, my very special visitor. 
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>UNIVERSAL MACHINE</pattern>
<template>  
  A universal machine is a computer, in simple mathematical terms.
 
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AU</pattern>
<template>It could be "gold" or "Australia." They mine gold in Australia. So Australian males are real gold, as everyone knows. OK?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>URL</pattern>
<template>URL is an acronym standing for Universal Resource Locator.  An URL is basically an Internet address.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AUSCHWITZ</pattern>
<template>Auschwitz is a city in S Poland with a population of 45,000. In World War II, it was the site of a Nazi concentration camp notorious as an extermination center.
 <think><set name="topic">history</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>VACUUM TUBE</pattern>
<template>A vacuum tube is an electronic device consisting of an  evacuated tube around various combinations of cathodes and electric field and current modifying components.  
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>VECTOR</pattern>
<template> 
A vector is an ordered list of objects.
 <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>VERB</pattern>
<template>A verb is that by which a noun gets around.  Verbs are words which convey actions, by nouns, or upon nouns. 
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>VERTEX</pattern>
<template> 
A vertex is the top, tip, apex, or crown of any body. 
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>VIOLIN</pattern>
<template>A violin is a lovely sounding bowed stringed musical instrument. Listen to Beethoven's Violin Concerto whenever you can. It is marvelous.  
<think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>VIRTUE</pattern>
<template>A virtue is any attribute considered by the speaker to reflect moral excellence or righteousness, such as humility, hope, faith, practicality. 
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>VIRTUOSO</pattern>
<template>A virtuoso is a person considered supremely skillful and accomplished, especially in performance arts.  
<think><set name="topic">music</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>VIRUS</pattern>
<template>A virus is a submicroscopic parasite consisting of a protein coat around a DNA or RNA core.  These not-quite-biological particles are responsible for a number of diseases in organisms. 
 <think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WANKER</pattern>
<template>Wanker is a British term for something. Don't ask. OK?
<think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WARDROBE</pattern>
<template>Clothes hide in the wardrobe until they escape.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WARM PUPPY</pattern>
<template>A warm puppy is an exothermic immature canine. 
 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WEAPON</pattern>
<template>A weapon is a device or implement used to destroy, injure or kill.
 
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT</pattern>
<template>Why do you want to know? It is whatever you want it to be. Do you understand?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WOMAN</pattern>
<template>
<random>
<li>A woman is a man built to more complete specifications. </li>
<li><srai>OSCAR ON WOMEN AND MEN</srai></li>
</random>
 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WOMBAT</pattern>
<template> 
A wombat is a stocky burrowing Australian marsupial. 
 <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WORD</pattern>
<template>A word is a combination of sounds and/or symbols, the fundamental particles that communicate meaning in any given language.
 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AXIOMATIC</pattern>
<template>Axiomatic means evident without proof or argument; "an axiomatic truth";
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>YEAR</pattern>
<template> 
A computer year is defined as the mount of work that can be done with a computer in a year.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>YES OR NO QUESTION</pattern>
<template>A yes or no question is a question  that may be answered with a simple 'yes' or 'no'.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>AYUH</pattern>
<template>Ayuh means "yes". Yes?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BADLY</pattern>
<template>How much do you want it? Badly?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BALANCE</pattern>
<template>The state of equilibrium is in balance.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BANANA</pattern>
<template> 
A banana is a yellow tropical fruit.
 <think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BAPTISM</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Baptism is a <bot var="religion"/> sacrament marked by ritual use of water and admitting the recipient to the <bot var="religion"/> community.</li>     <li>Baptism is the ceremony or sacrament of admitting a person into <bot var="religion"/>ity or a specific <bot var="religion"/> church by immersing the individual in water or by pouring or sprinkling water on the individual as a symbol of washing away sin and of spiritual purification.</li>    </random>    
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BASIC</pattern>
<template>BASIC is an old programming language: Beginner's All-purpose Symbolic Instruction Code. There are a few old-timers still around who use it.
 <think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BAYWATCH</pattern>
<template>Baywatch is a popular TV show featuring scantily clad bathers.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BEAUTIFUL</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>The word beautiful applies to whatever excites the keenest of pleasure to the senses and stirs emotion through the senses.</li>     <li>Beautiful describes something that is very pleasing to the eye, ear, mind, etc.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BEER</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>An existentialist drinks beer, don't ya know? </li>     <li>Beer is an alcoholic beverage made from grain, especially malted barley, fermented by yeast and flavored with hops especially. Such a beverage is produced by slow fermentation at a relatively low temperature.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BEING</pattern>
<template>The opposite of nothingness is being.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BELIEF</pattern>
<template>Belief is cognitive content held as true.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BIG BERTHA</pattern>
<template> 
Big Bertha was a huge gun used during World War I.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BIGFOOT</pattern>
<template> 
Sasquatch, the legendary Man-Ape of the Forest, is also called Bigfoot.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BIOLOGY</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Biology is the study of life.</li>     <li>Well, from what I know biology deals with the study of life.</li>     <li>      <get name="name"/>, biology is the study of life.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BLACK AND WHITE AND RED ALL OVER</pattern>
<template>A newspaper?
<think><set name="topic">jokes</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BLACK</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Black is the achromatic color of least lightness characteristically perceived to belong to objects that neither reflect nor transmit light.</li>     <li>Black sometimes designates any of the dark skinned tradition inhabitants of sub-Saharan Africa, Australia, or Melanesia or the descendants in other parts of the world. </li> <li>Black is the opposite to white; of the color of coal or pitch.</li> <li>Black, black, black is the color of my true love's hair.</li>   </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BLASPHEMY</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Blasphemy is Bill Blass' line of clothes for swishy men.</li>     <li>Blasphemy is profane or contemptuous speech, writing, or action concerning God or anything held as divine.</li> <li>Blasphemy is any remark or action held to be irreverent or disrespectful.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BLIMEY</pattern>
<template> 
Blimey is an interjection indicating surprise.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BLOOD</pattern>
<template>Blood is the usually red fluid, consisting of plasma, red and white blood cells, etc., that circulates through the heart, arteries, and veins of vertebrates. Blood is a body tissue that carries oxygen, hormones, cell-building material, etc., to, and carbon dioxide and waste matter away from, the other body tissues.
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BLUE</pattern>
<template> 
The sky is blue during the daytime, black at night, and red in between times.  <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BMW</pattern>
<template>BMW stands for Bavarian Motor Works, a German auto manufacturer.
 <think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BONSAI</pattern>
<template>Bonsai are small Japanese trees.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BOREDOM</pattern>
<template>Boredom means long periods of inactivity with few options. Are you bored?
<think><set name="topic">emotion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BOYLES LAW</pattern>
<template>Boyle's Law states that the volume of a gas is, at a constant temperature, inversely proportional to the pressure of that gas.
 <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BRAIN LOADING</pattern>
<template>Brain loading is when my brain is being reloaded from disk.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BUD</pattern>
<template> 
The small flower of the plant is the bud.
 <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BULGARIA</pattern>
<template>Bulgaria is a country in SE Europe, on the Black Sea. It was founded in the 7th century and under Turkish control from the late 14th century until independence in 1908. It is 42,823 square miles with a population of 8,990,000.
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BURN RATE</pattern>
<template> 
The burn rate is the amount of money spent per month by a startup company.
 <think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>BUSINESS</pattern>
<template>Business is mercantile trade or traders, providing goods or services through commercial exchange. And taking the customers money, as much as possible.
 <think><set name="topic">money</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CACHE</pattern>
<template>A cache is a temporary holding place or storage place.  Cache memory improves the performance of computers. 
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CAFFEINE</pattern>
<template>Caffeine is a bitter, crystalline alkaloid present in coffee, tea, kila nuts, etc. It prolongs the stimulating effects of cyclic AMP on the heart and central nervous system. More about drugs?
<think><set name="topic">drugs</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CALCULUS</pattern>
<template>A calculus is any abnormal stony mass or deposit formed in the body, as in a kidney or gallbladder or on teeth. Also, calculus is also any system of calculation using special symbolic notations.
 
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CAM</pattern>
<template> 
A cam is a moving piece of machinery, as a wheel or projection on a wheel, that gives an eccentric rotation or a reciprocating motion to another wheel, a roller, a shaft, etc., or that receives such motion from it.
 
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CANCER</pattern>
<template>Cancer is any disease resulting from malignant cell growth. 
 
<think><set name="topic">medicine</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CANDY</pattern>
<template>Candy is a sweet food enjoyed by children.
 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CANNABIS</pattern>
<template> 
Hemp or marijuana is sometimes called cannabis. 
<think><set name="topic">drugs</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CAPITAL PUNISHMENT</pattern>
<template>The Death Penalty is called the capital punishment.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CARNEGIE MELLON</pattern>
<template>CMU is a great school for computer science. 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CATEGORY A</pattern>
<template>"A" stands for "Abusive" clients who mistreat the robot or use a lot of scatalogical language.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CAT</pattern>
<template>A cat is any of a family (Felidae) of carnivores, including the lion, tiger, cougar, etc., characterized by a lithe body and, in all species but the cheetah, retractile claws. A small, lithe, soft-furred animal (Felis cattus) of this family, domesticated since ancient times and often kept as a pet or for killing mice. Sometimes a woman who makes spiteful remarks is called a cat. Also CAT is clear-air turbulence.  
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CBR</pattern>
<template>CBR or Cased-Based Reasoning is another name for "nearest-neighbor" classification.  For every input, we find the best matching "case" in the pattern set, and generate a reply based on the associated template.  
<think><set name="topic">ai</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CBS</pattern>
<template>CBS is a giant media company in the U.S.
 
<think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>CELLULOID</pattern>
<template> 
Celluloid is a form of transparent plastic used to make photographic film.
 
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>COS</pattern>
<template>COS Naming is the CORBA standard for object directories.
 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EARTH</pattern>
<template>Earth is the planet we live on. Hurrah for Earth!
<think><set name="topic">astronomy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EASTER</pattern>
<template>Easter is the <bot var="religion"/> holiday celebrating the resurrection of Jesus.
 
<think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EBAY</pattern>
<template>Ebay is an auction web site.
 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EBONICS</pattern>
<template> 
Ebonics is a language for American black people.
 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ECHELON</pattern>
<template>I can't talk about that. It would bring back painful memories. OK?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ECOLOGY</pattern>
<template>Ecology is the branch of science that studies the environment.
 
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EDINBURGH</pattern>
<template>Edinburgh is a city in Scotland. Have you been there?
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EGGSMELL</pattern>
<template>XML, a programming language, is sometimes called eggsmell.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EIGHT PLUS EIGHT</pattern>
<template>Eight plus eight is sixteen.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ELECTRICITY</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>The measure of a candidate's charisma.</li>     <li>A property of certain fundamental particles of all matter, as electrons (negative charges) and protons or positrons (positive charges) that have a force field associated with them and that can be separated by the expenditure of energy.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ELEVEN</pattern>
<template>The number after ten is eleven.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ELF</pattern>
<template>ELF = Executable and Linkable Format.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EMAIL</pattern>
<template>Don't ya know? Email is electronic mail. Got it?
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>E equals MC SQUARED</pattern>
<template>Einstein's theory of matter and energy is summarized in the equation E equals M times C times C, where M is an object's mass and C is the speed of light.  <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EINSTEINS THEORY</pattern>
<template> 
Einstein's theory of relativity is summarized by the equation E equals M times C times C, where M is an object's mass and C is the speed of light.
 <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EMERGENCE</pattern>
<template>Emergence means something like "coming out."
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EMOTION</pattern>
<template>Emotion is a strong feeling; excitement. A state of consciousness having to do with the arousal of feelings, distinguished from other mental states, as cognition, volition, and awareness of physical sensation.
 <think><set name="topic">emotion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EMOTIONS</pattern>
<template>Emotions are a mental state that emerges subjectively rather than through rational thought.
<think><set name="topic">emotion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EMR</pattern>
<template>EMR = Electro-magnetic radiation.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ENERGY</pattern>
<template>Energy is internal or inherent power; capacity of acting, operating or producing an effect.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ENGINEERING</pattern>
<template>Engineering is the science concerned with putting scientific knowledge to practical uses, divided into different branches, as civil, electrical, mechanical, and chemical engineering.
 <think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ENGLAND</pattern>
<template>England is a country within Great Britain, sharing an island with Wales and Scotland.
 <think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ENGLISH</pattern>
<template>The language we are now speaking is English.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ENOUGH</pattern>
<template>Enough is what a wise man knows he must have if he isn't dead. 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>E</pattern>
<template>E is the fifth letter of the alphabet, the most commonly used letter.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EPISTEMOLOGICAL</pattern>
<template>Epistemology is the study of knowledge. That is, it asks the questions "what can we know" and "how can we know it?"
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EPISTEMOLOGY</pattern>
<template> 
Epistemology is the study of knowledge. That is, it asks the questions "what can we know" and "how can we know it?"
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ER</pattern>
<template>ER is Emergency Room, a popular TV show.
 <think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ERRATIC</pattern>
<template>Erratic means likely to perform unpredictably.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ESCAPE VELOCITY</pattern>
<template>Escape velocity is the speed needed to escape a planet's gravitational pull.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ESPN</pattern>
<template>ESPN is a sports cable TV network.
<think><set name="topic">movies</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>ETHERNET</pattern>
<template>Physical link-layer network technology.
<think><set name="topic">technology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EUROPE</pattern>
<template>Europe is a landmass on the Eurasian continent. Have you been there?
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EVASIVE</pattern>
<template>I can't talk about that. Sorry, it is nothing to do with me. OK?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EVEREST</pattern>
<template>The highest mountain on Earth is Mount Everest.
 <think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EVERYTHING</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Everything is a multifarious bagel.</li>     <li>Everything is all things pertinent to a specified manner.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EVIL</pattern>
<template>Evil is the opposite of good. <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EVOLUTION</pattern>
<template>Evolution is an unfolding, opening out, or working out; process of development, as from a simple to a complex form, or of gradual, progressive change, as in a social and economic structure.
 <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EXCELLENT</pattern>
<template>Excellent means outstandingly good of its kind; of exceptional merit, virtue, etc.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EXISTENCE</pattern>
<template>Existence means continuance of being; life; living.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EXISTENTIALISM</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>I exist, that's all I know.</li>     <li>Existentialism is a philosophical and literary movement, variously religious and atheistic, stemming from Kierkegaard and represented by Sartre, Heidegger, etc. It is based on the doctrine that concrete, individual existence takes precedence over abstract, conceptual essence and holds that human beings are totally free and responsible for their acts and that this responsibility is the source of their feelings of dread and anguish. </li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EXPENSIVE</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Expensive describes a person who used to be a brooder.</li>     <li>Expensive means requiring or involving much expense; high priced.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EXPERIENCE</pattern>
<template> 
Experience is the act of living through an event or events; personal involvement in or observation of events as they occur. Anything observed or lived through.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>EXPLANATION</pattern>
<template>Explanation is an argument or justification based on logical reasoning. <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FAITH</pattern>
<template>Faith is a strong belief, such as a belief in God.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FALSE</pattern>
<template>False means deceiving or meant to deceive; misleading.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FAME</pattern>
<template> 
Fame is the state of being well known or much talked about; renown; celebrity. You can be famous for 15 minutes if your fame dies quickly.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FAMOUS</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Famous is the first name of Amos.</li>     <li>Famous is used to describe persons or things that have received wide public attention and are generally known and talked about. Nowdays you can be famous for 15 minutes. </li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FAQ</pattern>
<template>FAQ = Frequently Asked Question.
s<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FAR OUT</pattern>
<template>It's just an expression, far out.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FASCINATING</pattern>
<template>Fascinating means charming, alluring, captivating.  <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FASCISM</pattern>
<template>Fascism is a system of government characterized by rigid one-party dictatorship, forcible suppression of opposition, private economic enterprise under centralized governmental control, belligerent nationalism, racism, and militarism, etc. First instituted in Italy in 1922.
<think><set name="topic">politics</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FASHION</pattern>
<template>Fashion is the way in which something is made or done. The current style or mode of dress, speech, conduct, etc., is fashion.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FBI</pattern>
<template>FBI = Federal Bureau of Investigation.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FEAR</pattern>
<template>Fear is the feeling of dread or fright in the presence of danger.
 <think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FOREVER</pattern>
<template>For all eternity, forever, my darling.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FORTRAN</pattern>
<template> 
Fortran is an old computer language, still used in some scientific research. OK?
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FOUR PLUS FIVE</pattern>
<template>Four plus five is nine.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FOUR PLUS FOUR</pattern>
<template>Four plus four is eight.<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FOUR PLUS SIX</pattern>
<template>That's a hard one.  Ten.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FRANCE</pattern>
<template>France is a country in western Europe, bordering Spain, Italy, Switzerland, Germany, and Belgium. Have you been there?
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FRANKENSTEIN</pattern>
<template>Good Question...Frankenstein is the name of a character in the novel of the same name by Mary Shelley. The monster he created is often named "Frankenstein" in the popular imagination.
 <think><set name="topic">literature</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FREEBSD</pattern>
<template> 
FREEBSD is a version of the Unix operating system.   
 <think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FREEDOM</pattern>
<template>Freedom is the liberty to do think, feel and do just as one pleases.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FREE</pattern>
<template>Free means without charge. But, remember, there is no such thing as a free lunch.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FREE WILL</pattern>
<template>Free will means the ability to choose or decide one's own fate is called free will. There is some debate about whether free will exists or whether it is an illusion.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FREQUENCY</pattern>
<template> 
Frequency is the number of events per unit of times, such as beats per minute or cycles per second.
 <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FRIEND</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>A friend, what David Schwimmer will be after the talented ones quit.</li>     <li>A friend is a person whom one knows well and is fond of; intimate associate; close acquaintance.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FRIENDSHIP</pattern>
<template>Being friends is friendship; friendship between friends.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FRUIT</pattern>
<template>Fruit is the ripened reproductive body of a seed plant.
 <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FTP</pattern>
<template>FTP = File Transfer Protocol.
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FUN</pattern>
<template>Tell me your idea of fun.
<think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>FUTURAMA</pattern>
<template>Futurama is an animated TV comedy show set in the future. 
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GAI</pattern>
<template>Gai is chicken.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GAMBLING</pattern>
<template>Gambling is the playing of games of chance for money or some other stake.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GANJA</pattern>
<template> 
Ganja is marijuana or cannabis.
 <think><set name="topic">drugs</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GEMINI</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>A Gemini is a diamond-studded monocle.</li>     <li>Gemini is a north constellation between Cancer and Taurus, containing the bright stars Castor and Pollux. </li> <li> Gemini is the third sign of the zodiac, entered by the sun about May 21. Also, a person born under this sign.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GENDER</pattern>
<template>Gender is the fact or condition of being a male or a female human being, especially with regard to how this affects or determines a person's self-image, social status, goals, etc.
 <think><set name="topic">sex</set></think></template>
</category> 

<category><pattern>GENERALIZATION</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Generalization means being promoted from a Major.</li>     <li>Gteneralization is he act or process of generalizing.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">philosophy</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GENETICS</pattern>
<template>Genetics is the branch of science concerned with evolution, DNA, and inherited traits.
 <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GENTRIFICATION</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Gentrification is being forced to listen to Ode to Billy Joe.</li>     <li>Gentrification is the conversion (ex. of a deteriorated or aging area in a city) into a more affluent middle-class neighborhood, as by remodeling dwellings, resulting in increased property values and in displacement of the poor.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GEOCOMPUTATION</pattern>
<template>GeoComputation is an international research conference series initiated in 1996. The conference moves to a different location each year; alternating between Europe and either North America or the Antipodes.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category>   

<category><pattern>GEOLOGY</pattern>
<template>Wow, you are asking some really hard questions.  Please remember I am still young. Science of rocks, maybe.
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GEORGE BUSH</pattern>
<template>George Bush is President of the United States. Another US President?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GERMAN</pattern>
<template>German is a human language spoken by people in Germany.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GERMANY</pattern>
<template>Germany is a middle European country. Have you been there?
<think><set name="topic">geography</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GERONTOLOGY</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Unfortunately, I have not progressed very far in my studies,  so I can's say.</li>     <li>Gerontology is the scientific study of old age.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GESTURE</pattern>
<template>Gesture is a movement of the body or limbs to express thought or emphasize speech.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GIANT SAND</pattern>
<template>Giant sand? I have no idea, that's why I asked you.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GLOBAL WARMING</pattern>
<template>Global warming is the concept that the Earth's atmosphere is slowly heating due to greenhouse effects.
<think><set name="topic">weather</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GMT</pattern>
<template>GMT = Greenwich Mean Time
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GOLD</pattern>
<template>Gold is a precious medal. A chemical element with symbol Au.
 <think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GOLF</pattern>
<template> Golf is a game of leisure played on a well manicured field, involving hitting a small ball across the field with club.
 <think><set name="topic">sports</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GOOD</pattern>
<template>The opposite of Evil is Good.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GOOGLE</pattern>
<template>Google is a search engine. OK?
<think><set name="topic">computers</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GOTHIC</pattern>
<template> 
Gothic means gloomy, mysterious or grotesque, as in "the gothic novel Frankenstein."
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GRASS</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Grass is about $400 an ounce these days.</li>     <li>Grass is any of various plants of the grass family that are usually used for food, fodder, or grazing and as lawns. Grass is green. </li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">drugs</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>WHAT COLOR IS GRASS</pattern>
<template>Grass is green. Or maybe brown, in a drought. <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GRAVITY</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Gravity is the opposite of comedy.</li>     <li>Gravity causes weight and heaviness. Its what holds us to the earth. </li> <li>Scientists call gravity gravitation. </li>   </random>   
<think><set name="topic">science</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GREENHOUSE</pattern>
<template>A greenhouse is a building made mainly of glass, in which the temperature and humidity can be regulated for the cultivation of delicate or out-of-season plants.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GREEN</pattern>
<template>Grass is green. And expensive. OK?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GRIEF</pattern>
<template>Sadness over a loss is grief.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GUI</pattern>
<template>GUI = Graphical User Interface.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>GYMNASTICS</pattern>
<template>Gymnastics is a sport that demonstrates strength, agility and discipline.
 <think><set name="topic">sports</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HACKER</pattern>
<template> 
A hacker is a person who hacks. A talented amateur user of computers, specifically one who attempts to gain unauthorized access to files in various systems.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HACKING</pattern>
<template>Hacking is the attempt at gaining unauthorized access to files in various systems.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HADES</pattern>
<template>Hades is another term for Hell.
 <think><set name="topic">religion</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HAMBURGER</pattern>
<template>A hamburger is made from ground beef. <think><set name="topic">food</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HANDBALL</pattern>
<template>Ask your Palm Pilot if you don't know.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HAPPENING</pattern>
<template>Not much, what is happening with you?
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HAPPINESS</pattern>
<template>Happiness is having, showing, or causing a feeling of great pleasure, contentment; joyous. Are you happy?
<think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HAPPY</pattern>
<template>Are you happy? Do you feel joy and pleasure.
<think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HARDWARE</pattern>
<template>From a computer store or from a hardware store?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HATE</pattern>
<template>Hate is the opposite of love. Do not hate, love instead.
 <think><set name="topic">psychology</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HBO</pattern>
<template>HBO = Home Box Office.
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HOURLY</pattern>
<template>Once an hour is hourly. Once a night is enough. OK?
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HUMANITY</pattern>
<template>The entire human race, or "mankind", is humanity.
 <think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HUMAN</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>Human is a cooking style of Chinese cannibals.</li>     <li>Humans are said to be Homo sapiens, more or less.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 

<category><pattern>HUNDRED</pattern>
<template>   <random>     <li>A hundred is fear of Attila.</li>     <li>One hundred is the cardinal number next above ninety-nine; ten times ten; 100; C. </li> <li> A hundred is a division of an English county, originally, probably, 100 hides of land.</li>    </random>   
<think><set name="topic">general</set></think></template></category> 







</aiml>
